<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:38:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>TSMC posts record profit as AI chip demand surges</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tsmc-reports-record-q4-earning-UI_eIHdAQye11sAjPeCpIg</link>
      <description>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, the world's largest contract chipmaker, reported record fourth-quarter results on Thursday, with net profit surging 35% year-over-year to NT$505.74 billion ($16 billion), exceeding analyst expectations and fueling a rally across global semiconductor stocks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Taiwanese chipmaker announced revenue of NT$1.046 trillion ($33.7 billion) for the quarter ending December 31, marking a 20.5% increase from the previous year. TSMC also revealed plans to substantially increase capital expenditure to between $52 billion and $56 billion in 2026, up from $40.9 billion last year, and projected approximately 30% revenue growth for the full year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/QFTV3OC3TRJNFJM5EDSPXOGT5Y.jpg?auth=50cdfedc9acba2c4977d1d2c379246cd2c2b230cf146b31a6dbd0eb304592af3&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space economy markets forecast to double by 2030</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/space-economy-markets-set-for-Lvi9_e77TkudwdwHpt6Lvw</link>
      <description>Multiple sectors of the space economy are projected to surge over the next five years as governments and private investors pour unprecedented funding into satellite services, orbital manufacturing, space habitats, and rescue operations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;New market research reports released January 15, 2026, by ResearchAndMarkets.com detail growth trajectories across several emerging space economy segments. The space currency and economy market is forecast to grow from $1.91 billion in 2026 to $3.8 billion by 2030, while in-space manufacturing, servicing, and transportation is expected to expand from $2.6 billion to $5.23 billion during the same period. Space habitat development is projected to reach $11.54 billion by 2030, growing at a compound annual growth rate of 20.8%.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/LIEYDAVLLZOYBDFKK3JW4UELVQ.jpg?auth=f10d36d9c643805f579b9d8e1b7b4a030792ad83a170f3d47f42840251e238e9&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice quantum simulator reveals how vibrations drive energy flow in molecules</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/rice-quantum-simulator-tracks-sulyVHbeTuyV38HcGM2hPw</link>
      <description>Researchers at Rice University have built a quantum device capable of simulating molecular vibrations and directly observing how energy moves from one part of a molecule to another, findings that could deepen understanding of natural processes like photosynthesis and improve designs for solar energy technology.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The work, published Dec. 5 in Nature Communications, marks the first time scientists have used trapped-ion technology to simulate a two-mode molecular system while independently controlling energy loss to the environment, according to the research team.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/quantum-simulator-shed.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada and China sign trade roadmap as Carney makes first Beijing visit in 8 years</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canada-and-china-strengthen-tr-rgTU032AR2KJDPcNjzu2eg</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney and China's top officials signaled a major shift in bilateral relations Thursday as the two countries signed an economic and trade cooperation roadmap alongside six initial agreements covering energy, food safety, and other sectors during the first visit to Beijing by a Canadian leader in eight years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi characterized Carney's four-day state visit as a "turning point" in ties between the two nations, telling Canadian Foreign Affairs Minister Anita Anand that the progress would "open up new prospects for bilateral relations" amid what he described as "unprecedented and complex changes taking place in the world."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/OF7T4PORYNMAPH7YHJR7IOF5XQ.jpg?auth=f14b7f51bcd141a5b470910db86fed40d0fc42a9189d16e27c048a333fdd9a17&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu asked Trump to delay Iran strike, officials say</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/netanyahu-asks-trump-to-delay-ylzHUSDOTEyWjpP9mq0_IA</link>
      <description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu asked President Donald Trump on Wednesday to hold off on a military strike against Iran, according to senior U.S. officials, as four Arab nations conducted urgent diplomacy to avert an American attack that they feared could destabilize the region.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The request from Netanyahu came as Trump appeared to pull back from the brink of military action, telling reporters Wednesday that he had been informed by "very, very important sources on the other side" that the killing of protesters in Iran had stopped and planned executions would not take place.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1024-512%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2025-11/251130-netanyahu-nd-4a335a.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deforestation pushing mosquitoes to bite humans more, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/deforestation-drives-mosquitoe-SNM_w1YaQEeAeNDKA9ib6Q</link>
      <description>As Brazil's Atlantic Forest shrinks and wildlife vanishes, mosquitoes are increasingly targeting humans for their blood meals, raising fresh concerns about the spread of diseases such as dengue, Zika, and yellow fever, according to a study published this week in Frontiers in Ecology and Evolution.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, conducted by scientists at the Oswaldo Cruz Institute and the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, analyzed blood samples from mosquitoes captured in nature reserves within the Atlantic Forest. The results showed a pronounced shift: of the identifiable blood meals, 18 came from humans—far outpacing other sources, which included only six birds, one amphibian, one rodent, and one canid.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/mosquitoes-thirst-for.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump advisers warned Iran strike unlikely to topple regime</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-advisers-warned-iran-str-18ji.kBdRNSg6xa_ZweWfg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's national security advisers have cautioned him that a substantial military strike against Iran would probably not lead to the collapse of the Islamic Republic's government and could instead trigger a wider regional conflict, according to U.S. officials familiar with the discussions. The assessment came as Trump signaled a potential pause in his escalating threats against Tehran, saying Wednesday he had been informed that killings of protesters had stopped.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The president has communicated to his advisers that he wants any military action to be "swift and decisive" and deliver a "definitive" blow to the regime, according to NBC News. However, officials said his team has been unable to guarantee that outcome, with concerns mounting that the United States may lack sufficient military assets in the region to defend against what is expected to be an aggressive Iranian response.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2026-01/260110-donald-trump-ch-1533-720c46.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US and Taiwan reach trade deal cutting tariffs, securing chip investment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-and-taiwan-reach-landmark-t-bLbbji7oS9qvz.nDk2QwOA</link>
      <description>The United States and Taiwan have reached a trade agreement that will reduce tariffs on Taiwanese goods from 20 percent to 15 percent and secure hundreds of billions of dollars in semiconductor investment commitments, according to officials familiar with the matter. The deal, which the White House was set to announce Thursday, places Taiwan on equal footing with Japan and South Korea, which secured similar arrangements last year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Under the agreement, Taiwanese semiconductor companies will commit to a $500 billion increase in financing for American operations, with Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. pledging to build at least five additional fabrication plants in Arizona, effectively doubling its manufacturing presence in the state.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/03/multimedia/03biz-tsmc-sub-vzgl-wpzq/03biz-tsmc-sub-vzgl-wpzq-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global AI spending to surge 44% in 2026, Gartner forecasts</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/global-ai-spending-to-reach-3-frT4ZQ.GQfirWRig5gUmwA</link>
      <description>The artificial intelligence industry is on track for a historic year, with global spending projected to surge 44% to $2.53 trillion in 2026 before climbing to $3.33 trillion by 2027, according to new forecasts from Gartner released this week. The boom is simultaneously propelling semiconductor revenues past $1 trillion for the first time in the industry's history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://g.foolcdn.com/image/?url=https%253A%252F%252Fg.foolcdn.com%252Feditorial%252Fimages%252F838892%252Fnvidia-voyager-headquarters.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;op=resize" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's acting president proposes oil reforms to lure US investment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-s-rodriguez-seeks-oi-3qsHYGXxQsaYGSeljzr_pg</link>
      <description>Acting Venezuelan President Delcy Rodríguez has submitted a proposal to reform her country's hydrocarbon law, seeking to open doors to greater US investment in the oil-rich nation less than two weeks after US special forces captured former President Nicolás Maduro in a surprise military operation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rodríguez announced on Thursday that she was proposing the reforms to Venezuela's National Assembly, a move that addresses a key demand from major American oil companies who have described the country as "uninvestable" under current regulations. At her first press conference since Maduro's ouster, Rodríguez also declared Venezuela was entering a "new political era" marked by greater tolerance toward political rivals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768511210/getty_uploads/2256293841_zaopbf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil's Bolsonaro ordered transferred to maximum-security prison</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/bolsonaro-ordered-transferred-80_sKSCLQ8KzhBuFTw.TaQ</link>
      <description>Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered the transfer of former President Jair Bolsonaro to the Papuda Penitentiary Complex in Brasilia on Thursday, according to court documents released January 15, 2026. The move represents a stark shift in the conditions under which the 70-year-old far-right politician will serve his 27-year sentence for plotting a coup following his 2022 election defeat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bolsonaro has been detained at the Federal Police Superintendency since his arrest in late November 2025, housed in a 12-square-meter room equipped with a bed, private bathroom, air conditioning, television, and desk. Under the new order, he will be relocated to a building within the Papuda complex, Brazil's largest maximum-security penitentiary facility in the capital.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768512622/getty_uploads/2234877459_xx5kxq.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet's sunward jets baffle scientists</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/interstellar-comet-3iatlas-baf-UeUKFUMHQbqqRwRroBUJOw</link>
      <description>The third known interstellar object to visit our solar system continues to puzzle astronomers as it exits toward Jupiter, displaying sunward jets that defy conventional comet physics while yielding no detectable alien signals to radio telescopes scanning for signs of extraterrestrial technology.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Comet 3I/ATLAS, first spotted on July 1, 2025, by the NASA-funded ATLAS survey in Chile, has been the subject of intense scientific scrutiny since its discovery. With the Breakthrough Listen project confirming no technosignatures were detected during five hours of observation using the Green Bank Telescope on December 18, 2025, researchers have largely settled the question of whether this cosmic wanderer might be artificial.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We all would have been thrilled to find technosignatures coming from 3I/ATLAS, but they're just not there," Benjamin Jacobson-Bell from the University of California, Berkeley, told Space.com. "Finding no signals was the result we expected, due to the significant evidence for 3I/ATLAS being a comet with only natural features."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d1rldr9jdodfaa.cloudfront.net/images/01KCBFR8ZZ5921Q9SH2DFHJJ2Q/a68a0c35-9588-4296-ad79-ef131d82467e_1765617181.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMF awaits shareholder backing before aiding Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/imf-awaits-shareholder-recogni-uTgzyWRhTe6gSTIgonLiwg</link>
      <description>The International Monetary Fund stands ready to support Venezuela, but must first receive backing from its major shareholders to recognize the country's post-Maduro leadership before any assistance can flow, Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva said Thursday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If there is an opportunity to support the people of Venezuela, you can be sure the Fund will be there," Georgieva told Reuters during a visit to Ukraine. The remarks came nearly two weeks after U.S. forces removed former President Nicolás Maduro in a January 3 military operation, leaving acting President Delcy Rodríguez to navigate the country's economic turmoil.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://preview.thenewsmarket.com/Previews/IMFO/VideoAssets/1920x1080/IMFO_54923_693582_v3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists map hidden landscape beneath Antarctica's ice</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-unveil-detailed-map-D0.jRWgyR6umyQUa4pQbgQ</link>
      <description>A team of international scientists has produced the most comprehensive map yet of Antarctica's concealed terrain, revealing thousands of previously unknown hills, ridges, and river channels buried beneath miles of ice. The breakthrough, published Thursday in the journal Science, could transform researchers' ability to predict how the frozen continent will respond to climate change and contribute to rising sea levels.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The map uncovers geological features spanning 2 to 30 kilometers beneath the ice sheet, which covers more than 5.4 million square miles. Among the discoveries are deep alpine valleys, extensive channels carved by ancient flowing water that stretch for hundreds of kilometers, and sharp transitions between highland and lowland terrain that may indicate tectonic boundaries.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zrdwMQv5GKotVK6JHozwGi-1600-80.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese universities claim 8 of top 10 spots in global research rankings</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-universities-overtake-kfXdUHTRRRuMGXqeL5o6vA</link>
      <description>Zhejiang University has claimed the top spot in the Leiden Rankings, a global measure of research productivity, pushing Harvard to third place and marking a shift in academic power that reflects both China's strategic investments in science and the mounting financial pressures facing American higher education.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The rankings, produced by the Centre for Science and Technology Studies at Leiden University in the Netherlands, now feature eight Chinese institutions in the top 10. Twenty years ago, only one Chinese school would have made the top 25.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img2.chinadaily.com.cn/images/202510/24/68fb2feaa310f735017f66cc.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump announces 'Board of Peace' to oversee Gaza governance</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-formation-of-g-V7.67.UuRC6JC7MIynN5LQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced Thursday that the "Board of Peace" for Gaza has been officially formed, moving forward with the second phase of his 20-point plan to end the conflict in the Palestinian territory. The announcement came via his Truth Social platform, one day after his special envoy Steve Witkoff declared the launch of the plan's next stage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It is my Great Honor to announce that THE BOARD OF PEACE has been formed," Trump wrote, adding that the body's members would be revealed "shortly." He called it "the Greatest and Most Prestigious Board ever assembled at any time, any place."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/72RIUXQYOVPGJNQPHYJYWBGBOE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Einstein's wormholes may be time bridges, not space tunnels</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/new-research-reinterprets-worm-VkwZuU9hTYKcJNvizcHPsg</link>
      <description>Wormholes, long imagined as cosmic tunnels for interstellar travel and time machines, may not exist as shortcuts through space at all. Instead, new research suggests that Einstein-Rosen bridges—the mathematical structures behind the wormhole concept—represent something more fundamental: connections between two opposing directions of time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A paper published this week in the journal Classical and Quantum Gravity by astrophysicist Enrique Gaztañaga and colleagues presents a reinterpretation of the original 1935 work by Albert Einstein and Nathan Rosen. The researchers argue that the popular conception of wormholes arose from a misunderstanding of what the physicists intended.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/en/the_conversation_464/564d1607573689b91047c8cbfe4ca4de" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli startup nT-Tao fires first plasma in compact fusion reactor</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nt-tao-c3-fusion-prototype-ach-rEZJrCgGSF.AwkUb0qKZWw</link>
      <description>Israeli compact fusion energy company nT-Tao announced on January 15, 2026 that its C3 prototype has successfully fired its first plasma pulses, reaching operational status just over two months after assembly began. The milestone represents a concrete advancement in the company's pursuit of a container-sized fusion reactor capable of generating 10-20 MW of clean power.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Hod Hasharon-based startup's C3 system builds directly upon the successful experimental campaign of its predecessor, the C2-A, which achieved plasma temperatures of approximately one million degrees Celsius—roughly 100 electron volts—at the intended high-density regime. The new prototype incorporates design refinements across magnets, pulsed power systems, diagnostics, and overall integration, with experimental goals focused on reaching higher temperatures and extended confinement durations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/lo/mysterio/api/2FBF7BD88CB836199EDF5DAE3192554FA1DB3B7DBB52986A09D43AB194B6BC5B/subgraphmysterio/resizefit_w1200%3Bquality_90%3Bformat_webp/https:%252F%252Fs.yimg.com%252Fos%252Fen%252Finteresting_engineering_646%252F9d4294ed9233832bf20f2048915eea74" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's acting president calls for oil reforms, US thaw</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-s-new-leader-seeks-o-cg7.sL0HT8iHnxo_bgHGrQ</link>
      <description>Less than two weeks after the United States military captured Nicolás Maduro, Venezuela's acting president used her first major address to lawmakers to call for sweeping reforms to the country's oil industry and a diplomatic thaw with Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a 44-minute state of the union speech on Thursday, Delcy Rodríguez urged Venezuela's National Assembly to approve changes to the nation's hydrocarbon law that would open doors to greater foreign investment in the state-controlled oil sector. The address marked a striking departure from the anti-American rhetoric that defined her predecessor's rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4HV2AFG5QVKOTLUHQAUKOLQRSI.jpg?auth=9cb8a23b74e72ea1f9eddd8becb2464c255bdd3a9ff113663f4d0b0d79ca182f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT team cools trapped ions 10 times below standard limit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-uncover-new-quantum-JDj0suPnTSKZI6Vk69Wafw</link>
      <description>Two separate research efforts published this week are advancing the frontiers of quantum computing by solving distinct challenges: achieving efficient cooling for chip-based systems and discovering unexpected quantum states in exotic materials.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers at MIT and MIT Lincoln Laboratory announced Wednesday a technique for cooling trapped ions using integrated photonics that reaches temperatures about 10 times below the standard laser cooling limit, known as the Doppler limit. The method achieves this in approximately 100 microseconds, several times faster than existing approaches.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Meanwhile, scientists at TU Wien in Vienna and Rice University revealed Tuesday in Nature Physics that they observed an "emergent topological semimetal" — a quantum state previously considered impossible because it combines two phenomena thought to be incompatible.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://qci.dlr.de/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2025-10-01-Keyvisual-840-Toccata.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
