<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:40:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>European Parliament set to suspend US trade deal over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/europe-prepares-to-suspend-us-SiSdubsMRs6j5LswXNGUog</link>
      <description>The European Parliament is set to halt approval of the trade agreement reached with the United States last July, according to sources close to its international trade committee, as transatlantic tensions over Greenland threaten to unravel months of diplomatic negotiations. An official announcement is expected Wednesday in Strasbourg, France.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decision marks a rebuke to Washington after President Donald Trump on Saturday announced escalating tariffs on eight European nations—Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland—unless the US is allowed to purchase Greenland, a semi-autonomous Danish territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.lemde.fr/2026/01/20/3/0/3782/2521/1440/960/60/0/0f207e8_ftp-1-xlk7xnlh9anx-2026-01-20t122332z-1577463871-rc2z4jakn9kp-rtrmadp-3-eu-parliament.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexico transfers 37 cartel suspects to US amid pressure from Trump</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mexico-delivers-37-drug-cartel-nm9SA2VfS52dViJW8Qcsew</link>
      <description>Mexico has transferred another 37 drug cartel members to the United States, the country's security minister announced Tuesday, as the Trump administration continues to pressure governments to crack down on criminal networks smuggling drugs across the border.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mexican Security Minister Omar García Harfuch confirmed the transfer in a social media post on X, describing the individuals as "high impact criminals" who "represented a real threat to the country's security." The handover brings the total number of cartel operatives and leaders sent to the United States under President Claudia Sheinbaum's administration to 92.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4HWUZCRXIJPMLC4EUKZVIYANMA.jpg?auth=69fa12cb229c08bf4d1c22c57e625d09a7998e17787038d0ab6e66b16b60113f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran's parliament warns of jihad if Supreme Leader attacked</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-warns-jihad-if-supreme-le-Y7zKpa_kR_aKdUUy1mTiGA</link>
      <description>Iran's parliament issued a stark warning on Tuesday that any attack on Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei would trigger a declaration of jihad, or holy war, with the mobilization of Islamic fighters worldwide. The statement, from the national security committee of Iran's parliament, raises the stakes in a rapidly escalating confrontation between Tehran and Washington following a deadly crackdown on protests.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Any aggression against the Supreme Leader signifies a declaration of war against the entire Islamic community and necessitates a Jihad proclamation from Islamic scholars, along with the mobilization of Islam's fighters worldwide," the parliamentary committee stated, according to the Iranian Students News Agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-05-20t115850z-1894412973-rc2nleacha3a-rtrmadp-3-iran-nuclear-usa-20250629150751537.JPG?c=16x9&amp;q=h_833%2Cw_1480%2Cc_fill" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European leaders call for independence from U.S. at Davos</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-attends-davos-2026-amid-zEAPXA3QSpqu_TRXXdC8jw</link>
      <description>The World Economic Forum's annual meeting in Davos, Switzerland, has become a flashpoint for rising U.S.-European tensions as President Donald Trump prepares to address global leaders on Wednesday amid an escalating dispute over Greenland and new tariff threats against longtime allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;European leaders struck a defiant tone on Tuesday, the second day of the forum, as European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen called for a "permanent" shift toward European independence from the United States and French President Emmanuel Macron warned of a dangerous "shift towards a world without rules."</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4EPO2RX5PRONTC3RDIJCXBQ6CM.jpg?auth=8e9543263e090b354d7cb131edfbf0b54f18bd0a6627113bd8fd899c6a6f94dc&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists launch deep-sea mission to validate 'dark oxygen' discovery</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-deploy-deep-sea-lan-wA2PIbC_QmKU2dj1Dh7kCw</link>
      <description>Researchers have unveiled two specially designed deep-sea landers that will descend nearly seven miles beneath the Pacific Ocean to investigate the controversial phenomenon known as "dark oxygen," a discovery that could reshape understanding of how life emerged on Earth and complicate plans for commercial seabed mining.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At a press conference in London on Tuesday, Professor Andrew Sweetman of the Scottish Association for Marine Science (SAMS) introduced the landers named Alisa and Kaia, after his daughters, which are engineered to withstand pressures 1,200 times greater than those at the surface. The expedition, funded by a £2 million grant from The Nippon Foundation over three years, marks the most detailed examination yet of a process that defies the long-held scientific consensus that oxygen requires sunlight and photosynthesis to form.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Z2_a1a8ef.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second Spanish train derails near Barcelona, multiple injured</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/second-spanish-train-derails-n-gMPKCpqgQ4GdiJqL8a4ihw</link>
      <description>A commuter train derailed near Barcelona on Tuesday after a containment wall collapsed onto the tracks, injuring 15 passengers, Spanish emergency authorities said. The incident comes just two days after a catastrophic high-speed train collision in southern Spain killed more than 40 people.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768946020/url_uploads/Spanish_20rail_yezchy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IAEA chief warns Iran may be declared in nuclear treaty violation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/analysts-warn-iran-crisis-rais-hL09SUR9Tme2NUVK1wS8Uw</link>
      <description>As tensions between Washington and Tehran continue to escalate amid a violent crackdown on nationwide protests, arms control experts are sounding alarms about the security of Iran's near-weapons-grade uranium stockpile, warning that months of blocked inspections have created a dangerous void in international oversight.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The International Atomic Energy Agency has been unable to verify the status of an estimated 440.9 kilograms of uranium enriched to 60 percent purity—close to the roughly 90 percent considered weapons-grade—since U.S. and Israeli airstrikes struck key nuclear facilities in June 2025. That stockpile, according to IAEA standards, is theoretically enough material for 10 nuclear bombs if further enriched.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54293042288_2f6eee125d_b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says NATO would be 'ash heap of history' without him</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-claims-nato-owes-existen-P.onYnffQrCPMe8hiNlKyw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared on Tuesday that NATO would be "in the ash heap of history" without his leadership, as European leaders rallied to oppose his push to acquire Greenland and his threat to impose escalating tariffs on eight allied nations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"No single person, or President, has done more for NATO than President Donald J. Trump. If I didn't come along, there would be no NATO right now!!! It would have been in the ash heap of History," Trump wrote on Truth Social. In the same post, he added, "Sad, but TRUE!!!"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The remarks came just hours before Trump departed for the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, where European leaders assembled to present a united front against his territorial ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://dxltb3n5j8l6j.cloudfront.net/788185/uploads/324b8590-f642-11f0-977e-35ab0c61e9cb_1200_630.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and Putin envoys hold first talks on Ukraine at Davos</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-and-putin-envoys-hold-co-VMKxIHBWQQ.bqtTWuSuz7Q</link>
      <description>Envoys for U.S. President Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin met for approximately two hours in Davos on Tuesday to discuss a potential peace deal for Ukraine, with both sides characterizing the discussions as positive and constructive—even as key obstacles to ending Europe's deadliest conflict since World War II remain unresolved.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The meeting at "USA House" on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum brought together Trump's special envoy Steve Witkoff and son-in-law Jared Kushner with Kremlin representative Kirill Dmitriev, marking the first time a senior Russian official has publicly engaged at the Swiss gathering since the forum froze ties with Moscow following the 2022 invasion of Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768957326/getty_uploads/2256586635_u3p6o9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope captures dying star's fate and black hole's feeding</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-reveals-n-ZEoaWyRWTySzbdniGAvp7Q</link>
      <description>NASA released stunning new images from the James Webb Space Telescope on Tuesday, including a detailed look at the Helix Nebula that offers a glimpse into the eventual fate of our own Sun. Meanwhile, separate observations captured a supermassive black hole in the Circinus Galaxy actively consuming surrounding material, overturning decades of assumptions about how such cosmic giants feed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2026/01/webb_reveals_helix_nebula_in_glistening_detail/27049912-4-eng-GB/Webb_reveals_Helix_Nebula_in_glistening_detail_pillars.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada models guerrilla warfare response to US invasion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canadian-military-simulates-us-_WgxXgVURueKc1oAvoC4JA</link>
      <description>The Canadian Armed Forces have modeled a hypothetical U.S. military invasion of Canada and potential responses employing unconventional warfare tactics, The Globe and Mail reported on Tuesday, marking the first time in approximately 100 years that such scenarios have been war-gamed by Canada's military.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to two senior government officials who spoke to The Globe and Mail, military planners are simulating a U.S. invasion from the south, anticipating American forces could overwhelm Canada's strategic defenses on land and at sea within as little as two days. The officials emphasized, however, that a U.S. invasion remains highly improbable.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.the-independent.com/2026/01/20/21/06/GettyImages-2206320029.jpeg?trim=1%252C0%252C1%252C0&amp;width=1200&amp;height=800&amp;crop=1200%253A800" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX prepares Ship 39 for Starship Flight 12 debut</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-targets-mars-and-advanc-fAr4MKzYQJqKG_Pym8mN3w</link>
      <description>SpaceX is accelerating preparations for an ambitious year that could include the company's first uncrewed mission to Mars, while simultaneously advancing Starship development and maintaining a rapid pace of satellite launches.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company is targeting a Starship launch to Mars during the November-December 2026 planetary alignment window, which would represent the first private company mission to another planet. CEO Elon Musk has estimated a 50% chance of meeting the 2026 deadline, with plans to send Tesla Optimus humanoid robots on the initial missions to "prepare the way for humans."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.teslarati.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Starship-update-2022-SpaceX-Raptor-V1-vs-V2-1-crop-c.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela receives $300M from US-controlled oil sales</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-receives-300-million-iILx8irUQPek9CtKJnmGkg</link>
      <description>Venezuela's acting president Delcy Rodríguez announced on Tuesday that the country has received $300 million from the sale of Venezuelan crude oil facilitated by Washington, funds she intends to use to stabilize the country's battered currency and protect workers from inflation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We must inform you that we have received funds from the sale of oil, and of the first $500 million, we received 300 million," Reuters quoted Rodríguez as saying during a visit to a commune base in Caracas. The interim leader stated the revenues would be used "to stabilize" the foreign exchange market "to protect the income and purchasing power of our workers".</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768970804/getty_uploads/2256492636_qo2xr6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump demands NATO allies spend 5 percent of GDP, doubts their support</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-demands-nato-allies-spen-vRmqmMgoTLi5DAq9QgjilQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump used the one-year anniversary of his second term to renew calls for NATO allies to meet the alliance's 5% GDP defense spending commitment, while casting doubt on whether European partners would fulfill their mutual defense obligations. His remarks come amid escalating tensions over his campaign to acquire Greenland from Denmark.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I have done more for NATO than anyone else," Trump said during a White House briefing Tuesday. "The big fear I have with NATO is we spend tremendous amounts of money with NATO, and I know we'll come to their rescue, but I really do question whether or not they'll come to ours."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/17/multimedia/17dc-tariffs-greenland-topart-ctfl/17dc-tariffs-greenland-topart-ctfl-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds ChatGPT systematically favors wealthy Western nations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/study-finds-chatgpt-biased-tow-BC3lrUoASXOZwJ.6CEBJLg</link>
      <description>When prompted with subjective questions comparing places around the world, OpenAI's ChatGPT systematically favors wealthier, Western regions while ranking much of the Global South at the bottom, according to new research published Tuesday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, titled "The Silicon Gaze: A typology of biases and inequality in LLMs through the lens of place," analyzed more than 20 million queries submitted to ChatGPT's 4o-mini model. Researchers from the Oxford Internet Institute at the University of Oxford and the University of Kentucky found that the chatbot repeatedly ranked high-income countries, including the United States, Western Europe, and parts of East Asia, as "better," "smarter," "happier," and "more innovative" than poorer regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.euronews.com/articles/stories/09/61/97/17/1536x864_cmsv2_d37a6a81-89e7-555c-b86f-3795f66a6051-9619717.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weather disaster deaths decline despite climate change, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/climate-change-drives-disaster-xx0yqdJFTnSMP7O1kV2q3Q</link>
      <description>As climate change intensifies extreme weather events around the world, a paradox has emerged: overall mortality from weather-related disasters has declined in recent decades, even as storms, floods, and heatwaves grow more frequent and severe.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;An analysis by AFP of data from EM-DAT, a global disaster database run by the Belgium-based Centre for Research on the Epidemiology of Disasters (CRED), found that more than 2.3 million people died from weather-related events between 1970 and 2025. The death toll from 2015 to 2025 reached 305,156, a notable decline from 354,428 in the previous decade.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It's not because the events haven't become more dangerous. It's because we have become a lot better at coping with them," Dr. Marina Romanello, executive director of the Lancet Countdown, told AFP.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/3000x1688%2B0%2B156/resize/1400/quality/85/format/jpeg/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Feb%252F74%252Fe939da694982a4ec60c6d8718688%252Fgettyimages-1242172582.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Orbiter captures high-detail view of solar flare's trigger</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/solar-orbiter-reveals-magnetic-cXbdwKfUSry1PlSJ1bgKxQ</link>
      <description>The European Space Agency's Solar Orbiter spacecraft has captured the most detailed view ever of how solar flares ignite, revealing they are triggered by cascading magnetic avalanches rather than single coherent eruptions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published Wednesday in Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, could improve predictions of solar storms that pose radiation hazards to satellites, astronauts, and Earth-based technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6NhQakd7cZ9X3ZJ5kqJjbC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treasury chief calls Denmark 'irrelevant' amid Greenland tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-treasury-secretary-dismisse-NiACPZWYQtuFh3XbHTHfNQ</link>
      <description>U.S. Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent on Wednesday brushed aside concerns about potential European divestment from American government debt, making dismissive remarks about Denmark amid escalating tensions over President Donald Trump's push to acquire Greenland.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking to reporters at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, Bessent characterized Danish investments in U.S. Treasury bonds as insignificant. "Denmark's investment in U.S. Treasury bonds, like Denmark itself, is irrelevant," the Treasury secretary said. He added that he had "no worries at all" about any sell-off, pointing to "record foreign investment" in Treasury auctions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768989543/getty_uploads/2256680653_mxr1zy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Far-red light triggers protein that disarms antibiotic-resistant bacteria</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/far-red-light-reduces-virulenc-rEkRekYNSYWMpqcP44XtuA</link>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Chicago have uncovered a light-sensitive signaling pathway that suppresses biofilm formation and virulence in Pseudomonas aeruginosa, an antibiotic-resistant bacterium responsible for dangerous hospital-acquired infections. The discovery, published in Nature Communications, identifies a small protein called DimA as the master activator of the bacteria's response to far-red light, opening potential new avenues for infection control that do not rely on antibiotics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://biologicalsciences.uchicago.edu/sites/biologicalsciences/files/styles/social/public/2026-01/p-aeruginosa.jpg?h=c74750f6&amp;itok=BPq-Hyol" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JPMorgan CEO Dimon says AI will cut jobs at the bank</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jpmorgan-ceo-dimon-predicts-ai-ENxUsT2NTOiy7pxqzGzHMA</link>
      <description>Speaking at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, this week, JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon warned that artificial intelligence will transform the banking industry and reduce employment at the nation's largest financial institution over the next five years. Dimon estimated the bank will have fewer employees than its current workforce of more than 317,000, even as the company continues to grow globally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I do think it may go too fast for society," Dimon said during a panel discussion on Monday. "And if it goes too fast for society, that's where government and business and the collaborative ways to step in together and come up with a way to retrain people or move it over time."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EIV4HXAFVNNWNKBWJBKHMBHXDQ.jpg?auth=535d1002f0611a26955e5f60f54c72c9210bca170f65fab9d841fdd74c7b6a1d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
