<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 05:33:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Trump claim that NATO allies avoided Afghan frontlines sparks fury</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-sparks-backlash-claiming-YK19G4JTQBqRX.bNmReHgg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump ignited fury across NATO allies on Thursday after claiming in a Fox News interview that troops from allied nations "stayed a little back, a little off the front lines" during the war in Afghanistan. The remarks drew immediate condemnation from British, Polish, Danish, and Canadian officials, as well as veterans who served in the conflict, prompting British Prime Minister Keir Starmer to call the comments "insulting and frankly appalling."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Trump questioned whether NATO would support the United States if called upon. "We've never needed them. We have never really asked anything of them," Trump said. "They'll say they sent some troops to Afghanistan, and they did—they stayed a little back, a little off the front lines."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/mpx/2704722219/2026_01/f_mo_lon_starmer_260123-ccs6pj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos forum ends with climate sidelined as U.S. pushes fossil fuels</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/davos-2026-shifts-focus-away-f-jT.NvLwkQGmXCF0IV.MIPQ</link>
      <description>As the World Economic Forum wrapped up its 56th Annual Meeting in Davos, Switzerland, on January 23, the gathering revealed a stark realignment: climate change discussions had retreated to the sidelines, while fossil fuels took center stage amid a fractured geopolitical landscape.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;President Donald Trump's address on January 21 set the tone. "There are windmills all over Europe, and they are failures," Trump told the audience of global executives and policymakers, branding green initiatives "the Green New Scam." He promoted oil and nuclear power, claiming U.S. natural gas production had reached record highs and oil output had risen by 730,000 barrels per day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4YJKUNRDURJEPKV5ZSB2KSFUEQ.jpg?auth=8876dac4a9d2ad294b1cba969438a4ea8be368a9bb62c9c7af806bce821502cd&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says US military 'armada' is heading toward Iran</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-says-us-armada-heading-t-qmpMLFOFT3eVcIARmuDjAQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced Thursday that a US military "armada" is heading toward Iran, even as he expressed hope that the deployment would not be needed for further military action against Tehran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We have an armada. We have a massive fleet heading in that direction, and maybe we won't have to use it. We'll see," Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One as he returned from the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The deployment includes the aircraft carrier USS Abraham Lincoln, several guided-missile destroyers, and fighter aircraft, which began moving from the Asia-Pacific region last week, according to US officials speaking to Reuters. The carrier strike group is expected to arrive in the Middle East in the coming days, with officials also considering additional air defense systems to protect US forces and bases in the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2026/01/1200/675/uss-lincoln-trains-at-sea.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech CEOs tout AI job creation at Davos as workers grow anxious</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/davos-leaders-emphasize-ai-job-iO3xp6WlS4OHkER0pDyd5g</link>
      <description>Business leaders at the World Economic Forum's annual meeting in Davos, Switzerland, projected optimism this week about artificial intelligence creating jobs despite stark warnings from global economic officials and rising worker anxiety about the technology's disruptive potential.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang emerged as a leading voice for AI optimism, telling attendees that the technology would generate employment across blue-collar trades. "Energy is creating jobs. Chips industry is creating jobs. The infrastructure layer is creating jobs," Huang said during a conversation with BlackRock CEO Larry Fink. "Jobs, jobs, jobs."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Huang characterized the current AI buildout as "the largest infrastructure buildout in human history," predicting six-figure salaries for electricians, plumbers, and construction workers without needing "a Ph.D. in computer science."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769200076/getty_uploads/2256812762_tmi54i.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky urges caution after first day of Ukraine-Russia-US talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/zelensky-too-early-for-conclus-EuIOUis5TlO27fggbVksqg</link>
      <description>The first day of trilateral negotiations between Ukraine, Russia, and the United States concluded Friday in Abu Dhabi, with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky urging caution while the White House expressed measured optimism about the historic diplomatic effort.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It is still too early to draw conclusions about the content of today's negotiations; we will see how the talks go tomorrow and what the results will be," Zelensky said in his nightly address. The Ukrainian leader noted his negotiating team had provided updates "almost every hour" throughout the day but offered no details about specific discussions or progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769203877/getty_uploads/2256966685_pptljc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uganda military chief says 2,000 detained, 30 killed in post-election crackdown</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uganda-detains-2000-opposition-PNbHUv_AS1iH5pO4sPGsFw</link>
      <description>Uganda's military chief announced Friday that authorities have detained 2,000 opposition supporters and killed 30 people in an escalating crackdown following last week's contested presidential election in which his father, President Yoweri Museveni, won a seventh term.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;General Muhoozi Kainerugaba, who is also Museveni's son and widely believed to be his designated successor, disclosed the figures in a series of overnight social media posts, labeling members of the opposition National Unity Platform as "hooligans and terrorists." "So far we have killed 30 NUP terrorists," Kainerugaba wrote on X, without explaining the circumstances of the deaths. "Most NUP terrorist leaders are in hiding. We shall get them all," he added in another post.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://apicms.thestar.com.my/uploads/images/2026/01/23/3734988.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major airlines suspend Middle East flights amid US-Iran tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/major-european-airlines-suspen-UZCSuI9ZSMeX57CV_PNCsg</link>
      <description>KLM, Air France, Lufthansa, British Airways, Swiss, and several other major carriers abruptly suspended flights to Israel, the United Arab Emirates, and Saudi Arabia on Friday, citing escalating security concerns as U.S. President Donald Trump announced a naval "armada" heading toward Iran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The coordinated cancellations, which began late Thursday evening and extended through the weekend, disrupted travel plans for thousands of passengers across Europe and left airports scrambling to manage the sudden disruption. The flight suspensions came as Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan warned that Israel continues to seek an opportunity to strike Iran.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769207287/url_uploads/-1x-1_x7zjwi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold nears $5,000 in best week since 2020 as silver tops $100</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-hits-record-week-as-intel-DlE9NRm4Q66Kejc6MoDZhQ</link>
      <description>Gold approached $5,000 per ounce on Friday, capping its strongest week since March 2020, while silver breached the $100 threshold for the first time and Intel shares tumbled more than 17%, dragging down U.S. markets to a muted close.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The precious metals surge came amid lingering geopolitical uncertainty, a weakening U.S. dollar, and investor demand for safe-haven assets. Meanwhile, Wall Street concluded a volatile week with all three major indexes posting losses, as the chipmaker's disappointing outlook underscored persistent challenges in the semiconductor industry.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108255864-1769102920459-gettyimages-2256971421-BITGO_IPO.jpeg?v=1769102953&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s interim president says 626 prisoners freed but rights groups count 154</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuelas-interim-president-s-S0hinR.LQG2OcDJr6UpucQ</link>
      <description>Venezuela's interim president Delcy Rodriguez announced on Friday that 626 individuals have been released from prison as part of an ongoing initiative, though human rights organizations dispute the official figure, confirming far fewer releases.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rodriguez, who assumed interim leadership after U.S. forces captured former president Nicolas Maduro on January 3, made the announcement during the installation of a "Program for Coexistence and Peace" in Caracas. She did not provide a specific timeline for when these releases occurred.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2026-01-14T180613Z_2042008953_RC261JALUC9L_RTRMADP_3_USA-VENEZUELA-RODRIGUEZ-1768444465.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studies find AI language models mirror human brain in both processing and bias</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-language-models-mirror-huma-1E1tmu96QiSis0JKd0K52A</link>
      <description>Two new studies reveal that the systems powering AI chatbots like ChatGPT and Gemini share unexpected parallels with the human brain—not just in how they build meaning from words, but also in how they absorb social biases.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Research published in Nature Communications found that the human brain processes spoken language through a stepwise sequence that closely mirrors the layered architecture of large language models (LLMs). A separate study from the University of Vermont, posted to the arXiv preprint server, shows that widely used AI models exhibit "us vs. them" social biases similar to patterns documented in human psychology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/brain-ai-data-technology-artificial-intelligence-chip.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran warns any US attack will be treated as 'all-out war'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-warns-us-of-all-out-war-a-z0Sy8rtER3G2I1apEVFDhg</link>
      <description>Iran declared Friday that any military attack on its territory will be treated as "all-out war," issuing its starkest warning yet as a US aircraft carrier strike group steams toward the Middle East amid heightened tensions over the country's deadly crackdown on nationwide protests.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Any attack, limited or otherwise, will be treated as an all-out war against us, and we will respond in the hardest way possible," a senior Iranian official told Reuters, speaking on condition of anonymity. The warning came as Iranian forces remained on high alert ahead of the arrival of US military reinforcements in the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769214913/url_uploads/-1x-1_xxrqah.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon says South Korea will lead North Korea deterrence</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/pentagon-shifts-north-korea-de-mhldNGQES86WF6pX_BQlBg</link>
      <description>The Pentagon on Friday unveiled its National Defense Strategy, outlining a fundamental change in how the United States approaches security on the Korean Peninsula: South Korea will now be expected to take the lead in deterring North Korea, with Washington providing "more limited" support.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"South Korea is capable of taking primary responsibility for deterring North Korea with critical but more limited U.S. support," according to the document released Friday evening, as reported by Reuters. "This shift in the balance of responsibility is consistent with America's interest in updating U.S. force posture on the Korean Peninsula."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769216541/getty_uploads/2198761888_lvajmi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK-led mission to create artificial eclipses proposed to ESA</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mesom-mission-to-create-artifi-4WS5334gQqOUOBzHa_zGug</link>
      <description>An international consortium of scientists has proposed a spacecraft mission to generate artificial solar eclipses in space, offering unprecedented views of the Sun's atmosphere as Earth experiences its most severe solar radiation storm in over two decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Moon-Enabled Sun Occultation Mission, known as Mesom, has been submitted to the European Space Agency for consideration as a future mission. If approved, the mini-satellite would position itself within the Moon's shadow roughly once every 29.6 days, creating total eclipse conditions lasting up to 48 minutes—ten times longer than typical eclipses observed from Earth.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/714119/original/file-20260123-56-ni7t41.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;rect=0%252C512%252C2048%252C1024&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane-eating bacteria could turn pollution into plastics, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/methane-eating-microbes-turn-g-hnzAjoj9R1q3DdSWZENE5Q</link>
      <description>Bacteria that consume methane could transform one of the planet's most potent greenhouse gases into useful products including biodegradable plastics, animal feed, and cleaner fuels, according to a new scientific review examining rapid advances in methanotroph research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, published this week in the journal Energy &amp; Environment Nexus, positions methane-consuming bacteria as biological "gatekeepers" capable of both reducing climate-warming emissions and converting waste gases into valuable materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://seed.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/ThisGreenhouseGasTraps85TimesMoreHeat_Cultured_41025-2048x966.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese scientists achieve 10x boost in CO2-to-starch conversion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-scientists-achieve-10x-aYaq9Q2rRBm.IpTdRahVBQ</link>
      <description>Researchers at China's Tianjin Institute of Industrial Biotechnology have increased the productivity of their carbon dioxide-to-starch conversion technology by more than tenfold compared to their original 2021 breakthrough, according to a report published Friday by the Chinese Academy of Sciences-run China Science Daily.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The advance brings scientists closer to industrializing a process that could fundamentally reshape how one of the world's most important carbohydrates is produced, potentially eliminating the need for agricultural cultivation of corn and other starchy crops.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.i-scmp.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=contain%2Cwidth=1024%2Cformat=auto/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/23/6fd6b3e8-2054-4dcf-be2b-53075dbc4d63_f60200c9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens 100% tariffs if Canada proceeds with China deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-100-percent-ta-4a6TXc8.SpSTh8HBBrGEuA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump on Saturday threatened to impose a 100 percent tariff on all Canadian goods entering the United States if Canada proceeds with its newly signed trade agreement with China, dramatically escalating a week of diplomatic tensions with America's northern neighbor.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If Governor Carney thinks he is going to make Canada a 'Drop Off Port' for China to send goods and products into the United States, he is sorely mistaken," Trump wrote on Truth Social, referring to Prime Minister Mark Carney. "China will eat Canada alive, completely devour it, including the destruction of their businesses, social fabric, and general way of life."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d3i6fh83elv35t.cloudfront.net/static/2025/02/2025-01-31T211014Z_1374391267_RC28LCA72B6C_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP-1024x683.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold crosses $5,000 per ounce for the first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-price-surges-past-5000-as-n8ntkW1JTwSvcutEALA6ew</link>
      <description>Gold prices have breached the closely watched $5,000-per-ounce barrier for the first time, capping a historic rally fueled by a weakening U.S. dollar, robust central bank buying, and expectations of further Federal Reserve rate cuts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As of Saturday, January 24, 2026, spot gold traded at approximately $4,988 per ounce after establishing an intra-day record high above $5,009 earlier in the session. The precious metal has gained roughly 15% since the start of 2026 and nearly 80% compared to a year ago. Silver has been equally buoyant, with prices approaching $100 per ounce after hitting unprecedented highs in recent sessions.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108234177-1764563718395-gettyimages-2240539484-AUSTRALIA_GOLD.jpeg?v=1767720612&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China places two top generals under investigation in major purge</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-military-leaders-zhang-6A0kczJbSzChVt.srIGHbw</link>
      <description>China's highest-level military purge in decades became official on January 24, 2026, when state media confirmed that Zhang Youxia, vice chairman of the Central Military Commission and a member of the ruling Politburo, has been placed under investigation for "serious violations of discipline and law." Liu Zhenli, chief of the Joint Staff Department and a CMC member, is also being investigated, according to an announcement from the Ministry of National Defense.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The terse statement said the decision to open investigations into both senior military figures followed "deliberation by the Party's central leadership," providing no further details on the alleged violations.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769285741/url_uploads/im-83941943_vsblh2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump advisers meet Netanyahu to advance Gaza ceasefire talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/netanyahu-rejects-white-house-MhJEyUDnQyyFTPprIwcieQ</link>
      <description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu declined a direct White House request for President Isaac Herzog to represent Israel at the inauguration of President Trump's Gaza Board of Peace in Davos, Switzerland, resulting in Israel's notable absence from Thursday's ceremony and exposing tensions between Jerusalem and Washington as Trump's peace initiative advances into its second phase.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The White House extended invitations to 58 nations to join the Board of Peace, with Netanyahu himself receiving an invitation, according to Axios. However, due to an arrest warrant issued by the International Criminal Court in 2024, Netanyahu could not travel to Switzerland. With Herzog already attending the World Economic Forum, senior U.S. officials twice approached the Prime Minister's Office on Tuesday and Wednesday, proposing that Herzog sit on stage alongside Arab and Muslim leaders and sign the board's charter, according to Israel's Channel 12.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2025/10/WhatsApp-Image-2025-10-09-at-23.27.52-e1760042848341.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US envoys meet Netanyahu to discuss Gaza reconstruction plan</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/israel-backs-palestinian-milit-TtOhMwMBS.mw8cgZzJXzZg</link>
      <description>An anti-Hamas militia operating under Israeli control has claimed responsibility for the assassination of a senior Hamas police chief in Gaza, as US special envoys arrived in Israel on Saturday to discuss the future of the war-torn territory with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The targeted killing on January 12 by the Popular Forces militia reflects Israel's growing reliance on Palestinian armed groups to combat Hamas in areas it controls, even as the Trump administration pushes forward with its ambitious "Board of Peace" plan to rebuild Gaza.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769309160/url_uploads/WhatsApp-Image-2025-10-09-at-23.27.52-e1760042848341_mrfgxz.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
