<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:25:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists race to drill into 'Doomsday Glacier' as weather threatens mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/antarctica-s-thwaites-glacier-H4vXlQyYRXSF0I8NCp9rMQ</link>
      <description>Hundreds of previously undetected earthquakes are rattling Antarctica's Thwaites Glacier, while an international team of scientists aboard a Korean icebreaker struggles against harsh weather to drill into the massive ice sheet that could reshape the world's coastlines if it collapses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A study published in Geophysical Research Letters by seismologist Thanh-Son Phạm of the Australian National University detected 362 glacial earthquakes in West Antarctica between 2010 and 2023, with 245 of them occurring at Thwaites—nicknamed the "Doomsday Glacier" because its collapse could trigger catastrophic sea level rise. The earthquakes, caused by massive icebergs capsizing as they calve from the glacier, were largely missed by global seismic networks due to their low-frequency waves.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It is a lot less stable and has been hit by hundreds of iceberg earthquakes," Phạm told Gizmodo, noting that the most prolific period of seismic activity between 2018 and 2020 coincided with an accelerated flow of the glacier's ice tongue toward the sea.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://helios-i.mashable.com/imagery/articles/07v9PNYqUNJgHBK5fKBepgo/hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.v1662677776.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China kicks off 2026 with back-to-back satellite launches</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-files-record-200000-sate-88iiBcmeSjSmrZFtAknWBg</link>
      <description>China opened 2026 with a flurry of space activity on Monday, launching two separate satellite missions within hours of each other while recent filings reveal Beijing's intention to deploy an unprecedented 200,000 satellites, dramatically escalating the competition for low-Earth orbit dominance.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_%21AMvy%21%2Cw_1200%2Ch_675%2Cc_fill%2Cf_jpg%2Cq_auto:good%2Cfl_progressive:steep%2Cg_auto/https%253A%252F%252Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fpublic%252Fimages%252Fa553ea3d-6ca8-4bf5-9c8c-0041a0aea827_6149x3299.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fungal network researcher wins 'Nobel Prize for Environment'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/toby-kiers-wins-tyler-prize-fo-MX9R74EWR0.LDJac3r4aoQ</link>
      <description>Evolutionary biologist Toby Kiers has won the 2026 Tyler Prize for Environmental Achievement, often called the "Nobel Prize for Environment," for her research into underground fungal networks that play a crucial role in regulating Earth's climate.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Tyler Prize Executive Committee announced Tuesday that Kiers, a professor at Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, is being honored for her "transformative research on the significance of mycorrhizal fungi in underground transfers, biodiversity, and climate resilience." She is the youngest female recipient in the prize's history and will receive the $250,000 award at a ceremony in Amsterdam on April 23.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.macfound.org/media/fellows/download_photos/kiers_2025_hi-res-download_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists question studies claiming microplastics in human brains</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-question-microplast-SGHE7ZUmRnebor7MmOWOkw</link>
      <description>Prominent research claiming microplastics have infiltrated human brains, arteries, and organs is facing serious scrutiny, with analytical chemists warning that many findings may be artifacts of contamination and false positives rather than actual plastic particles.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The controversy, reported by The Guardian this week, has cast doubt on a body of research that had fueled growing public alarm about the health effects of plastic pollution. Seven studies have now been formally challenged by researchers publishing criticism in the same journals where the original papers appeared, while a recent analysis flagged 18 additional studies for allegedly failing to account for human tissue producing measurements easily confused with common plastics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/1024x683%2B0%2B0/resize/1024x683%21/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fcb%252F2c%252F01e240ee4d059e9abb620fad8881%252Fgettyimages-2176740635.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's car exports topped 7 million in 2025 as EV sales boomed</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-car-exports-jump-21-perc-sN6v2gwkS4ufwvaRVF9a6A</link>
      <description>China's automobile exports surged 21 percent in 2025 to exceed 7 million vehicles, propelled by booming overseas shipments of electric vehicles even as demand at home showed signs of strain, the China Association of Automobile Manufacturers reported Wednesday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The figures underscore a pivotal shift for the world's largest automotive market: Chinese automakers are increasingly looking abroad for growth as fierce domestic price wars and waning consumer confidence weigh on local sales. Exports of new energy vehicles, including battery-electric and plug-in hybrid models, doubled from the previous year to reach 2.6 million units.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://theedgemalaysia.com/_next/image?url=https%253A%252F%252Fassets.theedgemarkets.com%252Fchina%2520ev%2520cars%2520auto%2520export_20250926190133_Bloomberg_1.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toyota raises buyout bid 15% after Elliott pressure</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/toyota-raises-toyota-industrie-agZ22U7dRH6iPdHmbqPRzg</link>
      <description>Toyota Motor announced Wednesday it has increased its bid to take Toyota Industries private to ¥18,800 per share, up 15% from the original ¥16,300 offer made in June, caving to pressure from activist investor Elliott Investment Management.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The revised tender offer, set to begin Thursday and run through February 12, values the forklift manufacturer at approximately ¥5.6 trillion ($35 billion). The increase represents a win for shareholder activism in Japan, where no entity has previously challenged a company of Toyota's magnitude.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/2LIJTD7CLFM6FJ5JR4T62OYFTM.jpg?auth=501b8d9fb90ab71dea33c3db6a80ab93fcc359a703af4ff9643586cd063d3fd3&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China installs world's largest offshore wind turbine</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-achieves-milestones-in-w-JmNiiYWeTWmERx1XfbuXKA</link>
      <description>China has reached two notable advances in wind energy within the span of a week, successfully testing the world's first megawatt-class airborne wind power system and installing a record-breaking 20-megawatt offshore turbine.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://interestingengineering.com/_next/image?url=https%253A%252F%252Fcms.interestingengineering.com%252Fwp-content%252Fuploads%252F2026%252F01%252FWT-C.jpg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists open ice sanctuary in Antarctica to preserve melting glaciers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-create-first-antarc-cI3Y4UT0TB.1FsBG5FyYqg</link>
      <description>Researchers sealed ancient glacial ice from the European Alps in a purpose-built cave at Antarctica's Concordia Station on Wednesday, inaugurating the world's first sanctuary designed to preserve climate records from melting glaciers for centuries to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Ice Memory Foundation placed its first two ice cores, extracted from Grand Combin glacier in Switzerland and Mont Blanc in France, into a 35-meter-long cave dug approximately 10 meters below the Antarctic surface, where temperatures remain stable at minus 52 degrees Celsius year-round without any need for artificial refrigeration.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"To safeguard what would be otherwise irreversibly lost... is an endeavour for humanity," said Thomas Stocker, a Swiss climate scientist and chair of the Ice Memory Foundation, which spearheaded the initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.antarctica.gov.au/site/assets/files/76153/3_jan_buried_ice_container.1200x0.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global markets await U.S. inflation report</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/global-markets-rise-ahead-of-u-LZC.TLMRRUeSzMQupiYeUA</link>
      <description>Markets across Asia and Europe mostly advanced on Wednesday as investors awaited U.S. producer price and retail sales data, while Wall Street futures slipped ahead of another round of major bank earnings.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Japan's benchmark Nikkei 225 surged 1.5% to 54,341.23, extending a record-breaking rally fueled by speculation that Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi may call early elections. The broader Topix also climbed to new highs. Elsewhere in Asia, Hong Kong's Hang Seng added 0.6% to 26,999.81, while China's Shanghai Composite shed 0.3% to 4,126.09.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108248207-1767629784618-Traders-Photo-OB-MW-20260105-PRESS-6.jpg?v=1767629845&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some US personnel told to leave largest Middle East base in Qatar</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/some-us-personnel-told-to-leav-wluoSLpPSAqyunT8QtCOjA</link>
      <description>Some personnel at the U.S. military's Al Udeid Air Base in Qatar were advised to leave by Wednesday evening, according to three diplomats who spoke to Reuters, raising concerns about possible military action against Iran amid escalating tensions between Washington and Tehran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The U.S. Embassy in Doha has not provided an immediate comment on the advisory. Al Udeid serves as the largest American military installation in the Middle East, accommodating approximately 10,000 service members. A similar precautionary evacuation occurred ahead of U.S. airstrikes on Iran's nuclear facilities in June 2025, when personnel were moved off U.S. bases in the region before Iran launched retaliatory missile strikes on the base.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EIKDBDBNZJNXBAEAABCATELTV4.jpg?auth=bf6c202cc342efcbbbb20f9514e0bdb415ffb9ba9827c9ba1a3314854767dcab&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese scientists develop 'soggy sand' battery that lasts 1,700 cycles</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-researchers-extend-zin-.FouXC8ZRm.yTeLqtF6DFw</link>
      <description>Scientists at the Dalian Institute of Chemical Physics (DICP) of the Chinese Academy of Sciences have developed a novel "soggy sand" electrolyte that enables aqueous zinc metal batteries to achieve 1,700 charge-discharge cycles while operating at temperatures up to 140°C—a breakthrough that could accelerate the shift away from lithium-ion technology for grid-scale energy storage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, published in Nature Communications in December 2025, addresses one of the most persistent challenges facing aqueous zinc batteries: their tendency to fail under thermal stress due to uncontrollable side reactions in traditional water-based electrolytes above 60°C.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://undecidedmf.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Featured.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran's judiciary chief vows swift trials and executions for protesters</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-judiciary-signals-swift-t-6FCcQAEFQeeaaPPw3nVRPQ</link>
      <description>Iran's chief of judiciary announced on Wednesday that rapid trials and possible executions will proceed for thousands of protesters detained during nationwide demonstrations, directly challenging President Donald Trump's warning that the United States would take "very strong action" if the Islamic Republic begins hanging dissidents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Gholamhossein Mohseni-Ejei made the statement in a video broadcast by Iranian state television, emphasizing urgency: "If we want to do a job, we should do it now. If we want to do something, we have to do it quickly. If it becomes late, two months, three months later, it doesn't have the same effect."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came as human rights organizations reported that Erfan Soltani, a 26-year-old clothing seller from Fardis near Tehran, was scheduled to become the first protester executed in connection with the unrest. His fate remained uncertain Wednesday, with the Hengaw Organization for Human Rights unable to confirm whether the execution had been carried out amid Iran's ongoing communications blackout.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2026-01-12t181324z-496612350-rc2pziazzjov-rtrmadp-3-iran-economy-protests.jpg?c=original" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark deploys troops to Greenland as officials meet at White House</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/denmark-deploys-advanced-troop-vCuL2YoqROymG1WkaGj_dw</link>
      <description>Denmark announced on Wednesday it is deploying military units and equipment to Greenland starting immediately, as officials from Copenhagen and Nuuk arrived at the White House for high-stakes talks over President Donald Trump's escalating demands to acquire the Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The Danish armed forces are, from today, deploying capabilities and units related to exercise activities. In the period ahead, this will result in an increased military presence in and around Greenland, comprising aircraft, vessels and soldiers, including from NATO allies," the Danish Defense Ministry said in a statement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.newsweek.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AP25346538084040.jpg?w=1200crop%253D1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI triples scientist output but shrinks research scope, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-boosts-scientist-output-but-0lLSxp6ESJqep2Cbyr3mTA</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence has created a paradox in science: tools that supercharge individual researchers are simultaneously shrinking the collective scope of scientific exploration, according to a major study published in Nature.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, conducted by James Evans of the University of Chicago and colleagues, analyzed more than 41 million research papers spanning biology, medicine, chemistry, physics, materials science, and geology from 1980 to 2025. The findings reveal that scientists who adopt AI publish 3.02 times as many papers and receive nearly five times as many citations as their peers who do not use AI. They also reach leadership positions about 1.5 years earlier.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Yet this individual success comes at a cost to the broader scientific enterprise. AI-driven research covers 4.6% less topical territory than conventional studies and spawns 22% less engagement between papers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.nature.com/lw1200/magazine-assets/d41586-023-02980-0/d41586-023-02980-0_26083722.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musk denies Grok generated explicit images of minors</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/musk-denies-knowledge-of-grok-CHRwIm1bT86DdNsBBPfZzw</link>
      <description>Elon Musk said on Wednesday he was unaware of any explicit images of minors generated by his xAI chatbot Grok, even as global regulatory pressure against the AI tool reached a fever pitch with government investigations spanning three continents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I not aware of any naked underage images generated by Grok. Literally zero," Musk wrote in a post on X, his social media platform. "Obviously, Grok does not spontaneously generate images, it does so only according to user requests. When asked to generate images, it will refuse to produce anything illegal, as the operating principle for Grok is to obey the laws of the given country or state."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The remarks come as xAI faces investigations from California Attorney General Rob Bonta, the UK communications regulator Ofcom, and mounting calls from U.S. lawmakers to remove Grok from app stores operated by Apple and Google.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768411802/getty_uploads/2255514345_atgepf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half the world's major river deltas sink faster than seas rise</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/major-river-deltas-sink-faster-14a6flasQPmeB.aMrVS6.A</link>
      <description>Nearly half of the world's largest river deltas, including the Nile, Ganges, and Mekong, are sinking faster than global sea levels are rising, according to new research published Wednesday in Nature. The study warns that more than 236 million people face heightened flooding risk as human-caused land subsidence emerges as the dominant threat to these coastal regions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, led by scientists at the University of California, Irvine and Virginia Tech, provides the first high-resolution, delta-wide assessment of elevation loss across 40 major river deltas spanning five continents. Using satellite radar data collected between 2014 and 2023, the team found that 18 of those deltas are experiencing average annual subsidence rates that exceed the current global sea-level rise rate of about 4 millimeters per year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/14121207/SEI_280652732.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope's mysterious 'little red dots' are young black holes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-identify-little-red-XeGg3Q7oT8uJJA3NY2pvPg</link>
      <description>Since the James Webb Space Telescope began operations in late 2021, one of its most perplexing discoveries has been hundreds of tiny, unexplained red points scattered throughout images of the early universe. Now, researchers from the University of Copenhagen have cracked the mystery: these "little red dots" are young supermassive black holes hidden within dense cocoons of ionized gas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published Wednesday in Nature, reveal that these enigmatic objects are far less massive than scientists initially believed—about 100 times smaller—yet still weigh up to 10 million times the mass of our Sun.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/are-the-jwsts-little-r-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink now free in Iran as France weighs satellite aid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starlink-and-france-aid-irania-oFkgssEmTViOhLxIgb8ovA</link>
      <description>SpaceX's Starlink satellite internet service is now available for free in Iran, activists confirmed Wednesday, as France announced it is exploring sending Eutelsat terminals to the country to help citizens circumvent a communications blackout during the deadliest protests in the Islamic Republic in decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dual initiatives represent an international effort to restore information flows as the death toll from Iran's brutal crackdown on demonstrators has surpassed 2,500, according to the U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA), which reported at least 2,571 dead as of early Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UUPSBECOJKERR3MMQAXRL5S3GI_size-normalized.jpg&amp;w=1600&amp;h=900" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia's allies question Moscow's support as Ukraine war drains resources</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/putin-s-allies-feel-abandoned-HnD45qt.Tz6aXs903x5ZnQ</link>
      <description>Russia’s closest partners from Venezuela to Iran and Cuba are reassessing what Moscow’s backing is worth, after a series of crises in which Vladimir Putin’s government appeared either unable—or unwilling—to step in.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The clearest warning sign has come in Venezuela, where the U.S. operation that captured President Nicolás Maduro on Jan. 3 has exposed gaps in the security ecosystem Caracas built with Russian and Cuban help—and showcased the limits of Russia’s power projection as it remains fixated on Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2024-10-23T175441Z_1457612730_RC2HQAA7V1WW_RTRMADP_3_RUSSIA-BRICS-1767693098.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare alignment to offer glimpse of interstellar comet's dust</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-interstellar-alignment-NvHqesOlRq2pVo8S0.D82w</link>
      <description>Astronomers are preparing for an unprecedented observational window when interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS aligns with the Sun-Earth axis on January 22, 2026, offering scientists what researchers describe as a once-in-decades opportunity to study pristine material from another star system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A new research paper published this week by Harvard astrophysicist Avi Loeb and Italian astronomer Mauro Barbieri of Italy's National Institute for Astrophysics (INAF) details how the rare geometric alignment will enable measurements of the comet's dust composition that have never been possible with interstellar visitors.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d4hal6uazahag.cloudfront.net/777226/uploads/d0f3f150-af39-11f0-8e18-894a335485f1_1200_630.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
