<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:24:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Gold surges as Trump warns Iran amid 2026 market uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/experts-predict-uncertainty-fo-keCoAev0T.a_9mLH8.4F5A</link>
      <description>As 2026 begins, investors and policymakers are confronting a landscape defined by elevated geopolitical tensions and divergent economic forecasts, with Asia caught between U.S. policy unpredictability and Middle Eastern instability that sent gold surging above $4,300 per ounce on the year's first trading day.

Escalating U.S.-Iran tensions dominated early market sentiment, with President Donald Trump issuing a "locked and loaded" warning on January 2 following massive protests in Iran sparked by inflation exceeding 42%[1]. The rhetoric rekindled fears of direct military conflict after U.S. and Israeli forces reportedly struck Iranian nuclear facilities in June 2025, pushing investors toward safe-haven assets[1]. Meanwhile, experts warn that the Middle East's "armed peace" remains fragile, with analysts at SpecialEurasia assessing that the region faces "high-probability" prospects of renewed Israeli-Iranian conflict in early 2026[2].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--AN67pfup--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/02/multimedia/02db-market-pgtk/02db-market-pgtk-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 ranked among three hottest years on record</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/2025-breaks-global-and-uk-heat-9jmfwDZRTWGa2f_retn5uA</link>
      <description>Scientists confirmed Friday that 2025 was among the three hottest years ever recorded globally while the United Kingdom experienced its warmest and sunniest year since measurements began, marking a milestone in the accelerating climate crisis as the three-year temperature average exceeded the Paris Agreement's 1.5°C warming threshold for the first time[1][2][3][4][5].

The Met Office reported the UK's mean temperature reached 10.09°C in 2025, surpassing the previous record of 10.03°C set in 2022[3][4][5]. The reading makes 2025 only the second year since 1884 that the UK's annual temperature has topped 10°C, and places four of the last five years in the top five warmest on record[3][4][5]. The UK also recorded 1648.5 hours of sunshine, 61.4 hours more than the previous record set in 2003[4][6].

Globally, 2025 ranked as one of the three hottest years recorded, joining 2023 and trailing 2024, which the World Meteorological Organization confirmed in January as the warmest year at 1.55°C above pre-industrial levels[2][7][8]. More concerning to climate scientists, the three-year period from 2023 to 2025 marked the first time the running temperature average broke through the 1.5°C threshold established in the 2015 Paris Agreement[2][9][10][11].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--7ORIpCxy--/t_thumbnail/https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/8299dc8f-6930-4967-bba6-7b2f3bbe8fb8/wirestory_1e9028da87e518382482e21fef3cfeee_16x9.jpg%3Fw%3D1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump orders US military strikes on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-orders-us-military-strik-.bzAR1eyS_OEhQ_OLFvhAA</link>
      <description>Multiple explosions rocked Venezuela's capital Caracas in the early hours of Saturday as President Trump ordered military strikes on Venezuelan military facilities, marking a dramatic escalation in Washington's pressure campaign against the Maduro regime[1][2][3].

At least seven explosions were heard around 2 a.m. local time, accompanied by low-flying aircraft and power outages in several neighborhoods, according to witnesses and international reporting[4][5][3]. The strikes targeted key military installations including Fuerte Tiuna, Venezuela's largest military complex, and La Carlota Air Base in eastern Caracas[5][6][7]. Reports also indicated strikes on El Libertador Air Force Base in Maracay, a strategic hub for Venezuela's air force[6][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--cDyqC4T4--/t_thumbnail/https://assets.newsweek.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/2935776.jpg%3Fw%3D1200crop%253D1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump claims Maduro captured after US strikes Caracas</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-captures-venezuelan-preside-XFdRY2sQSvmBuE6Yn3vnrA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced early Saturday that the United States successfully captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife following military airstrikes on Caracas, though the claim could not be independently verified as of Saturday morning.

"The United States of America has successfully carried out a large scale strike against Venezuela and its leader, President Nicolas Maduro, who has been, along with his wife, captured and flown out of the Country," Trump wrote on Truth Social[1][2][3][4]. The operation was conducted "in conjunction with U.S. Law Enforcement," and Trump said he would hold a press conference at 11 a.m. at his Mar-a-Lago estate[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--yPjaJnB9--/t_thumbnail/https://assets3.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2025/09/09/79b1b9f5-18dd-4355-a676-fe1f1226ad55/thumbnail/1200x630/50564e4e7dee3782e5e72e8c75533bc2/trump-maduro.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro and wife indicted on narco-terrorism charges</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/maduro-and-wife-face-narco-ter-WlntkUgIRJiChb..KcD4NQ</link>
      <description>US Attorney General Pam Bondi announced Saturday that Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife Cilia Flores have been indicted in the Southern District of New York on multiple charges including narco-terrorism conspiracy, cocaine importation, and weapons offenses[1][2][3]. The announcement came hours after President Donald Trump confirmed that US forces had captured the couple following a large-scale military strike on Venezuela early Saturday morning[4][5][6].

"They will soon face the full wrath of American justice on American soil in American courts," Bondi wrote on social media[1][2][7]. The charges against Maduro include narco-terrorism conspiracy, cocaine importation conspiracy, possession of machine guns and destructive devices, and conspiracy to possess such weapons against the United States[2][3][6]. While specific charges against Flores were not detailed in Bondi's statement, the attorney general thanked Trump "for having the courage to demand accountability on behalf of the American People"[7][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--2PA3Omb_--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/3177x1787%2B0%2B166/resize/1400/quality/100/format/jpeg/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252F5f%252F93%252F84c158db4703bdf40f243b4fac05%252Fap25010532842611.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says US will govern Venezuela after Maduro capture</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-us-will-run-ve-IcRpWNQOSCiqOC3vGubQAg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared Saturday that the United States would govern Venezuela until a safe transition could be organized, marking an unprecedented assertion of American control over a sovereign nation in the Western Hemisphere following a dramatic overnight military operation that captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro[1][2][3].

"We're going to run the country until such time as we can do a safe, proper and judicious transition," Trump said at a press conference at his Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida[1][3]. "So we don't want to be involved with having somebody else get in, and we have the same situation that we had for the last long period of years."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--AK37nCEP--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AP26003246538765-1767424202.jpg%3Fresize%3D1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European advisers back $740B Ukraine aid plan</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/european-security-advisers-bac-ufWbNoP_TeKw4buFbzId6w</link>
      <description>National security advisers from across Europe convened in Kyiv on Saturday to advance a US-led peace proposal and coordinate international support for Ukraine, marking a pivotal moment in diplomatic efforts to end Russia's nearly four-year war.

Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy said the talks achieved progress on three fronts: security guarantees, reconstruction, and "a basic framework for a real rebuilding."[1] Representatives from Canada, NATO, and over a dozen European nations participated in the high-level discussions, which Ukraine's chief negotiator Rustem Umerov described as focusing on "security and economic issues, work on framework documents, and coordination of further steps with partners."[2][3]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--oc69_kqm--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108112527-1741342483713-gettyimages-2201176806-HL_ACORNU_2677011.jpeg%3Fv%3D1741342660%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US capture of Maduro draws international condemnation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-capture-of-maduro-draws-int-z4ZXJLnGTLKLIwO34uWrPw</link>
      <description>World leaders expressed deep concern and sharp divisions over the US military operation in Venezuela on Saturday, with the United Nations and major powers condemning the strikes as a dangerous violation of international law while some regional allies celebrated the capture of President Nicolás Maduro.

UN Secretary-General António Guterres said he was "deeply alarmed" by the overnight operation, warning that "these developments constitute a dangerous precedent," according to his spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric[1][2]. Guterres emphasized "the importance of full respect—by all—of international law, including the UN Charter" and expressed concern that "the rules of international law have not been respected"[1][3]. Venezuela has requested an emergency meeting of the UN Security Council[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ZbXpktLQ--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/5842x3286%2B0%2B304/resize/1400/quality/100/format/jpeg/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fb7%252F1f%252F022981374aaf951ffe13654ed8e2%252Fap26003462413795.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US seizes Maduro in strike, threatening Canada's oil dominance</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-captures-maduro-impacting-c-hNC3Ztn.Rlu7q1qLt1UeQg</link>
      <description>In the predawn hours of Saturday, US special forces captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro in a military strike on Caracas, a dramatic escalation that could eventually reshape North American oil markets and erode Canada's dominant position as America's top crude supplier.

President Donald Trump announced at a Mar-a-Lago press conference that Maduro and his wife were seized by Delta Force operators and flown out of Venezuela to face narco-terrorism charges in New York[1][2]. The operation, dubbed "Absolute Resolve," involved 150 aircraft and lasted approximately two hours[3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 22:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--zR2n2ADl--/t_thumbnail/https://static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2025/12/oil-venezuela-refinery-stacks.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump defends skipping Congress briefing on Venezuela raid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-defends-not-notifying-co-AMDy0REjR7.rDCDdZeFFOw</link>
      <description>President Trump and Secretary of State Marco Rubio defended their decision to bypass congressional notification before an overnight military operation that captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro on Saturday, arguing that advance warning could have jeopardized the mission due to potential leaks from Capitol Hill.

"Congress has a tendency to leak," Trump said during a Saturday press conference at Mar-a-Lago[1][2][3]. "This would not be good. If they leaked...I think maybe it would have been a very different result."

The administration's decision not to brief the so-called "Gang of Eight"—the top congressional leaders and chairs and ranking members of the House and Senate intelligence committees—before the operation has sparked sharp criticism from Democrats and some Republicans who argue it violated the War Powers Act[4][5][6]. The 1973 law requires the president to consult with Congress "in every possible instance" before introducing forces into hostilities or situations where imminent hostilities are likely[3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 22:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767478174/url_uploads/im-73367360_zlfuqe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council to meet Monday on U.S. capture of Maduro</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/international-condemnation-as-EuWpNLGFTK6R1wkSt8GKWg</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council will convene an emergency session Monday morning to address the U.S. military operation in Venezuela that resulted in the capture of President Nicolás Maduro, following widespread international condemnation and warnings that the strikes set a "dangerous precedent" for global order[1][2][3].

UN Secretary-General António Guterres expressed deep alarm at the overnight events, stating through his spokesperson that "these developments constitute a dangerous precedent" and that he remains "deeply concerned that the rules of international law have not been respected"[1][4][5]. The 15-member Security Council meeting, scheduled for 10 a.m. Monday, was requested by Venezuela and Colombia with support from Russia and China[6][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 22:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Tx1eydw7--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/CORQYBRJS5KXPMHLQ3NPWUMEKQ.jpg%3Fauth%3De671a3fd8fdd275a183fa4eba36474ad031a796008a7e9dd042d308952b6dbb0%26height%3D1005%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80%26smart%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caracas residents hunker down after US captures Maduro</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuelans-in-caracas-hunker-yiTUfx0NS_yTQwCa2VnYdQ</link>
      <description>Hours after US forces captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro in an overnight military strike, the streets of Caracas remained largely deserted Saturday as residents grappled with an uncertain future and Venezuelan officials demanded proof their leader was still alive.

The capital awoke to desolate streets patrolled by security forces following explosions that began around 2 a.m. local time[1][2]. Parts of southern Caracas remained without electricity after strikes targeted the Fuerte Tiuna military base and La Carlota airbase[2][3], while smoke continued billowing from the Port of La Guaira to the north[1][4]. Downtown Caracas smelled of gunpowder, according to CNN reporters[5].

President Donald Trump announced on Truth Social that Maduro and his wife, Cilia Flores, had been "captured and flown out of the country" following what he called a "large-scale strike"[6][7]. The operation, which Trump said was conducted with US law enforcement, marked the first such American military intervention in Latin America since the 1989 Panama invasion that ousted Manuel Noriega[1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 22:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--25t3SSgD--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/03/multimedia/03us-venezuela-streets-react-topart-sub-zgwb/03us-venezuela-streets-react-topart-sub-zgwb-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK and France strike ISIS weapons site in Syria</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uk-and-france-conduct-joint-ai-DRDRGr.IQM.dWTUJWkMI7g</link>
      <description>British and French air forces launched a coordinated strike Saturday evening on a suspected ISIS weapons facility in the mountains north of Palmyra, Syria, marking the latest Western operation to prevent the terror group's resurgence in the region[1][2][3][4][5].

RAF Typhoon FGR4 jets, supported by a Voyager refueling tanker, joined French aircraft in targeting multiple access tunnels leading to an underground site believed to store weapons and explosives[1][3][6][7]. The operation used Paveway IV guided bombs, with initial assessments indicating successful engagement of the target[1][2][8][7]. Britain's Ministry of Defence confirmed all aircraft returned safely and that the remote location was devoid of civilian habitation[1][3][8][7][9].

"This action shows our UK leadership, and determination to stand shoulder to shoulder with our allies, to stamp out any resurgence of Daesh and their dangerous and violent ideologies in the Middle East," British Defence Secretary John Healey said, using an alternative name for ISIS[1][4][5][9].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Rx8kJdAG--/t_thumbnail/https://uknip.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/raf-typhoons-strike-isis-underground-weapons-facility-in-syria-alongside-french-forces-using-paveway-bombs-as-mod-confirms-no-civilian-risk-1767481893-dbjds2.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US military captures Maduro in Venezuela operation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuelans-worldwide-celebrat-DSvJoqXzQNCsJ0O6JC4T0g</link>
      <description>Venezuelans across the globe erupted in jubilation Saturday after US forces captured President Nicolás Maduro in a predawn military operation, ending his authoritarian rule that prompted one of the world's largest migration crises in recent history.

In the early hours of January 3, the United States launched "Operation Absolute Resolve," a massive strike involving more than 150 aircraft that disabled Venezuela's air defenses and extracted Maduro and his wife, Cilia Flores, from the presidential compound in Caracas[1][2]. President Donald Trump announced at a Mar-a-Lago press conference that Maduro had been "captured and flown out of the country" and would face drug trafficking charges in New York[1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 01:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--r8hVLrEk--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/a84ede0/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3600x1890%2B0%2B78/resize/1200x630%21/quality/90/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fc6%252F59%252F03cd30104dc481c5bf08e39c928a%252Fmia-100venezueladoral03newppp.jfif" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan VP rejects Trump claim, demands Maduro release</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuelan-vp-rodriguez-defies-Nj721C0FT16NHB40R_LqmA</link>
      <description>Venezuelan Vice President Delcy Rodríguez publicly rejected President Trump's assertion that she had assumed power as interim president following the U.S. capture of Nicolás Maduro, instead demanding the authoritarian leader's release in a televised address that underscored the immediate obstacles facing Washington's efforts to govern the South American nation[1][2][3].

In a Saturday morning press conference at Mar-a-Lago, Trump claimed that Rodríguez "was just sworn in as president" and had told Secretary of State Marco Rubio she was "essentially willing to do what we think is necessary to make Venezuela great again"[4][5]. Within hours, however, Rodríguez appeared on Venezuelan state television flanked by the country's National Defense Council—including the defense minister, attorney general, and legislative and judicial leaders—to denounce the U.S. military operation as "an aggression, a military aggression unprecedented against the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela"[6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--VflFlPAp--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/03/multimedia/03us-venezuela-delcy-defiant-topart-bpcf/03us-venezuela-delcy-defiant-topart-bpcf-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At least 40 killed in US raid capturing Maduro, Venezuelan official says</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/at-least-40-killed-in-us-raid-b.O6k5yIQ3S618.g51nhwg</link>
      <description>At least 40 people, including civilians and soldiers, were killed in the U.S. military strikes on Venezuela early Saturday that resulted in the capture of President Nicolás Maduro, according to a senior Venezuelan official cited by The New York Times[1]. Official casualty figures remain pending as Venezuelan authorities continue to assess the toll from the two-hour operation dubbed "Absolute Resolve."

Venezuelan Vice President Delcy Rodríguez confirmed deaths among both civilians and military personnel without providing specific numbers[2][3][4]. "Innocent victims have been mortally wounded and others killed by this criminal terrorist attack," Attorney General Tarek William Saab said in a televised statement[5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767492384/url_uploads/03us-venezuela-apartment-strike2-zvlc-articleLarge_h802pn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela oil exports halt amid U.S. blockade, Maduro capture</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-halts-oil-exports-am-U0AvODpQRey9p54ll5evCw</link>
      <description>Venezuela's oil exports have come to a near standstill as tankers avoid the South American nation amid an escalating U.S. naval blockade and the dramatic capture of President Nicolás Maduro on Saturday. The paralysis threatens to further cripple the economy of a country sitting atop the world's largest proven oil reserves.

Following weeks of mounting pressure, including vessel seizures and sanctions, oil shipments from Venezuela have effectively ceased, with only tankers chartered by Chevron continuing operations under special U.S. authorization. More than 11 million barrels of crude remain stranded on vessels in Venezuelan waters, while the country's storage facilities have filled to capacity, forcing state oil company PDVSA to shut in wells across its main production region[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--uND62ot9--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/6MTDJNCXZZMJ3GAZ6O6YDTBA6U.jpg%3Fauth%3D8dd81d68c6cc47f9ae7855252d9e44b9a8007e67804a1f8e065aa2a61f24d270%26height%3D1005%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80%26smart%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela court orders VP Rodriguez to assume presidential powers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-grants-vp-rodriguez-h4od9PW7R1CgPO04fUJffw</link>
      <description>Venezuela's Supreme Court ordered Vice President Delcy Rodriguez to immediately assume all presidential powers in an acting capacity on Saturday, establishing legal continuity for the government one day after U.S. forces captured President Nicolás Maduro in a dramatic overnight raid[1][2][3].

The Constitutional Chamber of the Supreme Court of Justice issued the order on January 3, directing Rodriguez to take charge of the presidency to guarantee "administrative continuity" and the "defense of the nation" following what the court described as Maduro's forced absence[1]. Rodriguez, 56, stepped into the role Saturday afternoon, hours after the U.S. military operation[2][3].

Under Venezuela's constitution, the executive vice president assumes presidential duties when the president becomes temporarily or permanently unavailable to serve[2][3][4]. Articles 233 and 234 outline the succession process, making Rodriguez's assumption of power the legally prescribed course of action[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Xe0lTdsj--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/03/multimedia/03us-venezuela-maduro-inner-circle-topart-gzqk/03us-venezuela-maduro-inner-circle-topart-gzqk-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine, allies advance $800B economic package at Kyiv talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/european-security-advisers-bac-ksB8o.81RIeExswinURsYw</link>
      <description>National security advisers from approximately 18 countries convened in Kyiv on Saturday to advance a U.S.-led peace framework for Ukraine, including an $800 billion economic support package designed to sustain the country's recovery and growth over the next decade[1][2][3][4].

The high-level talks, which brought together representatives from Germany, the United Kingdom, France, Italy, Poland, and other European nations, as well as NATO and European Union officials, mark a critical step in efforts to end the nearly four-year war[2][5]. Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said all documents under discussion, including those on security guarantees, had been shared with the advisers, allowing work to accelerate[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 03:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--K73qEJLE--/t_thumbnail/https://d3i6fh83elv35t.cloudfront.net/static/2026/01/2026-01-03T125941Z_909217260_RC2KTIARL62T_RTRMADP_3_UKRAINE-CRISIS-TALKS-ADVISORS-1024x682.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No alien signals found from 3I/ATLAS interstellar object</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-shows-no-alien-signals-NWipmojZQVSoH6aGU.P.TQ</link>
      <description>The world's most sensitive radio telescope has found no evidence of artificial signals from 3I/ATLAS, the largest interstellar object ever detected, according to results published this week by the Breakthrough Listen program[1][2][3]. Yet the mysterious visitor continues to captivate astronomers with unusual features that challenge conventional understanding of comets.

On December 18, one day before the object's closest approach to Earth, the 100-meter Green Bank Telescope in West Virginia scanned 3I/ATLAS across radio frequencies from 1 to 12 gigahertz[3][4][5]. The search, conducted by a team led by astronomer Ben Jacobson-Bell of the University of California, Berkeley, initially flagged 471,198 potential signals[4][6]. After filtering out interference, nine candidates remained—all of which were traced to human-made radio noise on Earth[2][4].

"No artificial radio emission localized to 3I/ATLAS was detected," the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence Institute confirmed[1][2][7]. The telescope was sensitive enough to detect transmitters as weak as 100 milliwatts, roughly the power of a mobile phone[8][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--FNrg9Ina--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/9Su_TQooIvR2jdjJaDuRrw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02MzA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/futurism_981/3cf62feeb4b6e6eb2782650b079ca99b" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
