<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:38:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Holocaust survivors urge action against rising hatred on 81st anniversary of Auschwitz liberation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/world-marks-international-holo-gOzU1HUzSxu_PB1EE.PS3A</link>
      <description>Holocaust survivors, world leaders, and ordinary citizens gathered at ceremonies across Europe and beyond on Tuesday to commemorate International Holocaust Remembrance Day, marking 81 years since the liberation of Auschwitz-Birkenau. With the community of survivors dwindling and concerns about antisemitism rising, speakers at events from Poland to London urged the world to remember — and to act.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.prsa.pl/images/7eb4a18e-8b48-49d7-b579-42bce785645e.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoftBank in talks to invest $30B more in OpenAI, WSJ reports</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/softbank-eyes-30-billion-addit-dW6KCSX.Tlacdkb228KXPw</link>
      <description>SoftBank Group Corp. is in discussions to invest up to an additional $30 billion in OpenAI, according to a report by The Wall Street Journal on Tuesday, a move that would deepen the Japanese conglomerate's position as one of the artificial intelligence startup's largest financial backers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The potential investment comes as OpenAI pursues a massive $100 billion funding round that could value the ChatGPT maker at up to $830 billion, one of the largest private fundraises in history. The negotiations are part of CEO Sam Altman's globe-spanning effort to secure capital from deep-pocketed investors, including Middle Eastern sovereign wealth funds.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJ2LMPbbpeLw/v0/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio warns of military force as Venezuela resists US demands</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-captures-maduro-as-trump-th-ygu_1wImS8qwNX93jsLMrQ</link>
      <description>Secretary of State Marco Rubio warned Tuesday that the Trump administration is prepared to use military force to ensure Venezuela's acting President Delcy Rodríguez complies with American demands, escalating tensions nearly a month after US special forces captured Nicolás Maduro in a dramatic predawn raid on Caracas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The warning came as Colombia's President Gustavo Petro called for Maduro to be returned to Venezuela to face trial in his home country rather than in the United States. "They have to return him and have him tried by a Venezuelan court, not a US one," Petro said Tuesday, one week before a scheduled February 3 meeting with Trump at the White House.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769562735/url_uploads/-1x-1_aq2kmk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kim Jong Un teases nuclear plans ahead of Workers' Party congress</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/kim-jong-un-announces-next-sta-eZYM3JUZTuOuLUElR32qlA</link>
      <description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un declared that the upcoming Workers' Party congress will reveal "next-stage plans" for strengthening the country's nuclear war deterrent, the state-run Korean Central News Agency reported on Wednesday. The announcement came after Kim supervised a ballistic missile test on Tuesday that drew international condemnation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Kim made the remarks while overseeing a test of a large-caliber multiple-rocket launch system that KCNA said demonstrated "significant upgrades" in strike power, mobility, and accuracy. The rockets reportedly struck targets 358 kilometers away in the East Sea. Kim emphasized that developing a "reliable offensive capability and deterrence strategy" is a key policy of the ruling Workers' Party to counter any attempts at armed conflict.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769564608/getty_uploads/2233683175_osyvs6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liverpool scientists find 3D material that mimics graphene</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/liverpool-creates-3d-graphene-3ZVSUCtVRhy8tLMco8F.ug</link>
      <description>Scientists at the University of Liverpool have discovered a three-dimensional material that replicates graphene's remarkable electron-conducting properties while overcoming the fragility that has limited the wonder material's practical applications.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, published Tuesday in the journal Matter, identifies that a compound called hafnium stannide (HfSn₂) can mimic graphene's fast, two-dimensional electron flow despite having a fully three-dimensional atomic structure. The discovery opens new pathways for developing more robust materials for low-energy computing technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://hixhlmpcokxhartfkpyi.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/images/thumbnails/89e371fc2792c67b07368195706ec817.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI could propose and test scientific hypotheses within five years, researchers say</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/experts-predict-ai-will-soon-p-k86fN9K5SzC5CFV8kpfU.g</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence could be autonomously generating scientific hypotheses and conducting research experiments within the next five years, according to leading researchers, even as philosophers and scientists debate whether machines can ever truly replace human researchers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;EPFL associate professor Robert West and Northwestern University professor Ágnes Horvát said in an interview published this week that the role of AI in science is poised for a fundamental shift—from assisting with writing and data analysis to actually proposing the questions that drive research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I think the next step, and perhaps five years is a reasonable time frame for that, is for AI to come up with the ideas we study," Horvát said. "That's very different territory because then the AI is providing the hypothesis that needs to be researched."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://gumlet.assettype.com/down-to-earth%252Fimport%252Flibrary%252Flarge%252F2024-01-15%252F0.65605600_1705321108_istock-1136060838.jpg?format=auto" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China approves first Nvidia H200 AI chip imports amid Huang visit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-approves-first-batch-of-zT74gX33TsKkaLUAo7XS2A</link>
      <description>China has granted approval for its first shipment of Nvidia H200 artificial intelligence chips, marking a pivotal shift in Beijing's approach to balancing its AI ambitions with efforts to promote domestic semiconductor development. The authorization covers several hundred thousand units and was issued during Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang's ongoing visit to the country, according to Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The approval, which extends to three major Chinese internet companies, signals a thaw in tensions that saw Chinese customs briefly block H200 shipments earlier this month despite U.S. export clearance. Sources indicate that Alibaba, Tencent, and ByteDance are among the firms granted initial clearance, with additional companies awaiting future approvals.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/5ZYYVU4T7VM4TLII2NXDOMA2OE.jpg?auth=e72f423a8bfdbaee7f0f8b2581dcc8a5d6d5ed67ba545926049721ffc7ec3a66&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stone tools found in China push back date of composite technology in East Asia</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/xigou-site-discovery-reveals-e-guF50G55TyiYfkbo3J80eg</link>
      <description>Archaeologists working at the Xigou site in central China have unearthed more than 2,600 stone artifacts that represent the earliest known composite tools in East Asia, challenging the long-held assumption that early humans in the region lagged behind their African and European counterparts in technological innovation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published this week in Nature Communications, document sophisticated toolmaking techniques spanning roughly 90,000 years at the site in Henan Province's Danjiangkou Reservoir Region.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://diaridigital.urv.cat/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Fig.-1-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold hits record high as dollar falls to four-year low</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/dollar-hits-new-lows-after-tru-ijNZLrPQSlO70o97TVjqbw</link>
      <description>The U.S. dollar tumbled to its lowest level since early 2022 on Tuesday after President Donald Trump appeared unconcerned about its recent slide, describing the currency as "doing great" when asked if it had fallen too much. The remarks accelerated a sell-off that lifted gold to record highs above $5,200 an ounce on Wednesday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dollar index, which measures the greenback against six major currencies, dropped to 95.566 on Tuesday — its weakest reading in nearly four years — before stabilizing around 96 in Asian trading on Wednesday. Trump's comments in Iowa intensified what had already been the currency's largest three-day drop since last April's tariff turmoil.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2026-01/2026-01-28T003245Z_1_LYNXMPEM0R00O_RTROPTP_4_USA-TRUMP.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea's Kospi breaks 5,100 for first time as gold tops $5,200</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-shares-mixed-as-s-p-500-u4BVOsfdRiiJM0veafMKRg</link>
      <description>Asian markets delivered a mixed performance on Wednesday as investors navigated a complex landscape of record-breaking U.S. equities, soaring precious metals, and a weakening dollar, all while awaiting the Federal Reserve's interest rate decision later in the day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;South Korea's Kospi broke through the 5,100 level for the first time in history, rising more than 1.5% in early trading. Meanwhile, Japan's Nikkei 225 fell about 0.5% as a strengthening yen weighed on export-heavy stocks. Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index pointed to gains, with futures trading above the previous close.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.khan.co.kr/news/2026/01/28/rcv.YNA.20260128.PYH2026012802030001300_P1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese researchers train AI to 'mumble' to itself</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/oist-researchers-boost-ai-lear-_wz6vOvHQ9GElUm_tWRKwg</link>
      <description>New research from Japan suggests artificial intelligence systems may benefit from a surprisingly human trait: talking to themselves. Scientists at the Okinawa Institute of Science and Technology (OIST) have demonstrated that AI models learn more efficiently, adapt to new situations more easily, and handle multiple tasks better when trained to use internal "mumbling" alongside short-term memory systems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published in Neural Computation on January 28, reveal that combining self-directed inner speech with working memory architecture allows AI to generalize across different tasks more effectively while requiring far less training data than conventional approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.ctfassets.net/mrbo2ykgx5lt/24235/091980aca978f37a0fc40e1a1f0028ce/neuroscience-brain-simulation-algorithm-exascale.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesian stocks plunge after MSCI freezes index additions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-shares-mixed-as-s-p-500-ZuEcx3gSTGGvtsVQlBJ5mg</link>
      <description>Asian markets diverged sharply on Wednesday as investors weighed a fresh record on Wall Street and record-high gold prices against significant regional headwinds, including a plunge in Indonesian stocks and a weakening U.S. dollar ahead of the Federal Reserve's interest rate decision.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The S&amp;P 500 closed at a record high on Tuesday, climbing 0.41% to 6,978.60 — its fourth record close of 2026 and fifth consecutive day of gains. The tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite also advanced, rising 0.91%. The Dow Jones Industrial Average, however, fell amid pressure on health insurer stocks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://english.news.cn/20250409/ef4f3ccc7405447c9508cb7760dd5f2a/20250409ef4f3ccc7405447c9508cb7760dd5f2a_ChkhgeE007009_20250409_CBMFN0A001.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU to elevate Vietnam ties to highest level during Costa visit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-and-vietnam-to-boost-cooper-6nLPhi0CTJKgMYtNegEnnA</link>
      <description>The European Union and Vietnam are set to deepen cooperation on critical minerals, semiconductors, and "trusted" 5G communications infrastructure during European Council President António Costa's visit to Hanoi this week, according to a draft joint statement reviewed by Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The eight-page document, scheduled to be adopted on Thursday when Costa meets Vietnamese leaders, will elevate diplomatic ties to Vietnam's highest level—placing the EU on the same tier as the United States, China, and Russia.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://bcp.cdnchinhphu.vn/zoom/670_420/344443456812359680/2025/6/10/hoidongchauau-1749520381261285754800-27-0-513-777-crop-1749520383980225500531.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope may have found birthplaces of massive black holes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jwst-discovers-potential-birth-.pYtekHLTsyIBFbvvHIHNA</link>
      <description>A growing body of research suggests that mysterious objects called "Little Red Dots," discovered by the James Webb Space Telescope, may represent the first observational evidence of direct-collapse black holes forming in the early universe—potentially solving one of astronomy's most vexing puzzles.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These compact, red objects, identified through deep extragalactic surveys conducted by the JWST since it began operations in 2022, existed when the universe was less than a billion years old. Scientists now believe they could be witnessing the birth of the most massive black holes in the cosmos.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.princeton.edu/sites/default/files/styles/scale_1440/public/images/2023/11/Abell2744_JWST_3000x1688.jpg?itok=agEjSC5H" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold hits record high above $5,300 as dollar tumbles</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-surges-past-5280-to-new-r-lOP2AxoRTMqSJhHKi9.fyg</link>
      <description>Gold prices breached the $5,300 mark for the first time on Wednesday, hitting an all-time high of $5,311.31 per ounce as the U.S. dollar plunged to a near four-year low ahead of the Federal Reserve's first interest rate decision of 2026.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The precious metal climbed as much as 2.3% during the session, extending a blistering rally that has seen prices surge more than 20% since the start of the year. The gains followed a 3.4% jump on Tuesday, the largest single-day increase since April.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/DHcxLHaRtai2VS4W5Ch4VQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/8e3d91e0-fc23-11f0-bdfd-60445a49298c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 50 million in West Africa face acute hunger by summer, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/officials-warn-of-climate-chan-rSvJV2OLQlurCizevGCgYQ</link>
      <description>A worsening pattern of climate-driven displacement and hunger is taking shape across the globe, as rising sea levels threaten coastal communities from Liberia to Hawaii while crop losses deepen food insecurity affecting tens of millions in Africa.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The United Nations World Food Programme warned in January that 318 million people now face crisis levels of hunger or worse globally—more than double the figure recorded in 2019. In West Africa and the Sahel alone, the Food and Agriculture Organization reported this week that 41.8 million people are currently experiencing acute food insecurity, a number projected to climb to 52.8 million during the June-August lean season without urgent intervention.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2024/in-niger-people-were-f.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European stocks slip as investors await Fed rate decision</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/european-stocks-fall-as-invest-82BEr14uSduQJNdeQDD8Eg</link>
      <description>European stock markets traded lower on Wednesday as investors exercised caution ahead of the Federal Reserve's first interest rate decision of 2026, while contrasting corporate earnings results created a mixed sector backdrop.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The CAC 40 in Paris dropped about 0.9% to around 8,080 points at midday, weighed down heavily by disappointing results from luxury giant LVMH. The FTSE 100 in London fell 0.4% to 10,165.25, while the DAX in Frankfurt slipped 0.2%. The pan-European Stoxx Europe 600 index declined 0.4%.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/V2JHKABKQNLP7LQKMJFYTPEHPI.jpg?auth=9b6f7321ed9fa2c17ff8e4a2eaad27cfe9a0a93ebecf2953d9bcb0c9cded2a7e&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dollar recovers from four-year low as traders await Fed decision</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/dollar-recovers-after-four-yea-1VOr.hIPS6.Ey_F_7ZFeGQ</link>
      <description>The U.S. dollar clawed back some ground on Wednesday after tumbling to a four-year low, as markets turned their attention to the Federal Reserve's first policy decision of 2026.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;President Donald Trump's casual dismissal of the currency's recent slide triggered the sharpest single-day drop in the greenback since the tariff upheaval in April. When asked Tuesday whether the dollar had declined too much, Trump told reporters in Iowa, "No, I think it's great," adding that it should "just seek its own level." Traders interpreted the remarks as a green light to sell the U.S. currency aggressively.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/bIlqmosaIcVBn.eM_sETWw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/dea2377cf8df0f44d5113ea36ea41485" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musk eyes June planetary alignment for record SpaceX IPO</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/musk-plans-spacex-ipo-for-june-uzxPRo4MRgColT0nhVCnag</link>
      <description>Elon Musk has proposed timing SpaceX's potential initial public offering to coincide with a rare planetary alignment in mid-June, according to the Financial Times. The rocket maker is targeting a $1.5 trillion valuation and aims to raise up to $50 billion, which would make it the largest IPO in history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company is eyeing mid-June when Jupiter and Venus will appear very close together in the sky for the first time in more than three years, five people familiar with the matter told the Financial Times. On June 8 and 9, the two planets will be positioned within roughly 1.6 degrees of each other, about the width of a thumb held at arm's length, according to the nonprofit Planetary Society. Musk's 55th birthday on June 28 was also a factor in the timing decision, sources said.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/SIEU4L73zv8kGmqB7tTi7A--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/3c213431a99fd4793326b8619d0a899e" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's solar and wind capacity surpasses coal for first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-solar-and-wind-capacity-EHntyMxJR.yccrBWoBxeSw</link>
      <description>China installed a record 315 gigawatts of new solar capacity in 2025 alongside 119 gigawatts of wind power, pushing combined wind and solar capacity past coal-based thermal generation for the first time in the nation's history, according to official data released by the National Energy Administration on January 28.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The figures mark a structural shift in the energy mix of the world's largest greenhouse gas emitter. By the end of December, China's cumulative wind and solar capacity reached 1.84 terawatts, exceeding thermal power by 300 million kilowatts and accounting for 47.3 percent of the country's total installed power generation capacity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://photos.watchmedier.dk/Images/17829631/mznwe6/ALTERNATES/schema-16_9/24353468342510-3600x2027ma-jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
