<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:36:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Studies find AI language models mirror human brain in both processing and bias</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-language-models-mirror-huma-1E1tmu96QiSis0JKd0K52A</link>
      <description>Two new studies reveal that the systems powering AI chatbots like ChatGPT and Gemini share unexpected parallels with the human brain—not just in how they build meaning from words, but also in how they absorb social biases.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Research published in Nature Communications found that the human brain processes spoken language through a stepwise sequence that closely mirrors the layered architecture of large language models (LLMs). A separate study from the University of Vermont, posted to the arXiv preprint server, shows that widely used AI models exhibit "us vs. them" social biases similar to patterns documented in human psychology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/brain-ai-data-technology-artificial-intelligence-chip.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran warns any US attack will be treated as 'all-out war'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-warns-us-of-all-out-war-a-z0Sy8rtER3G2I1apEVFDhg</link>
      <description>Iran declared Friday that any military attack on its territory will be treated as "all-out war," issuing its starkest warning yet as a US aircraft carrier strike group steams toward the Middle East amid heightened tensions over the country's deadly crackdown on nationwide protests.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Any attack, limited or otherwise, will be treated as an all-out war against us, and we will respond in the hardest way possible," a senior Iranian official told Reuters, speaking on condition of anonymity. The warning came as Iranian forces remained on high alert ahead of the arrival of US military reinforcements in the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769214913/url_uploads/-1x-1_xxrqah.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon says South Korea will lead North Korea deterrence</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/pentagon-shifts-north-korea-de-mhldNGQES86WF6pX_BQlBg</link>
      <description>The Pentagon on Friday unveiled its National Defense Strategy, outlining a fundamental change in how the United States approaches security on the Korean Peninsula: South Korea will now be expected to take the lead in deterring North Korea, with Washington providing "more limited" support.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"South Korea is capable of taking primary responsibility for deterring North Korea with critical but more limited U.S. support," according to the document released Friday evening, as reported by Reuters. "This shift in the balance of responsibility is consistent with America's interest in updating U.S. force posture on the Korean Peninsula."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769216541/getty_uploads/2198761888_lvajmi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK-led mission to create artificial eclipses proposed to ESA</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mesom-mission-to-create-artifi-4WS5334gQqOUOBzHa_zGug</link>
      <description>An international consortium of scientists has proposed a spacecraft mission to generate artificial solar eclipses in space, offering unprecedented views of the Sun's atmosphere as Earth experiences its most severe solar radiation storm in over two decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Moon-Enabled Sun Occultation Mission, known as Mesom, has been submitted to the European Space Agency for consideration as a future mission. If approved, the mini-satellite would position itself within the Moon's shadow roughly once every 29.6 days, creating total eclipse conditions lasting up to 48 minutes—ten times longer than typical eclipses observed from Earth.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/714119/original/file-20260123-56-ni7t41.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;rect=0%252C512%252C2048%252C1024&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane-eating bacteria could turn pollution into plastics, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/methane-eating-microbes-turn-g-hnzAjoj9R1q3DdSWZENE5Q</link>
      <description>Bacteria that consume methane could transform one of the planet's most potent greenhouse gases into useful products including biodegradable plastics, animal feed, and cleaner fuels, according to a new scientific review examining rapid advances in methanotroph research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, published this week in the journal Energy &amp; Environment Nexus, positions methane-consuming bacteria as biological "gatekeepers" capable of both reducing climate-warming emissions and converting waste gases into valuable materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://seed.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/ThisGreenhouseGasTraps85TimesMoreHeat_Cultured_41025-2048x966.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese scientists achieve 10x boost in CO2-to-starch conversion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-scientists-achieve-10x-aYaq9Q2rRBm.IpTdRahVBQ</link>
      <description>Researchers at China's Tianjin Institute of Industrial Biotechnology have increased the productivity of their carbon dioxide-to-starch conversion technology by more than tenfold compared to their original 2021 breakthrough, according to a report published Friday by the Chinese Academy of Sciences-run China Science Daily.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The advance brings scientists closer to industrializing a process that could fundamentally reshape how one of the world's most important carbohydrates is produced, potentially eliminating the need for agricultural cultivation of corn and other starchy crops.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.i-scmp.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=contain%2Cwidth=1024%2Cformat=auto/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/23/6fd6b3e8-2054-4dcf-be2b-53075dbc4d63_f60200c9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens 100% tariffs if Canada proceeds with China deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-100-percent-ta-4a6TXc8.SpSTh8HBBrGEuA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump on Saturday threatened to impose a 100 percent tariff on all Canadian goods entering the United States if Canada proceeds with its newly signed trade agreement with China, dramatically escalating a week of diplomatic tensions with America's northern neighbor.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If Governor Carney thinks he is going to make Canada a 'Drop Off Port' for China to send goods and products into the United States, he is sorely mistaken," Trump wrote on Truth Social, referring to Prime Minister Mark Carney. "China will eat Canada alive, completely devour it, including the destruction of their businesses, social fabric, and general way of life."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d3i6fh83elv35t.cloudfront.net/static/2025/02/2025-01-31T211014Z_1374391267_RC28LCA72B6C_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP-1024x683.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold crosses $5,000 per ounce for the first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-price-surges-past-5000-as-n8ntkW1JTwSvcutEALA6ew</link>
      <description>Gold prices have breached the closely watched $5,000-per-ounce barrier for the first time, capping a historic rally fueled by a weakening U.S. dollar, robust central bank buying, and expectations of further Federal Reserve rate cuts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As of Saturday, January 24, 2026, spot gold traded at approximately $4,988 per ounce after establishing an intra-day record high above $5,009 earlier in the session. The precious metal has gained roughly 15% since the start of 2026 and nearly 80% compared to a year ago. Silver has been equally buoyant, with prices approaching $100 per ounce after hitting unprecedented highs in recent sessions.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108234177-1764563718395-gettyimages-2240539484-AUSTRALIA_GOLD.jpeg?v=1767720612&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China places two top generals under investigation in major purge</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-military-leaders-zhang-6A0kczJbSzChVt.srIGHbw</link>
      <description>China's highest-level military purge in decades became official on January 24, 2026, when state media confirmed that Zhang Youxia, vice chairman of the Central Military Commission and a member of the ruling Politburo, has been placed under investigation for "serious violations of discipline and law." Liu Zhenli, chief of the Joint Staff Department and a CMC member, is also being investigated, according to an announcement from the Ministry of National Defense.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The terse statement said the decision to open investigations into both senior military figures followed "deliberation by the Party's central leadership," providing no further details on the alleged violations.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769285741/url_uploads/im-83941943_vsblh2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump advisers meet Netanyahu to advance Gaza ceasefire talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/netanyahu-rejects-white-house-MhJEyUDnQyyFTPprIwcieQ</link>
      <description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu declined a direct White House request for President Isaac Herzog to represent Israel at the inauguration of President Trump's Gaza Board of Peace in Davos, Switzerland, resulting in Israel's notable absence from Thursday's ceremony and exposing tensions between Jerusalem and Washington as Trump's peace initiative advances into its second phase.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The White House extended invitations to 58 nations to join the Board of Peace, with Netanyahu himself receiving an invitation, according to Axios. However, due to an arrest warrant issued by the International Criminal Court in 2024, Netanyahu could not travel to Switzerland. With Herzog already attending the World Economic Forum, senior U.S. officials twice approached the Prime Minister's Office on Tuesday and Wednesday, proposing that Herzog sit on stage alongside Arab and Muslim leaders and sign the board's charter, according to Israel's Channel 12.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2025/10/WhatsApp-Image-2025-10-09-at-23.27.52-e1760042848341.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US envoys meet Netanyahu to discuss Gaza reconstruction plan</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/israel-backs-palestinian-milit-TtOhMwMBS.mw8cgZzJXzZg</link>
      <description>An anti-Hamas militia operating under Israeli control has claimed responsibility for the assassination of a senior Hamas police chief in Gaza, as US special envoys arrived in Israel on Saturday to discuss the future of the war-torn territory with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The targeted killing on January 12 by the Popular Forces militia reflects Israel's growing reliance on Palestinian armed groups to combat Hamas in areas it controls, even as the Trump administration pushes forward with its ambitious "Board of Peace" plan to rebuild Gaza.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769309160/url_uploads/WhatsApp-Image-2025-10-09-at-23.27.52-e1760042848341_mrfgxz.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO chief calls U.S. withdrawal reasons 'untrue,' says exit makes world 'less safe'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/who-chief-dismisses-us-withdra-zLPRDB5WQW.h1tlXROzf6g</link>
      <description>World Health Organization Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus on Saturday rejected the reasons cited by the United States for its formal withdrawal from the U.N. health agency, calling them "untrue" and warning that the exit "makes both the U.S. and the world less safe."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The sharp rebuke came two days after Secretary of State Marco Rubio and Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. announced the completion of the withdrawal process in a joint statement, marking the first time since the WHO's founding in 1948 that the United States has not been a member.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 04:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2020-10-22T075352Z_1671871270_RC2JNJ9UXK56_RTRMADP_3_HEALTH-CORONAVIRUS-EU-WHO.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's top general investigated over alleged nuclear leak to US</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-s-top-general-zhang-youx-XRk7kJcERuKoNm7Z1xfp_w</link>
      <description>China's highest-ranking general is accused of disclosing sensitive nuclear arsenal information to the United States, according to The Wall Street Journal, in what analysts are calling the most significant military purge in modern Chinese history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;General Zhang Youxia, 75, the senior vice chairman of the Central Military Commission and long considered one of Xi Jinping's closest military allies, was placed under investigation on Saturday for "serious violations of discipline and law," China's Defense Ministry announced. Liu Zhenli, the CMC's chief of staff who oversees combat planning, was also placed under investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/24/multimedia/24int-china-military-mvfl/24int-china-military-mvfl-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada has 'no intention' of China free trade deal, Carney says</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/carney-rejects-china-trade-dea-S7Pjtfz0RVS9kcl97lQMRg</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney declared Sunday that Canada has "no intention" of pursuing a free trade agreement with China, pushing back against President Donald Trump's threat to impose 100 percent tariffs on all Canadian goods if Ottawa strikes a broader trade pact with Beijing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We have no intention of doing that with China or any other nonmarket economy," Carney told reporters in Ottawa, emphasizing that the recent agreement with Beijing merely addressed specific tariff disputes that emerged over the past two years.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/20/multimedia/20img-carney-davos-ztlf/20img-carney-davos-ztlf-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum, silver, palladium hit record highs as metals rally</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/platinum-silver-and-palladium-HH4TDUvYSHSYZ165HPNBXQ</link>
      <description>Platinum, silver, and palladium surged to fresh all-time highs on Sunday as a historic rally in precious metals continued unabated, driven by safe-haven demand amid geopolitical turmoil and expectations for Federal Reserve interest rate cuts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to Reuters via MarketScreener, spot platinum climbed more than 3% to reach $2,859.25 per ounce, while spot silver extended its gains to rise nearly 5% to $107.99 per ounce—its highest level ever. Palladium also rallied, rising 3% to $2,076.93 per ounce.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The moves come as gold breached the $5,000 per ounce mark for the first time on Saturday, according to the BBC, capping a week in which precious metals posted extraordinary gains. Silver has now gained more than 40% since the start of 2026 after rallying 147% in 2025, Reuters reported.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108234177-1764563718395-gettyimages-2240539484-AUSTRALIA_GOLD.jpeg?v=1767720612&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists find 1,730 viruses in world's deepest blue hole</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-discover-1700-virus-k2FcERsZSwWpiTbX9zv88Q</link>
      <description>Chinese marine scientists have identified approximately 1,730 distinct viruses lurking in the oxygen-depleted depths of the world's deepest known underwater blue hole, revealing a hidden ecosystem teeming with microbial life forms largely unknown to science.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discovery, conducted by researchers from the Chinese Academy of Sciences, centers on the Yongle Blue Hole, colloquially known as the "Dragon Hole," a massive marine sinkhole in the South China Sea that plunges nearly 1,000 feet into the ocean floor. The findings, detailed in research published in the journal Environmental Microbiome, indicate that approximately 77 percent of the viruses detected had never been recorded before and could not be matched to existing databases.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 02:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/160728165214-south-china-blue-hole.jpg?q=x_0%2Cy_134%2Ch_810%2Cw_1440%2Cc_crop/w_1280" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 European nations to sign pact for 100 GW of offshore wind</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uk-and-european-nations-pledge-xhGvAnPvRSGkqLijD.sFgQ</link>
      <description>Britain, Germany, and eight other European nations are set to sign a clean energy pact on Monday committing to jointly develop 100 gigawatts of offshore wind power through cross-border projects in the North Sea, underscoring the region's resolve to pursue renewable energy despite recent criticism from U.S. President Donald Trump.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The agreement will be formalized at the North Sea Summit in Hamburg, hosted by German Chancellor Friedrich Merz. Participating countries include Britain, Belgium, Denmark, France, Germany, Iceland, Ireland, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, and Norway.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://hansa.news/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Borkum-Riffgrund-3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesia raises $200M at $4B valuation, offers employee share cashout</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/synthesia-raises-200m-at-4b-va-cL_5mAIJTViCkm0_f2iqQA</link>
      <description>British AI video startup Synthesia has closed a $200 million Series E round that nearly doubles its valuation to $4 billion, while pioneering an unusual move for a European company: partnering with Nasdaq to let employees sell their shares without going public.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The funding round was led by existing investor GV, the venture arm of Alphabet, with participation from Nvidia's NVentures, Kleiner Perkins, Accel, New Enterprise Associates, PSP Growth, and Air Street Capital. New investors include Evantic, the venture firm founded by former Sequoia investors Matt Miller, and secretive VC firm Hedosophia.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://imageio.forbes.com/specials-images/imageserve/690226682806fc9c44e9c148/photo-of-victor-riparbelli/1960x0.jpg?format=jpg&amp;width=960" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU approves ban on Russian gas imports by 2027</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-finalizes-ban-on-russian-ga-M6Daks9yQNaapYa0cLS1.w</link>
      <description>European Union countries on Monday gave final approval to a law banning Russian gas imports by late 2027, marking a decisive step in the bloc's effort to end its energy dependence on Moscow nearly four years after Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Under the approved legislation, the EU will halt Russian liquefied natural gas (LNG) imports by the end of 2026 and pipeline gas by September 30, 2027. The deadline may extend to November 1, 2027, if a member state struggles to fill its gas storage with non-Russian supplies ahead of winter.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.lemde.fr/2025/12/03/0/0/1982/1321/664/0/75/0/4c9a9e8_ftp-1-1ivjljzouhri-f5ac0ddb01cb4b36b46a25c39468198a-0-0a13eed4b1fd4e94ab1f1ea1c6f15dcb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold surges past $5,000 for the first time as dollar weakens</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-tops-5000-as-dollar-falls-LfRAKXN.RTaA1Ngpdrd6SQ</link>
      <description>Gold smashed through the $5,000 barrier for the first time on Monday, climbing to a record above $5,100 as investors piled into safe-haven assets amid a weaker dollar and mounting speculation that the United States and Japan may jointly intervene to prop up the yen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spot gold touched an all-time high of $5,110.50 per ounce, extending a historic rally that has seen the precious metal gain more than 17% in the first weeks of 2026, following a 64% surge last year — its biggest annual gain since 1979. Silver continued its parallel ascent, scaling new peaks above $109 an ounce after breaking $100 for the first time on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://en.apa.az/storage/news/2026/january/26/big/6976f6abb46a86976f6abb46a917694040756976f6abb46a66976f6abb46a7.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
