<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:34:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft launches Maia 200 AI chip to challenge Nvidia</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/microsoft-unveils-maia-200-ai-TkvRCkrRRMOhuUpM_pbKjw</link>
      <description>Microsoft on Monday unveiled the Maia 200, its second-generation in-house artificial intelligence chip, marking an escalation in the growing competition among tech giants to reduce their reliance on Nvidia hardware.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The new accelerator comes online this week in a data center in Iowa, with plans for deployment at a second facility in Arizona, according to Reuters. Microsoft claims the chip, designed for AI inference workloads, delivers three times the FP4 performance of Amazon's third-generation Trainium processor and Alphabet's TPU offerings.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/VgePfBkTFiy0fRB4VvTVnQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/motleyfool.com/63afee76386efda72c04685f47fdfb4f" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope produces most detailed dark matter map ever</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jwst-unveils-most-detailed-dar-EZ3QiY0uRmWGUSuAwlZpVA</link>
      <description>Astronomers have produced the highest-resolution map of dark matter ever created, using data from NASA's James Webb Space Telescope. The new map, published January 26 in Nature Astronomy, confirms with unprecedented clarity how dark matter's gravity shaped the structure of the cosmos by drawing normal matter toward it throughout billions of years of cosmic history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, led by scientists from Durham University in the United Kingdom and Northeastern University in the United States as part of the COSMOS-Web collaboration, analyzed Webb observations of a section of sky about 2.5 times larger than the full moon in the constellation Sextans.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://universemagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/54txzv60hg-2048x1187.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK and Germany to build first direct offshore wind power link</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uk-and-germany-to-build-north-M_uGvT19TYGQ47kI0dtcqw</link>
      <description>Britain's National Grid and Germany's TenneT announced on Monday a partnership to develop an offshore wind interconnector in the North Sea, the first direct power link between wind farms in the two countries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came as ten European nations gathered at the North Sea Summit in Hamburg, where they signed the Hamburg Declaration pledging to deliver 100 gigawatts of joint offshore wind projects by 2050 in a bid to reduce reliance on fossil fuels.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cached.imagescaler.hbpl.co.uk/resize/scaleWidth/1272/cached.offlinehbpl.hbpl.co.uk/news/OPW/Baltic2cEnBW.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India, EU conclude 18 years of free trade negotiations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-leaders-attend-india-republ-sq5X_3WoQ4G0CciBhYNSmA</link>
      <description>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen and European Council President António Costa stood alongside Indian leaders on Monday as chief guests at India's 77th Republic Day parade in New Delhi, marking the first time both EU heads have jointly attended the celebration. The visit comes as both sides prepare to formally announce the conclusion of negotiations on a free trade agreement at the 16th India-EU Summit on Tuesday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;India's Commerce Secretary Rajesh Agrawal confirmed Monday that the two sides have successfully wrapped up talks on the FTA, ending 18 years of negotiations that began in 2007, were suspended in 2013, and revived in 2022. "Negotiations have been successfully concluded. The deal has been finalised," Agrawal said, adding that legal review of the text is underway and both sides aim to sign the pact this year, with implementation expected early next year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://im.rediff.com/news/2026/jan/26modi-ursula.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USS Abraham Lincoln arrives near Iran as U.S. naval buildup intensifies</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-imposes-new-sanctions-targe-lFGU.Ca_S9O4otGG_0MFBA</link>
      <description>The United States has escalated its pressure campaign on Iran, imposing fresh sanctions on nine vessels and their management firms while positioning the USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier within striking distance of the Islamic Republic as tensions between Washington and Tehran reach their highest point in years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The aircraft carrier arrived in the Middle East on Sunday evening near Iran, according to Israel's Channel 13. The arrival of the Abraham Lincoln Carrier Strike Group, accompanied by guided-missile destroyers and missile defense systems being deployed to the region, represents what President Donald Trump has called a U.S. "armada" approaching Iran.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/methode/2019/05/07/e82e14ba-700a-11e9-b91a-87f62b76a5ee_image_hires_023753.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold miners surge as bullion tops $5,100, silver breaks $100</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mining-stocks-rally-as-gold-an-RxkSabvqRX6RnL37YUim5A</link>
      <description>Shares of major gold and silver miners surged in premarket trading on Monday as bullion prices smashed through historic thresholds, with gold topping $5,100 per ounce for the first time and silver extending its rally above $100.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The precious metals rally, fueled by geopolitical uncertainty and concerns about a potential U.S. government shutdown, sent investors rushing into safe-haven assets and the companies that mine them. Top miner Newmont rose 4.4%, while U.S.-listed shares of Barrick Mining climbed 3.8%, according to Reuters. Canadian miners Agnico Eagle Mines and Kinross Gold each gained 4% in premarket trading.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RLUKIFYVOZPSBGC6KLJWR4DTAE.jpg?auth=57b2cc53f61b9725bba86f78eb624aef64cb010cc3e49656baa52154adcae4f1&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia-Ukraine peace talks to continue in Abu Dhabi on Feb. 1</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/next-russia-ukraine-peace-talk-HYgOAxfGRNeWm7lcYvfYWQ</link>
      <description>The next round of trilateral peace negotiations between Russia, Ukraine, and the United States is set to take place on February 1 in Abu Dhabi, according to U.S. officials, following two days of talks that all sides described as constructive but which revealed deep divisions over territorial issues.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov confirmed Monday that another round of discussions is planned for next week, though he said the exact date is still being finalized. The upcoming talks will build on initial meetings held January 23-24 in the United Arab Emirates capital, marking the first trilateral format in months to include political and military representatives from all three countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/epa_6973ded12f33-1769201361.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran-backed militias threaten action as US carrier nears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-backed-militias-threaten-WAw1W3eWSTSRtCr3icnsyQ</link>
      <description>Yemen's Houthi rebels and Iraq's Kataib Hezbollah have issued coordinated threats of military action in support of Iran as the USS Abraham Lincoln aircraft carrier strike group enters Middle Eastern waters, raising fears that a potential U.S.-Iran confrontation could ignite a broader regional conflict.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The threats from Iran's proxy forces mark a departure from June 2025, when members of the so-called "axis of resistance" notably refrained from coming to Tehran's defense during a 12-day war with Israel that also saw U.S. strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/archetype/KTHLKFNKB5H5HKIYUF4CG57E5Y.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO chief says Europe 'cannot defend itself' without US</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nato-secretary-general-says-eu-sgehFWoITICVxdUm09t9pw</link>
      <description>NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte delivered a blunt message to European lawmakers on Monday, insisting that the continent cannot defend itself without American military support and warning that any attempt to pursue strategic autonomy would require doubling defense spending and abandoning the US nuclear umbrella.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If anyone thinks here that the European Union or Europe as a whole can defend itself without the US, keep on dreaming. You can't," Rutte told the European Parliament's Committee on Foreign Affairs and Committee on Security and Defence in Brussels. "We need each other."</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RBAR3QLQRNKA7GSC4Q4EPDRLZM.jpg?auth=a769f2dd529c6cb87e9f87be0e6e5ff9346646028565914b203d7efe574981e6&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World's oldest wooden tools found in Greece, dating back 430,000 years</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-discover-430000-yea-LzArQzCcQaGGrpQinM7FpQ</link>
      <description>Two wooden artifacts found at an ancient lake shore in Greece have been confirmed as the oldest handheld wooden tools ever discovered, dating back 430,000 years and revealing that early human ancestors were crafting wooden implements long before the emergence of Homo sapiens.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discovery, published January 26 in Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, includes a digging stick and a smaller tool of unknown purpose. Both objects show clear evidence of intentional shaping by human hands.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://dehayf5mhw1h7.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/2100/2026/01/26200302/ap-news-og-image-2026-01-26-20-03-08-980x563.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria's Sharaa to meet with Putin in Moscow on Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/syria-s-sharaa-to-meet-putin-i-tSae.932RQqfxDc9GZKdSQ</link>
      <description>Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa is set to travel to Moscow this week for talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin, pro-government Syria TV reported on Monday, as Russia simultaneously withdraws forces from a key northeastern Syrian airbase.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The meeting, scheduled for Wednesday, January 29, comes at a pivotal moment in Syrian-Russian relations, with Damascus seeking to consolidate control over the entire country while Moscow recalibrates its military footprint following the ouster of longtime ally Bashar al-Assad more than a year ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769466480/getty_uploads/2240729730_yp90cd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI agents now coordinate entire battery research workflows</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-accelerates-solid-state-bat-7icJhC5JTw6kksOVUP2E4w</link>
      <description>Researchers at Tohoku University have detailed how artificial intelligence agents are transforming the search for solid electrolytes, the materials essential for building safer and more efficient solid-state batteries. A review published in the journal AI Agent outlines how these software-based systems are moving beyond simple predictions to coordinate entire research workflows, from data analysis to experimental planning.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Solid-state batteries have emerged as a leading candidate for the future of energy storage, particularly for electric vehicles and large-scale renewable systems. Unlike conventional lithium-ion batteries that rely on flammable liquid electrolytes, solid-state batteries use solid materials to transport ions, offering advantages in safety, energy density, and long-term reliability.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/battery_66fddc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doomsday Clock update to come as nuclear arms treaty nears end</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/doomsday-clock-update-set-for-6k18q5GBT7aOxOm.Y7dGzw</link>
      <description>The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists will reveal the 2026 setting of the Doomsday Clock on Tuesday morning, with experts warning the symbolic timepiece measuring humanity's proximity to catastrophe may move even closer to midnight amid escalating nuclear tensions and the imminent expiration of the last remaining U.S.-Russia arms control treaty.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement, scheduled for 10 a.m. ET at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace in Washington, D.C., will feature Nobel Peace Prize Laureate Maria Ressa alongside leading experts on nuclear risk, climate change, biological threats, and disruptive technologies such as artificial intelligence.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/AP25028564127068-1738137426.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK's Starmer says Britain won't choose between US and China</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starmer-says-uk-won-t-choose-b-h4y4KIGHTgGxw_8_sMVOsA</link>
      <description>Prime Minister Keir Starmer declared on Monday that the United Kingdom would not be forced to choose between the United States and China, highlighting what he called "significant opportunities" for British businesses as he prepares to depart for Beijing this week.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In an interview with Bloomberg, Starmer dismissed questions about whether strengthening ties with China would come at the expense of Britain's relationship with its closest allies. The trip, which marks the first official visit by a British prime minister to China since Theresa May's 2018 journey, represents a key moment in Starmer's bid to reset Sino-British relations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769468096/url_uploads/-1x-1_dtzyd8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moore's Law era ends as chip industry shifts to new strategies</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/moores-law-ends-as-computing-a-F5RUhjfwRJ.NJnSPMQPG1A</link>
      <description>For five decades, Moore's Law provided the semiconductor industry with a reassuring trajectory: the number of transistors on a chip roughly doubled every two years, delivering predictable performance gains. That era has now ended, according to experts, as the physical principles underpinning the trend have reached their limits.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The computing industry is responding with a combination of overlapping strategies rather than a single breakthrough, relying on new materials, specialized processors, and experimental technologies to sustain progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zdx4HgQxLhNYgvq7EtB3N3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agency warns hundreds dead in Mediterranean shipwrecks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-warns-hundreds-dead-in-medi-NaU0mNY0RK.RhgXbOjTsJQ</link>
      <description>The International Organization for Migration issued a grave warning on Monday that hundreds of migrants may be missing or dead following multiple shipwrecks in the Central Mediterranean over the past ten days, with vessels sent to sea during Cyclone Harry despite what the agency called "near-certain risk of death."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Three fatalities have been confirmed in Lampedusa, Italy, including twin girls approximately one year old who died of hypothermia shortly before disembarkation, according to the IOM. A man also died from hypothermia on the same vessel, which departed from Sfax, Tunisia. The twins' mother, a Guinean national who survived the ordeal, recounted days of treacherous conditions at sea during the crossing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"While IOM is still seeking official confirmation, the scale of the reported fatalities points to yet another major tragedy in the Central Mediterranean," the agency said in a statement.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.lemde.fr/2023/09/22/334/0/4000/2000/1342/671/60/0/42bd420_1695393700426-88a2725.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's Anta Sports to buy 29% Puma stake for €1.5 billion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/anta-sports-buys-29-percent-pu-KcyBFMoCRqWj9DvN3FkC.g</link>
      <description>Anta Sports Products, China's largest sportswear company, announced Tuesday it has agreed to purchase a 29.06% stake in Puma from the Pinault family's Groupe Artémis for €1.51 billion ($1.79 billion), positioning itself as the German brand's largest shareholder.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Hong Kong-listed company will pay €35 per share in cash for approximately 43 million Puma shares, representing a 62% premium to Puma's Monday closing price of €21.63, according to a stock exchange filing. The transaction is expected to close by the end of 2026, subject to regulatory approvals and customary conditions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 01:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://marathonhandbook.com/wp-content/uploads/Puma-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carney walked back Davos remarks in Trump call, Bessent says</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/carney-walks-back-davos-commen-DnIxKzz3R0Gp7ntRHF8_.g</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney "aggressively" walked back remarks he made at last week's World Economic Forum during a phone call with U.S. President Donald Trump on Monday, according to Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I was in the Oval Office with the President today. He spoke to Prime Minister Carney, who was very aggressively walking back some of the unfortunate remarks he made at Davos," Bessent said in an interview on Fox News.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Carney's office did not immediately respond to a request for comment late Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/6552x4696%2B0%2B0/resize/6552x4696%21/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252F67%252F26%252Fa52a85f84573b8347aa45184b7d5%252Fgettyimages-2213172328.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startup Genyro launches to speed DNA synthesis for AI-designed biology</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-use-ai-to-create-ne-f1E7AHUSR0OjG80WGBTUaw</link>
      <description>A tiny virus designed by artificial intelligence and assembled in a lab is reigniting debate over how quickly biology is becoming an engineering discipline—and how prepared regulators are for that shift.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The virus is a bacteriophage, meaning it infects bacteria rather than humans. It is part of a research effort in which Stanford University and Arc Institute scientists used genome language models—AI systems trained on DNA rather than text—to generate complete phage genomes and test them against Escherichia coli (E. coli) in the lab. The researchers reported 16 viable, AI-designed phages, with several showing **higher fitness and faster bacterial killing** than the natural phage template, ΦX174, in competition and lysis experiments.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.gbnews.com/media-library/science-experiement.jpg?id=63248662&amp;width=1200&amp;height=600&amp;coordinates=0%252C47%252C0%252C287" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN study links Iran's protest hotspots to water crisis zones</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/environmental-crisis-drives-ir-3nFIi39UQ927C7Qr76OIyg</link>
      <description>The anti-government protests convulsing Iran since late December are rooted not only in economic collapse and political repression but in a deeper, environmental catastrophe that has reached an inflection point. Dwindling water supplies, poisonous air, and crumbling infrastructure have compelled Iranians to take to the streets in the deadliest uprising the country has seen in decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A new analysis published this week by Nima Shokri of the United Nations University reveals a pattern: protests are more likely to erupt in areas suffering from groundwater depletion, land subsidence, and water rationing. Provinces such as Tehran, Khuzestan in the southwest, and Isfahan in central Iran, all regions with high levels of protest, are grappling with acute water shortages and disputes over access.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://eadn-wc03-5062647.nxedge.io/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Ahvaz-air-pollution.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
