<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:52:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Meta to report Q4 earnings amid AI spending surge, layoffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/meta-prepares-q4-2025-earnings-H6xu6Va9Q3mOqtQwxpmLtg</link>
      <description>Meta Platforms, Inc. will announce its fourth-quarter 2025 earnings after market close Wednesday as Wall Street scrutinizes the social media giant's aggressive artificial intelligence spending and recent workforce cuts in its virtual reality division.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Analysts surveyed by Bloomberg expect the company to report revenue of approximately $58.4 billion, a 21% year-over-year increase, with earnings per share of around $8.16 to $8.21. Bank of America analysts project the company could beat consensus estimates, forecasting revenue of $59.2 billion and EPS of $8.27.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/10/29/multimedia/META-EARNINGS-1-jkvf/META-EARNINGS-1-jkvf-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft shares fall despite beating cloud revenue expectations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/microsoft-cloud-revenue-grows-.FDTth66SOushhaza8y_Qw</link>
      <description>Microsoft reported stronger-than-expected quarterly results on Wednesday, but its shares fell more than 7% in extended trading as investors questioned whether the tech giant's cloud growth justifies the scale of its artificial intelligence investments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company posted fiscal second-quarter revenue of $81.3 billion, up 17% year-over-year and slightly above the $80.3 billion analysts had expected. Earnings per share of $5.16 also beat Wall Street estimates of $3.92. Azure, the cloud computing division closely watched by investors, grew 39%—narrowly edging past the 38.8% consensus estimate.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/zRXQazeHHQdEuu9K7cow0Q--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02ODU-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-07/8ee90540-cac7-11ea-b8ba-1c6dec32d9d2" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dutch court orders Netherlands to protect Bonaire from climate change</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/dutch-court-orders-climate-act-fpN_woPGT7a3WoFR.sHgAQ</link>
      <description>A Dutch court on Wednesday ruled that the Netherlands violated the human rights of residents on the Caribbean island of Bonaire by failing to protect them from climate change, ordering the government to set binding emission reduction targets within 18 months and implement a comprehensive adaptation plan by 2030.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Hague District Court found that the Dutch state discriminated against Bonaire's approximately 20,000 residents by not devising timely climate protections for the low-lying island, which faces rising sea levels, extreme weather, and coral reef degradation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://morningstaronline.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/wide/public/2025-10/Bonaire_1.jpg.webp?itok=dFJAZB4U" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens to cut Iraq support over al-Maliki nomination</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-warns-iraq-against-retur-Oo_itsTDSD.SOJijnmt7MA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump warned Iraq on Tuesday that the United States will end support for the country if former Prime Minister Nouri al-Maliki returns to power, threatening to restrict Iraq's access to its oil revenues held at the Federal Reserve Bank of New York.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Last time Maliki was in power, the Country descended into poverty and total chaos. That should not be allowed to happen again," Trump wrote on Truth Social. "Because of his insane policies and ideologies, if elected, the United States of America will no longer help Iraq and, if we are not there to help, Iraq has ZERO chance of Success, Prosperity, or Freedom. MAKE IRAQ GREAT AGAIN!".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Al-Maliki, 75, rejected the warning on Wednesday, vowing to continue his bid for the premiership. "We categorically reject the blatant American interference in Iraq's internal affairs," he wrote on X, calling Trump's remarks "a violation of sovereignty and a contravention of the democratic order in Iraq since 2003".</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/P5LTGA7R3FMYXIT4IJOOFUDTHM.jpg?auth=bff1b54af73c9f8696813aaca094832e628aca0870d73329dd8a1e488432cd59&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US intelligence doubts Venezuela's Rodríguez will cut ties with adversaries</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-intelligence-doubts-venezue-Vx2dw8P1S6uoj2supyDcig</link>
      <description>Recent U.S. intelligence assessments have cast doubt on whether Venezuela's interim President Delcy Rodríguez will comply with the Trump administration's demands to formally cut diplomatic and economic ties with Iran, China, and Russia, according to four people familiar with the reports.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The intelligence findings, disclosed as Secretary of State Marco Rubio testified before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on Wednesday, underscore Washington's uncertain position in Venezuela nearly a month after U.S. special forces captured former President Nicolás Maduro on January 3.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108247810-17674610972026-01-03t132926z_132401784_rc2iada1blsr_rtrmadp_0_usa-venezuela-vicepresident.jpeg?v=1767482399&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tesla to discontinue Model S and Model X to make Optimus robots</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tesla-ends-model-s-and-x-to-fo-KPo8Q.9XS2aXJzqIlrkOVg</link>
      <description>Tesla will discontinue production of its Model S sedan and Model X SUV by the end of the second quarter of 2026, CEO Elon Musk announced Wednesday during the company's fourth-quarter earnings call. The Fremont, California factory lines that currently build those vehicles will be converted to manufacture Optimus humanoid robots, with a target capacity of one million units annually.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It's time to basically bring the Model S and X programs to an end with an honorable discharge, because we're really moving into a future that is based on autonomy," Musk said during the call, according to TechCrunch. "If you're interested in buying a Model S and X, now would be the time to order it."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/ModelS_70.jpg?quality=90&amp;strip=all&amp;crop=7.8125%252C0%252C84.375%252C100&amp;w=2400" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists detail plans to study asteroid's potential moon strike</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-prepare-for-potenti-cgj7dpFHSqi4hx9FUweWpA</link>
      <description>A 60-meter-wide asteroid discovered just over a year ago carries a small but notable chance of striking the moon in late 2032, and researchers worldwide are preparing for what could be the most energetic lunar impact ever recorded in human history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Asteroid 2024 YR4, which was first detected on December 27, 2024, at the Asteroid Terrestrial-impact Last Alert System telescope in Chile, has approximately a 4% probability of colliding with the moon on December 22, 2032. While that means there is a 96% chance the asteroid will miss, scientists are treating the possibility as both a potential hazard and a rare scientific opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://orbitaltoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Asteroid-2024-YR4-Moon.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold surges past $5,500 to record high on safe-haven demand</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-surges-past-5400-dollars-m7Q8mjTQScqu3KzzUYdQ1Q</link>
      <description>Gold prices vaulted past $5,400 per ounce on Wednesday, extending an explosive rally that has seen the precious metal gain more than 25% since the start of the year, as investors sought refuge from mounting geopolitical risks and a weakening dollar ahead of the Federal Reserve's decision to hold interest rates steady.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The yellow metal climbed as much as 4% during the session, with spot gold reaching $5,393.19 an ounce and U.S. gold futures for February settling 4.3% higher at $5,303.60, according to Reuters. By early Thursday trading in Asia, gold had pushed above $5,500 per ounce, marking gains of more than $500 over four sessions since first breaking the $5,000 barrier on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/INGIB4VICZKTZJ7OYOZBJJO6VE.jpg?auth=1275bd6aff3189a1763e176ed9782287daeb0ee17e0ea358a6eddfebac72b434&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio says Donetsk territory is last major hurdle in Ukraine talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-brokered-peace-talks-contin-kmmZ8RdIRnGszHY1V5yhaQ</link>
      <description>Negotiations to end the nearly four-year war between Russia and Ukraine have narrowed to a single, pivotal issue: control over Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region. U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio told the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on Wednesday that resolving the territorial dispute remains "very difficult," even as both sides prepare for another round of talks in Abu Dhabi scheduled for February 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It's still a gap, but at least we've been able to narrow down the issue set to one central one," Rubio said during testimony. He indicated there may be American participation in the upcoming discussions, though President Donald Trump's key envoys—Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner—will not attend.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769653387/getty_uploads/2258665596_bxi8ur.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starmer and Xi meet in Beijing to reset UK-China relations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starmer-meets-xi-jinping-to-re-DTvi7QzFSzCnHKf5iIJGgg</link>
      <description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer met with Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing on Thursday, marking the first visit by a UK leader to China in eight years as the two nations seek to repair relations strained by years of tension over security concerns and human rights issues.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At the Great Hall of the People, Xi acknowledged that the UK-China relationship had "gone through some twists and turns that did not serve the interests of our countries," while declaring China "ready to develop with the UK a long-term and consistent strategic partnership." Starmer responded by calling for a "more sophisticated relationship" with Beijing, emphasizing that "China is a vital player on the global stage."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/BCHMTAR5Z5JZLKAVOKWHYE2GKY.jpg?auth=4792e921f44370f0ae7af73d0978883caac4a30f9d7aff22b07f197d005823e5&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change made southern Africa flooding 40% worse, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/climate-change-intensifies-ext-DIEPJthNRNugGfjDrMN96A</link>
      <description>A rapid new scientific assessment has linked deadly flooding across southern Africa to human-caused warming and shifting climate patterns, as large parts of the continent lurch between extremes—deluges in the south and intensifying dryness across the Horn of Africa.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a report released Thursday, the World Weather Attribution (WWA) initiative said the kind of extreme multi-day rainfall that fuelled recent floods in Mozambique, South Africa, Zimbabwe and Eswatini has become about 40% more intense since pre-industrial times, based on observational datasets. The study also found that the current weak La Niña made such extreme rainfall spells around five times more likely and boosted their intensity by about 22%—a compounding effect layered on top of long-term warming.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.dw.com/image/75575128_605.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK-Korean team begins first drilling into main Thwaites Glacier</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/antarctic-expeditions-reveal-n-5i3IGb1OQMOfrSdu7bNBPg</link>
      <description>International research teams are conducting multiple expeditions across Antarctica this month, collecting unprecedented data about ice sheet stability, ancient climate patterns, and the forces driving glacier melt in a warming world.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In one of the largest coordinated scientific pushes to the frozen continent in recent years, researchers from Australia, the UK, Korea, the US, and several European nations are racing against time and extreme conditions to gather information that could reshape understanding of future sea-level rise.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thwaitesglacier.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/The%2520hot%2520water%2520drill%2520rig%2520and%2520Icefin_David%2520Vaughan.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP authorizes $10B buyback as cloud revenue hits record</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sap-q4-2025-results-cloud-reve-P9goJjwTRhmB2zHyatgFng</link>
      <description>SAP reported fourth-quarter and full-year 2025 results showing continued momentum in its cloud business, with cloud revenue rising to €5.61 billion in Q4 and total cloud backlog reaching a record €77 billion. Alongside the earnings, the company authorized a new two-year share repurchase program of up to €10 billion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Total revenue for the quarter was €9.7 billion, matching a company-compiled consensus, as demand for cloud software and related services held up amid a softer macro backdrop.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.techmonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/29/2025/01/shutterstock_2423167951.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicist proposes time emerges from information, not entropy</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/physicists-question-whether-ti-KmFzvPmPTsKznw5NtcFpew</link>
      <description>Time feels like the most basic feature of everyday life—clocks tick, causes precede effects, and memories seem to pile up in one direction. But a new strand of physics research is reviving an old, unsettling possibility: **time may not be fundamental at all**, and what humans experience as “flow” could instead be a byproduct of how the universe stores and spreads information.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In an essay published January 28, physicist Florian Neukart of Leiden University argued that modern physics still lacks a unified account of time, in part because its two pillars treat it differently: **Einstein’s relativity** folds time into spacetime, while **quantum mechanics** typically assumes time as an external parameter. Attempts to combine the two, he wrote, can even yield equations in which time “disappears,” a long-running difficulty known as the “problem of time”.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/713591/original/file-20260121-56-ahajey.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;rect=0%252C348%252C4176%252C2088&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam, EU upgrade ties to strategic partnership amid U.S. tariff pressure</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/vietnam-and-eu-elevate-ties-am-ea0IQ3tDRniqiYlYnfLUNQ</link>
      <description>Vietnam and the European Union announced Thursday that they have upgraded their relationship to a comprehensive strategic partnership, a top-tier diplomatic status in Vietnam’s system, as both sides seek to broaden international partnerships amid disruptions linked to higher U.S. tariffs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decision was unveiled during a visit to Hanoi by European Council President Antonio Costa, and was framed by Vietnamese leaders as a political milestone rather than a deal with binding commitments. Vietnam’s President Luong Cuong called the upgrade “a historic milestone,” according to Reuters.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.barrons.com/asset/external-media/afp/AFP9424869023870230802764282382811411976092---1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese researchers report perovskite solar efficiency record</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-scientists-boost-solar-aGdyZdHyTz2Y7zsd_CVmAg</link>
      <description>A cluster of Chinese-led research results published and announced in January points to rapid progress on two long-running solar challenges: pushing conversion efficiency higher while keeping cells and panels stable under heat, humidity and uneven real-world conditions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In one of the latest headline-grabbers, trade outlets reported that Shenzhen-based perovskite developer SolaEon said it reached 27.87% power-conversion efficiency on a single-junction perovskite cell, with the measurement certified by China’s National Photovoltaic Industry Metrology and Testing Center (NPVM). The reports described the result as a laboratory-scale device, underscoring that the road from record cells to mass-produced modules still runs through durability testing and manufacturing scale-up.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/CVTEjYL7w_2v66ng1XgeOg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_cool_down_737/0c2dd0b8e8ae69a0dff9e8ae72d6ac81" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Webb confirms most distant galaxy ever observed</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-maps-dark-wl.4RV2iSGGzE6_AsX8acw</link>
      <description>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope has delivered two landmark discoveries this week, producing the most detailed map of dark matter ever created and confirming the most distant galaxy ever observed, offering new windows into the universe's invisible architecture and earliest moments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dark matter map, published January 26 in the journal Nature Astronomy, captures nearly 800,000 galaxies in the constellation Sextans and reveals the universe's hidden scaffolding with twice the resolution of any previous map. Just two days later, astronomers announced the confirmation of galaxy MoM-z14, which existed just 280 million years after the Big Bang—making it the most distant known object in the universe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/VKw2siavwce_5UrGje.JbQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD01MDA-/https://d29szjachogqwa.cloudfront.net/images/user-uploaded/Webb_Telescope_MoM-z14.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds water can survive near Earth's core in superionic state</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/superionic-state-enables-long-4HyRAmdWTZ.pRBFR49vX2g</link>
      <description>New research published January 28 in Science Advances reveals that water can survive the extreme conditions of Earth's deep lower mantle by entering a superionic state, challenging the long-held assumption that most hydrous minerals release their water at high temperatures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Scientists from the Institute of Geochemistry of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (IGCAS) used molecular dynamics simulations combining ab initio and deep-learning potential methods to study how water behaves near Earth's core-mantle boundary. The findings suggest that ancient water from Earth's early stages may have been preserved over geological timescales, accumulating as a long-term reservoir near the base of the mantle.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.thebrighterside.news/uploads/2026/01/water-3.webp?format=auto&amp;optimize=high&amp;width=1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford, Osaka teams advance light-based quantum computing</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/researchers-advance-light-base-BOUmB9KbRrStVyzSAuYRgw</link>
      <description>Two research teams are using light to tackle one of quantum computing’s core hurdles: how to scale fragile atomic systems from laboratory demonstrations into machines with enough qubits to do useful work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In results published over the past week, Stanford researchers reported an optical-cavity “readout” platform designed to pull information quickly from many atom-based qubits at once, while a University of Osaka group detailed a nanophotonic routing scheme aimed at delivering multiple laser colors across trapped-ion chips without a tangle of free-space optics.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/new-light-based-platfo-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China unveils plans for space tourism and orbital AI data centers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-plans-space-tourism-and-4LbkB1KkQTiaJh.5VQ2dfA</link>
      <description>China unveiled ambitious plans this week to develop space tourism and launch orbiting artificial intelligence data centers within five years, escalating competition with the United States in what both nations see as the next frontier for commercial and strategic dominance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;State media reported on Thursday that China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC), the country's primary space contractor, has committed to establishing gigawatt-class "space digital intelligence infrastructure" as part of its 15th Five-Year Plan spanning 2026-2030. The initiative aims to process Earth-generated data in orbit by combining computing power, storage capabilities, and transmission bandwidth, according to CCTV.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_%21RWlT%21%2Cw_1200%2Ch_675%2Cc_fill%2Cf_jpg%2Cq_auto:good%2Cfl_progressive:steep%2Cg_auto/https%253A%252F%252Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fpublic%252Fimages%252F7e49472c-3117-4edf-8029-3ad11db7d91a_3746x2082.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
