<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:10:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Iran's judiciary chief vows swift trials and executions for protesters</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-judiciary-signals-swift-t-6FCcQAEFQeeaaPPw3nVRPQ</link>
      <description>Iran's chief of judiciary announced on Wednesday that rapid trials and possible executions will proceed for thousands of protesters detained during nationwide demonstrations, directly challenging President Donald Trump's warning that the United States would take "very strong action" if the Islamic Republic begins hanging dissidents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Gholamhossein Mohseni-Ejei made the statement in a video broadcast by Iranian state television, emphasizing urgency: "If we want to do a job, we should do it now. If we want to do something, we have to do it quickly. If it becomes late, two months, three months later, it doesn't have the same effect."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came as human rights organizations reported that Erfan Soltani, a 26-year-old clothing seller from Fardis near Tehran, was scheduled to become the first protester executed in connection with the unrest. His fate remained uncertain Wednesday, with the Hengaw Organization for Human Rights unable to confirm whether the execution had been carried out amid Iran's ongoing communications blackout.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2026-01-12t181324z-496612350-rc2pziazzjov-rtrmadp-3-iran-economy-protests.jpg?c=original" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark deploys troops to Greenland as officials meet at White House</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/denmark-deploys-advanced-troop-vCuL2YoqROymG1WkaGj_dw</link>
      <description>Denmark announced on Wednesday it is deploying military units and equipment to Greenland starting immediately, as officials from Copenhagen and Nuuk arrived at the White House for high-stakes talks over President Donald Trump's escalating demands to acquire the Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The Danish armed forces are, from today, deploying capabilities and units related to exercise activities. In the period ahead, this will result in an increased military presence in and around Greenland, comprising aircraft, vessels and soldiers, including from NATO allies," the Danish Defense Ministry said in a statement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.newsweek.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AP25346538084040.jpg?w=1200crop%253D1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI triples scientist output but shrinks research scope, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-boosts-scientist-output-but-0lLSxp6ESJqep2Cbyr3mTA</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence has created a paradox in science: tools that supercharge individual researchers are simultaneously shrinking the collective scope of scientific exploration, according to a major study published in Nature.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, conducted by James Evans of the University of Chicago and colleagues, analyzed more than 41 million research papers spanning biology, medicine, chemistry, physics, materials science, and geology from 1980 to 2025. The findings reveal that scientists who adopt AI publish 3.02 times as many papers and receive nearly five times as many citations as their peers who do not use AI. They also reach leadership positions about 1.5 years earlier.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Yet this individual success comes at a cost to the broader scientific enterprise. AI-driven research covers 4.6% less topical territory than conventional studies and spawns 22% less engagement between papers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.nature.com/lw1200/magazine-assets/d41586-023-02980-0/d41586-023-02980-0_26083722.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musk denies Grok generated explicit images of minors</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/musk-denies-knowledge-of-grok-CHRwIm1bT86DdNsBBPfZzw</link>
      <description>Elon Musk said on Wednesday he was unaware of any explicit images of minors generated by his xAI chatbot Grok, even as global regulatory pressure against the AI tool reached a fever pitch with government investigations spanning three continents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I not aware of any naked underage images generated by Grok. Literally zero," Musk wrote in a post on X, his social media platform. "Obviously, Grok does not spontaneously generate images, it does so only according to user requests. When asked to generate images, it will refuse to produce anything illegal, as the operating principle for Grok is to obey the laws of the given country or state."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The remarks come as xAI faces investigations from California Attorney General Rob Bonta, the UK communications regulator Ofcom, and mounting calls from U.S. lawmakers to remove Grok from app stores operated by Apple and Google.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768411802/getty_uploads/2255514345_atgepf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half the world's major river deltas sink faster than seas rise</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/major-river-deltas-sink-faster-14a6flasQPmeB.aMrVS6.A</link>
      <description>Nearly half of the world's largest river deltas, including the Nile, Ganges, and Mekong, are sinking faster than global sea levels are rising, according to new research published Wednesday in Nature. The study warns that more than 236 million people face heightened flooding risk as human-caused land subsidence emerges as the dominant threat to these coastal regions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, led by scientists at the University of California, Irvine and Virginia Tech, provides the first high-resolution, delta-wide assessment of elevation loss across 40 major river deltas spanning five continents. Using satellite radar data collected between 2014 and 2023, the team found that 18 of those deltas are experiencing average annual subsidence rates that exceed the current global sea-level rise rate of about 4 millimeters per year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/14121207/SEI_280652732.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope's mysterious 'little red dots' are young black holes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-identify-little-red-XeGg3Q7oT8uJJA3NY2pvPg</link>
      <description>Since the James Webb Space Telescope began operations in late 2021, one of its most perplexing discoveries has been hundreds of tiny, unexplained red points scattered throughout images of the early universe. Now, researchers from the University of Copenhagen have cracked the mystery: these "little red dots" are young supermassive black holes hidden within dense cocoons of ionized gas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published Wednesday in Nature, reveal that these enigmatic objects are far less massive than scientists initially believed—about 100 times smaller—yet still weigh up to 10 million times the mass of our Sun.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/are-the-jwsts-little-r-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink now free in Iran as France weighs satellite aid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starlink-and-france-aid-irania-oFkgssEmTViOhLxIgb8ovA</link>
      <description>SpaceX's Starlink satellite internet service is now available for free in Iran, activists confirmed Wednesday, as France announced it is exploring sending Eutelsat terminals to the country to help citizens circumvent a communications blackout during the deadliest protests in the Islamic Republic in decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dual initiatives represent an international effort to restore information flows as the death toll from Iran's brutal crackdown on demonstrators has surpassed 2,500, according to the U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA), which reported at least 2,571 dead as of early Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UUPSBECOJKERR3MMQAXRL5S3GI_size-normalized.jpg&amp;w=1600&amp;h=900" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia's allies question Moscow's support as Ukraine war drains resources</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/putin-s-allies-feel-abandoned-HnD45qt.Tz6aXs903x5ZnQ</link>
      <description>Russia’s closest partners from Venezuela to Iran and Cuba are reassessing what Moscow’s backing is worth, after a series of crises in which Vladimir Putin’s government appeared either unable—or unwilling—to step in.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The clearest warning sign has come in Venezuela, where the U.S. operation that captured President Nicolás Maduro on Jan. 3 has exposed gaps in the security ecosystem Caracas built with Russian and Cuban help—and showcased the limits of Russia’s power projection as it remains fixated on Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2024-10-23T175441Z_1457612730_RC2HQAA7V1WW_RTRMADP_3_RUSSIA-BRICS-1767693098.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare alignment to offer glimpse of interstellar comet's dust</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-interstellar-alignment-NvHqesOlRq2pVo8S0.D82w</link>
      <description>Astronomers are preparing for an unprecedented observational window when interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS aligns with the Sun-Earth axis on January 22, 2026, offering scientists what researchers describe as a once-in-decades opportunity to study pristine material from another star system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A new research paper published this week by Harvard astrophysicist Avi Loeb and Italian astronomer Mauro Barbieri of Italy's National Institute for Astrophysics (INAF) details how the rare geometric alignment will enable measurements of the comet's dust composition that have never been possible with interstellar visitors.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d4hal6uazahag.cloudfront.net/777226/uploads/d0f3f150-af39-11f0-8e18-894a335485f1_1200_630.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark, US remain divided on Greenland after White House talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/denmark-and-us-remain-divided-4aDH.eqXQ.GjGOUZU6bq7g</link>
      <description>A "fundamental disagreement" persists between Denmark and the United States over Greenland's future, Danish Foreign Minister Lars Løkke Rasmussen said Wednesday after talks with Vice President JD Vance and Secretary of State Marco Rubio at the White House. The meeting, which also included Greenland's Foreign Minister Vivian Motzfeldt, came as President Donald Trump doubled down on his insistence that America must control the Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking after roughly an hour of discussions, Løkke Rasmussen told reporters that Trump has made clear his desire for the United States to acquire Greenland. "It is absolutely not necessary for the U.S. to seize Greenland," he said, urging Washington to engage in "respectful cooperation" over the island.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/afp_6967ebd6b42e-1768418262.jpg?resize=730%252C410&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ocean climate engineering could threaten global food supply, study warns</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/study-finds-climate-engineerin-n7rnYfviSr6BeAXi48SjBg</link>
      <description>A major scientific review warns that proposed methods to combat climate change through ocean-based interventions could pose serious risks to marine ecosystems and global food supplies, even as commercial ventures push ahead with deploying these technologies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The review, published in Reviews of Geophysics, examines eight climate intervention strategies and concludes that while some approaches carry fewer risks than others, none is entirely safe for ocean life. The authors caution that without careful research, these interventions could disrupt the marine food chain that sustains more than a billion people worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/6O-YlLyO1CY/maxresdefault.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK, France bolster Arctic presence as Trump presses Greenland demands</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uk-and-france-boost-arctic-pre-5yYxWCulT.WGg5qLOBm1DA</link>
      <description>British Foreign Secretary Yvette Cooper called on NATO on Wednesday to "step up its military and security presence in the Arctic," warning that the region is becoming "a front line of geopolitical competition" as climate change opens new shipping routes and exposes strategic resources. The appeal came as France announced it would open a consulate in Greenland next month, with both European allies taking concrete steps to counter U.S. President Donald Trump's repeated threats to take over the strategic Danish territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.independent.co.uk/2025/12/16/16/031b9e6e6ac8e1aa83e5473ed192d656Y29udGVudHNlYXJjaGFwaSwxNzY1OTg3MjA2-2.82732179.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=900&amp;fit=crop" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI signs $10B computing deal with AI chip maker Cerebras</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-signs-multibillion-doll-qMYy9fuaRsmsvEBN_.Kjrw</link>
      <description>OpenAI has agreed to purchase up to 750 megawatts of computing power over three years from AI chip startup Cerebras Systems in a deal worth more than $10 billion, according to The Wall Street Journal. The partnership marks another step in OpenAI's aggressive campaign to secure computing capacity from multiple chip suppliers as it races to develop increasingly powerful AI systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108205460-1759193863075-Handout_Cerebras_DSC08412.jpg?v=1759209631&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan officials arrive in Washington for final trade talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/taiwan-officials-visit-washing-CmUwl.ybS5Kh5kQL67E4aA</link>
      <description>Taiwan's Vice Premier Cheng Li-chiun and trade envoy Yang Jen-ni departed for Washington on Wednesday to advance negotiations aimed at reducing U.S. tariffs on Taiwanese exports, according to a person familiar with the matter who spoke to Reuters. The delegation is expected to arrive late Wednesday or early Thursday for meetings with Trump administration officials in the coming days.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The trip comes after Taiwan's Office of Trade Negotiations announced Tuesday that the two sides had reached a "broad consensus" on trade matters and were scheduling a final wrap-up meeting. If finalized, the agreement could be announced this month, according to The New York Times.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/5mqXR6zld3ZywhRdKiLTKA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/e2fb519b8e22c04504b5e6437f0e328f" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says Iran stopped killing protesters after his threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-says-iran-protester-kill-g6oyA_joQO6rYJYCGgj2aQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced Wednesday that he has received assurances Iran has ceased killing protesters, suggesting his warnings of military action may have prompted the regime to back down amid one of the deadliest crackdowns in the country's modern history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We've been told that the killing in Iran is stopping — it's stopped," Trump told reporters during an Oval Office bill signing. "There's no plan for executions. I've been told that on good authority."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came just hours before Iran was expected to carry out the execution of Erfan Soltani, a 26-year-old shopkeeper from Fardis, west of Tehran, who was detained on January 8 and sentenced to death without access to a lawyer or trial, according to human rights groups and the U.S. State Department. Trump did not specify who provided the assurances, though Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi had been in contact with Trump's top aide Steve Witkoff over the weekend.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1024-512%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2026-01/260112-iran-rs-a03ac1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump signs tariffs on semiconductors, critical minerals</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-orders-new-tariffs-on-se-D_MsavtnQU6toXblpjQ0Wg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump signed two executive orders Wednesday aimed at protecting domestic supply chains for semiconductors and critical minerals, invoking Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, the national-security clause that allows presidents to impose tariffs on imports deemed threats to U.S. security.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At a White House signing ceremony, Staff Secretary Will Scharf explained that the critical minerals order establishes "a mechanism, a process by which the United States will seek to secure its international supply chain of critical minerals and critical mineral derived products." The moves represent the culmination of investigations launched by the Department of Commerce in April 2025 into whether imports of these strategic materials threaten U.S. national security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768426222/getty_uploads/2252601751_rwtl95.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain temporarily closes Tehran embassy after protest</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/britain-temporarily-closes-emb-R14q5ePkQyKg1ybwACYfhg</link>
      <description>The British government has temporarily closed its embassy in Tehran and shifted operations to remote mode following a protest by pro-regime activists outside the facility on Wednesday, as Western nations continue to respond to Iran's deadly crackdown on anti-government demonstrators.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We have temporarily closed the British Embassy in Tehran, this will now operate remotely. Foreign Office travel advice has now been updated to reflect this consular change," a UK government spokesperson told Politico.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768423010/getty_uploads/2255649562_fvwprw.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump weighing Iran strike within 24 hours, officials say</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-weighs-iran-military-str-GVGF9t9wTWqEqEyRJFyhbQ</link>
      <description>US military intervention in Iran could occur within the next 24 hours, two European officials told Reuters on Wednesday, as President Donald Trump appears poised to authorize strikes amid protests that have killed more than 2,500 people in what French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot called "the most violent repression in Iran's contemporary history."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;An Israeli official also told Reuters that Trump appears to have decided to intervene, though the scope and timing remain unclear. A Washington source close to the administration told The Independent that strikes could be imminent. "President Trump is ready to push the button on Iran," the source said. "It will be a surgical removal of the regime."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2254867320.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860%2Cc_fill" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran shuts airspace as tensions with US escalate</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-closes-airspace-amid-fear-K_Illv8vTnml2PkC3.O7lA</link>
      <description>Iran issued a NOTAM late on Wednesday night, shutting its airspace to all flights except international flights with special permission, as Western military officials warned that US military intervention could be imminent. The airspace closure, valid for just over two hours, sparked widespread flight diversions and cancellations across the Middle East amid escalating tensions between Washington and Tehran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;FlightRadar24 announced on X that airspace over Iran began emptying rapidly before the notice was officially issued, with the flight-tracking platform noting: "New NOTAM just issued by Iran closing airspace to all flights except international flights to/from Iran with permission."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.bssnews.net/assets/news_photos/2025/06/14/image-282271-1749890663.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI rehires key researchers who left for Thinking Machines Lab</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-rehires-key-researchers-5.ZUox1WTbOEJJwVg8oqOQ</link>
      <description>OpenAI has secured the return of several high-profile researchers who departed the ChatGPT maker in 2024 to join former CTO Mira Murati's rival startup Thinking Machines Lab, according to industry reports. The move comes amid a significant shakeup at Murati's venture and as OpenAI continues to expand its research capabilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768436885/url_uploads/GettyImages-2198164367-e1742569013723_mwjpfw.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
