<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:28:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens tariffs on nations opposing his Greenland bid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-tariffs-over-g-ulearT0aRQqvMyMY65iJwQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump warned Friday that he may impose tariffs on countries that do not support his efforts to acquire Greenland, escalating his campaign to take control of the strategically vital Arctic territory despite growing international opposition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I may put a tariff on countries if they don't go along with Greenland, because we need Greenland for national security," Trump said during a roundtable event at the White House. The threat came as European nations deployed military personnel to the semiautonomous Danish territory for joint exercises, and a bipartisan delegation of U.S. lawmakers arrived in Copenhagen to demonstrate solidarity with Denmark.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.arctictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2026-01-14T162111Z_2038492178_RC221JA20R53_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP-GREENLAND-DENMARK-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US and Taiwan reach trade deal cutting tariffs, securing chip investment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-and-taiwan-reach-landmark-t-bLbbji7oS9qvz.nDk2QwOA</link>
      <description>The United States and Taiwan have reached a trade agreement that will reduce tariffs on Taiwanese goods from 20 percent to 15 percent and secure hundreds of billions of dollars in semiconductor investment commitments, according to officials familiar with the matter. The deal, which the White House was set to announce Thursday, places Taiwan on equal footing with Japan and South Korea, which secured similar arrangements last year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Under the agreement, Taiwanese semiconductor companies will commit to a $500 billion increase in financing for American operations, with Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. pledging to build at least five additional fabrication plants in Arizona, effectively doubling its manufacturing presence in the state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/03/multimedia/03biz-tsmc-sub-vzgl-wpzq/03biz-tsmc-sub-vzgl-wpzq-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky rejects Trump's claim that Ukraine is blocking peace</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/zelensky-rejects-trump-s-claim-.CTTFbCiQTi__bLXeDKZ_g</link>
      <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy firmly rejected U.S. President Donald Trump's assertion that Ukraine is obstructing peace negotiations, declaring that his country "has never been and will never be an obstacle to peace" while pointing to ongoing Russian attacks on civilian infrastructure as evidence of Moscow's true intentions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dispute erupted after Trump told Reuters on January 15 that Russian President Vladimir Putin is "ready to make a deal" while characterizing Ukraine as "less ready." When asked why U.S.-led negotiations had failed to end the nearly four-year-old conflict, Trump responded with a single word: "Zelenskyy."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thehill.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/12/mr-zelensky-trump_122925ap.jpg?w=1280" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet's alien dust unlike anything in our solar system</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-interstellar-comet-she-1jTNJpmQTJWkaIBJYmBPmw</link>
      <description>The interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS continues to defy expectations, maintaining active outgassing and shedding material with a chemical composition unlike anything found in our solar system—even as it recedes toward the outer reaches of space.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A ground-based telescope in Hawaii captured the object on January 14, 2026, revealing a compact nucleus surrounded by a structured coma and the early formation of a tail, despite the comet being approximately 300 million kilometers from Earth. At such distances, most small bodies would fade into obscurity, yet 3I/ATLAS remains visible and active.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/48/2025/11/3i-atlas-11-november-2025.jpg?w=1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA to roll out SLS rocket for first crewed Moon mission in 50 years</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-rolls-out-sls-rocket-for-qBSxvzgaQMqP2BUABb5iHw</link>
      <description>NASA is set to begin rolling out its towering Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft for the Artemis II mission as early as Saturday morning, marking the final preparatory steps before the first crewed voyage to the Moon in more than half a century.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The rollout from the Vehicle Assembly Building to Launch Pad 39B at Kennedy Space Center in Florida is targeted to begin no earlier than 7 a.m. EST on January 17, according to NASA. The 322-foot rocket will travel approximately 6.4 kilometers over the course of up to 12 hours aboard the agency's crawler-transporter-2.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/48/2026/01/artemis-i-rollout.jpg?w=1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI to test ads in ChatGPT for the first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-begins-testing-ads-in-c-iftvcU5LSGyw9AKiVGW_wg</link>
      <description>OpenAI announced this week it will begin testing advertisements in ChatGPT for the first time, marking a pivotal shift for the artificial intelligence company as it seeks new revenue streams amid mounting financial pressures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to OpenAI's official statement, the company will start testing ads in the U.S. in the coming weeks, limited to users of the free tier and the newer $8-a-month ChatGPT Go plan. Ads will appear at the bottom of responses when a sponsored product or service is relevant to the conversation, and will be clearly labeled as such. Users of premium tiers including Plus, Pro, Business, and Enterprise will not see advertisements.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.wsj.net/im-43992188?width=1280&amp;size=1.501" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI to begin testing ads in ChatGPT's free tier</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-to-begin-testing-ads-in-2EXornIkQamQywz7OEDx4Q</link>
      <description>OpenAI announced Friday it will begin testing advertisements in ChatGPT, a major shift for the artificial intelligence company as it seeks to diversify revenue beyond subscriptions amid mounting operational costs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The ads will roll out to users of the free version of the chatbot as well as those subscribing to ChatGPT Go, the company's newly launched budget-tier subscription that is becoming available globally at around $8 per month, according to The Wall Street Journal and Bloomberg. The move comes as OpenAI faces pressure to monetize its massive user base, with only about 5% of ChatGPT's 800 million weekly active users paying for subscriptions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/zxiQh.BqtI1GzO19tk4Oqg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTI0MDA7aD0xNjAw/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_independent_635/9ee224bdd15987a4e510c71e0f72884f" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists open world's first ice core sanctuary in Antarctica</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-map-antarctica-and-TlthFNS0QMi8Nbn1WUnioQ</link>
      <description>In a week of advances for polar science, researchers have unveiled the most detailed map ever created of Antarctica's hidden bedrock while a separate team inaugurated the world's first ice core sanctuary on the frozen continent, both efforts aimed at understanding and preserving climate data before it disappears.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/6a7ac34a-d717-4857-b5dc-dbe52078c268/wirestory_25c45a3a1e6375a1f241c825e5e63e5c_16x9.jpg?w=1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia says Grok ban won't lift until X proves misuse 'will no longer occur'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/malaysia-and-indonesia-block-g-52YkM94VTFeQ2idrFnsBHA</link>
      <description>Malaysia and Indonesia have become the first countries in the world to block access to Elon Musk's AI chatbot Grok after regulators determined the tool was being used to generate sexually explicit and nonconsensual deepfake images, including content depicting women and minors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Indonesia's Ministry of Communication and Digital Affairs ordered restrictions on January 10, with Malaysia's Communications and Multimedia Commission following on January 11. The bans came after officials in both countries concluded that safeguards implemented by xAI, the company behind Grok, had failed to stop the spread of obscene content on X, the social media platform formerly known as Twitter.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AFP__20250116__36U737B__v1__MidRes__FranceTechnologyAiGrok-1768206919.jpg?resize=1920%252C1280&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China breaks ground on world's first hybrid nuclear plant for petrochemicals</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-builds-world-s-first-hyb-E6llUp7iTNacG8zC7n7kNw</link>
      <description>China has begun construction of the world's first large-scale nuclear power plant designed to directly supply industrial steam to the petrochemical sector, marking a new approach to decarbonizing heavy industry.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On Friday, workers poured the first concrete for the nuclear island of Unit 1 at the Xuwei Nuclear Heating and Power Plant in Lianyungang, Jiangsu Province, according to China National Nuclear Corporation (CNNC), the state-owned developer. The project is the first nuclear power unit to break ground in the opening year of China's 15th Five-Year Plan, which runs from 2026 to 2030.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/images/articles/Xuwei_1_FCD_-_1_%28CNNP%29_4735e09c.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US House committee accuses South Africa of threatening national security</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-escalates-criticism-of-sout-t1NCURCoSJGWmO5VugMWwA</link>
      <description>The United States has intensified its condemnation of South Africa following the "Will for Peace 2026" naval exercises that concluded on Friday off Cape Town's coast, with the House Committee on Foreign Affairs accusing Pretoria of undermining American national security. The criticism comes one day after the US Embassy in South Africa publicly lambasted the country for allowing Iran to participate in the drills alongside Chinese and Russian vessels.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The week-long exercises, which ran from January 9 to 16, brought together naval forces from Iran, China, Russia, South Africa, and the United Arab Emirates, along with observers from Brazil, Ethiopia, Indonesia, and Egypt. The drills are described by South African officials as part of the BRICS Plus framework aimed at enhancing maritime security.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768675539/url_uploads/-1x-1_xqv3ms.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump announces 10 percent tariffs on Denmark and allies over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-10-percent-tar-unFibFpvQEKAj5i.TNllSQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump escalated his campaign to acquire Greenland on Saturday by announcing a 10 percent tariff on eight European countries that have rallied behind Denmark in opposing U.S. control of the Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a post on Truth Social, Trump said the tariffs would take effect on February 1 and apply to Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland. According to Investing.com, the tariffs would increase to 25 percent on June 1 and remain in place until "a deal is reached for the United States to purchase Greenland".</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/0c350901-cc2e-4056-be46-f6795c2b11f8/donald-trump-4-ap-gmh-260116_1768582285613_hpMain_16x9.jpg?w=1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA rolls Artemis II rocket to launch pad ahead of moon mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jeremy-hansen-prepares-for-his-C_VG_cHPT6uOOdcO9ugD1Q</link>
      <description>Canadian astronaut Jeremy Hansen stood at NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Saturday morning, watching as the rocket that will carry him around the moon began its slow journey to the launch pad. Hansen, a 49-year-old from London, Ontario, is set to become the first non-American to travel beyond low Earth orbit when Artemis II lifts off as early as next month.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The four-mile rollout of NASA's Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft began at 7:04 a.m. EST on January 17, with the 11-million-pound stack creeping toward Launch Complex 39B at about one mile per hour. The journey to the launch pad is expected to take up to 12 hours.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/17/multimedia/17HS-ARTEMIS-II-stillpromo-cglm/17HS-ARTEMIS-II-stillpromo-cglm-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump held secret talks with Venezuela's Cabello before Maduro capture</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-administration-engaged-i-s2h87isSQEGo.DrBd1jjsA</link>
      <description>The Trump administration held months of quiet discussions with Venezuela's interior minister Diosdado Cabello before the January 3 military operation that captured President Nicolás Maduro, and communications have continued since, according to multiple sources familiar with the matter in an exclusive Reuters report published Friday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;U.S. officials warned Cabello, 62, against deploying security services or militant ruling-party supporters to target Venezuela's opposition, four sources told Reuters. The talks also addressed U.S. sanctions imposed on him and his federal drug-trafficking indictment. Despite being named in the same indictment that justified Maduro's arrest—with a $25 million bounty on his head—Cabello was not apprehended during the operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768678583/getty_uploads/2256293839_ubjgqt.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran's Khamenei admits thousands killed in protests blaming US</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-s-khamenei-admits-thousan-K9CrD2QdQgmd5Oft27VfNQ</link>
      <description>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on Saturday accused U.S. President Donald Trump of being a "criminal" responsible for casualties, destruction, and spreading falsehoods against the Iranian people, as the country emerges from its deadliest unrest in decades with thousands reported killed in a brutal crackdown.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We consider the U.S. president a criminal for the casualties, damages, and the slander he inflicted on the Iranian nation," Khamenei said during a speech marking Eid al-Mab'ath, the anniversary of the Prophet Muhammad's mission, according to Iranian media. He described the protests as an "American sedition" designed to "devour Iran."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2026/01/AP26003388650698-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron slams Trump's Greenland tariff threats, vows united EU response</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/macron-calls-trump-greenland-t-v9FG.Uj1Sgqsihmx2zB7wA</link>
      <description>French President Emmanuel Macron responded forcefully on Saturday to U.S. President Donald Trump's announcement of sweeping tariffs on eight European countries, declaring that "no intimidation or threat will influence us" and promising a united European response to what he called an unacceptable escalation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The sharp rebuke came hours after Trump announced on Truth Social that Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland would face a 10 percent tariff on all goods exported to the United States starting February 1, rising to 25 percent on June 1. The levies would remain in place "until such time as a Deal is reached for the Complete and Total purchase of Greenland," Trump said.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 20:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/Q275TYSCINN2TAXAT5BFEEVKHU.jpg?auth=cd71b39a44d76a4acdf3a0d092311bf61aaf02c57d682c0bfaf0baaec61fa4db&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands protest Trump's Greenland push in Denmark, Arctic</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mass-protests-erupt-in-denmark-XkvSYtmpQJGgxPwEjQ.tUw</link>
      <description>Thousands of demonstrators took to the streets across Denmark and Greenland on Saturday, January 17, 2026, in a forceful rejection of President Donald Trump's escalating campaign to acquire the Arctic territory. The protests came hours after Trump announced sweeping tariffs on eight European nations opposing his push, deepening an unprecedented diplomatic rift between NATO allies.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/2RVQDW52LFKXXCGL4SQEWUU73Q.jpg?auth=26a90eab0c3121481607a96bef3fbf016fee107b66b32a8d917136810da0180c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump asks countries to pay $1 billion for permanent peace board seats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-wants-nations-to-pay-1-b-juzl8dT9Sj2TkEURIgx_zA</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is asking countries that want a permanent spot on President Donald Trump's new Board of Peace to contribute at least $1 billion, according to a draft charter of the body sent to world leaders this weekend.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The provision, outlined in the charter distributed alongside invitation letters on Friday, effectively creates a two-tier membership structure. Countries that contribute $1 billion or more in cash funds to the Board of Peace would be exempt from the standard three-year membership term, securing them a permanent seat on the panel.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thehill.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/10/Leading-Trump-and-Milei_101425_Greg-Nash.jpg?w=1280" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU lawmakers move to freeze US trade deal after Trump tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-halts-us-trade-deal-approva-Ibq3iLbcSzGJ54hUAhhSug</link>
      <description>European Union lawmakers are poised to freeze approval of the EU-US trade deal after President Donald Trump announced tariffs on eight NATO allies Saturday in his latest bid to acquire Greenland. The move marks a dramatic escalation in transatlantic tensions, jeopardizing the landmark agreement struck just six months ago.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Manfred Weber, president of the European People's Party—the largest political faction in the European Parliament—declared that proceeding with the trade deal is no longer feasible. "The EPP is in favor of the EU-US trade deal, but given Donald Trump's threats regarding Greenland, approval is not possible at this stage," Weber posted on social media Saturday, adding that "zero tariffs on US products must now be put on hold."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i73poNj8ag5I/v1/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU calls emergency meeting after Trump tariff threat over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-calls-emergency-meeting-ove-jwin0js5SYeLM5aYJMMJGg</link>
      <description>Ambassadors from the European Union's 27 member states will convene for an emergency meeting on Sunday after U.S. President Donald Trump announced a wave of escalating tariffs on European allies over their opposition to the American acquisition of Greenland, an unprecedented move that threatens to fracture the transatlantic alliance and ignite a new trade war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Cyprus, which holds the EU's six-month rotating presidency, called the urgent session late Saturday, with diplomats indicating it is scheduled to begin at 5 p.m. GMT. European Council President António Costa confirmed he is coordinating a collective response from member states, stating, "The EU will maintain its stance on upholding international law, wherever it is applicable".</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/35TURRJKS5OOPAB6Q2NLOWITQA.jpg?auth=9357ab30f7046186c9c8ae998283aae191725346ad13be364fabcc03d3224df7&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
