<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:28:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Euro zone inflation hits ECB target at 2.0%</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/euro-zone-and-czech-december-i-MLrM5VneTlWOUEY7AEb.Yg</link>
      <description>Inflation in the euro zone eased to 2.0% in December 2025, reaching the European Central Bank's target, while the Czech Republic's inflation held steady at 2.1%, according to flash estimates released Wednesday by Eurostat and the Czech Statistical Office[1][2][3][4]. The convergence signals stable price growth across Central Europe as policymakers maintain current interest rates.

Euro area consumer prices rose 2.0% year-over-year in December, down from 2.1% in November and matching economists' expectations[1][5][6][7]. Core inflation, which excludes volatile food and energy costs, slowed to 2.3% from 2.4% the previous month[6][7]. The deceleration was driven primarily by falling energy prices, which dropped 1.9% compared to a 0.5% decline in November[1].

Services inflation, a key concern for ECB policymakers, eased to 3.4% from 3.5%, while food, alcohol, and tobacco prices rose 2.6%, up from 2.4% the prior month[1][6]. Country variations remained wide, with Estonia and Slovakia recording the highest rates at 4.1%, while Cyprus posted just 0.1% and France 0.8%[1].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--jkWuMzAB--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108248623-1767693301611-gettyimages-2212947782-_dsh7421-3.jpeg%3Fv%3D1767693342%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered gadgets steal spotlight at CES 2026</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-highlights-ai-innovat-K5XDnDH5SRy4pLjlp4h02g</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence took center stage at CES 2026 in Las Vegas this week, with major technology companies unveiling AI-powered innovations spanning entertainment, robotics, and health monitoring that aim to reshape how people work and play.

The four-day consumer electronics showcase, which opened Tuesday, featured demonstrations across 2.6 million square feet of exhibit space, drawing thousands of exhibitors eager to display products planned for store shelves this year[1].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MI4IpjLn--/t_thumbnail/https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/DSC01392.jpg%3Fquality%3D90%26strip%3Dall%26crop%3D0%252C10.806933475316%252C100%252C78.386133049368%26w%3D1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI dominates CES 2026 with robots, health tech</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-highlights-ai-innovat-mEbs5px8QqW1Ol4uboZ0Mw</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence dominated the showroom floors at CES 2026 in Las Vegas this week, as tech giants unveiled AI-powered companions, robots and health devices designed to integrate seamlessly into daily life.

Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang drew massive crowds to his keynote on January 5, where he introduced "physical AI" as the next frontier of artificial intelligence[1][2]. The company unveiled Cosmos, a world foundation model trained to understand real-world physics, and Alpamayo, an autonomous driving system that Huang called "the world's first reasoning autonomous driving AI"[2][3]. The technology, which will power Mercedes-Benz robotaxis launching in the first quarter of 2026, uses synthetic data to learn how vehicles interact in complex traffic scenarios[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Uo3rn8Dy--/t_thumbnail/https://helios-i.mashable.com/imagery/articles/05oH82ww6bI0q8hZoNIeGSp/hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.v1767689372.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, Siemens deepen partnership in industrial AI</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-and-robotics-dominate-ces-2-JBo.1hHGTQCYsjBtkZZxSg</link>
      <description>The Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas showcased a wave of artificial intelligence and robotics innovations this week, with tech giants and startups unveiling products designed to transform industries from manufacturing to home care.

Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang opened the conference Monday with the announcement of the company's Rubin platform, a suite of six chips designed to power AI applications in robotics, autonomous vehicles, and edge computing[1][2][3]. Huang introduced the concept of "physical AI"—AI models trained in virtual environments using synthetic data, then deployed in physical machines[4][5]. The company also unveiled Alpamayo, open reasoning models for autonomous vehicle development[2].

On Tuesday, Siemens President Roland Busch joined Huang onstage to announce an expanded partnership focused on Industrial AI[6][7][8]. The collaboration aims to revolutionize manufacturing, production, and supply chain management using AI-driven automation[6][7]. Siemens unveiled its Digital Twin Composer, which will be available on the Siemens Xcelerator Marketplace in mid-2026[9].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--aQ1Zt8fK--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/rhbrUWyFopC23nfbvKrMvQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/30297530-ea97-11f0-bfff-8b7fb0dbf5a1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huang calls robots 'AI immigrants' to address labor gap</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-ceo-highlights-ai-robot-92nQ2d.nT52TXjeLVLDXUQ</link>
      <description>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang declared robots "AI immigrants" at CES 2026 on Tuesday, arguing that advanced robotics powered by artificial intelligence will address a mounting global workforce crisis while creating new employment opportunities. Speaking to 200 journalists and analysts at a Las Vegas hotel during the technology conference, Huang estimated the global labor shortage at "tens of millions" of workers due to aging populations and demographic decline[1][2][3].

"Having robots will create jobs," Huang said. "We need more AI immigrants to help us on manufacturing floors and do work that maybe we've decided not to do anymore"[1][2][3]. The leader of the world's most valuable company, with a market capitalization of roughly $3.5 trillion, dismissed fears that automation would eliminate human employment, instead predicting a "robotics revolution" that would boost economies and expand hiring[1][2][3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767790185/getty_uploads/2254217759_pty6lz.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran army chief threatens preemptive strike after Trump warning</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-army-chief-threatens-pree-J.Xf3QSHSIWxNfJjx0NqMA</link>
      <description>Iran's army commander warned Wednesday of potential preemptive military action in response to what he called threatening "rhetoric" from the United States, marking a sharp escalation as nationwide protests over economic collapse enter their second week[1][2][3].

Maj. Gen. Amir Hatami, speaking to military academy students, appeared to reference President Donald Trump's statement last week that if Tehran "violently kills peaceful protesters," America "will come to their rescue"[1][2][4]. "The Islamic Republic considers the intensification of such rhetoric against the Iranian nation as a threat and will not leave its continuation without a response," Hatami said, according to state-run IRNA news agency[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Z6wau9Ue--/t_thumbnail/https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/39e7238a-58c1-42dd-a3e1-6ecb049ddcd2/wirestory_dca88a657009aae21e2b8b5086c682ce_16x9.jpg%3Fw%3D1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2026 highlights AI integration in toys, health tech</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-highlights-ai-innovat-iAZVyZw5Sgy7euz60KM9Qg</link>
      <description>The annual Consumer Electronics Show opened its doors in Las Vegas this week with artificial intelligence taking center stage across nearly every product category, from interactive toys to health monitoring devices. Day 2 of the exhibition, which runs through January 9, featured keynote presentations from major technology companies and hundreds of product demonstrations emphasizing how AI is moving from abstract concept to practical application[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Uo3rn8Dy--/t_thumbnail/https://helios-i.mashable.com/imagery/articles/05oH82ww6bI0q8hZoNIeGSp/hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.v1767689372.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists extract DNA from da Vinci artwork</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-extract-possible-le-DApGjwHfSb6Itm7.BWKwFA</link>
      <description>In a remarkable development five centuries after his death, researchers have recovered trace DNA from Renaissance artifacts that may belong to Leonardo da Vinci, potentially offering unprecedented insights into the legendary polymath's genetic heritage.

Scientists from the Leonardo da Vinci DNA Project reported in a study published Monday that they successfully extracted minuscule DNA samples from a red chalk drawing titled "Holy Child," possibly created by da Vinci, and from letters written by his ancestor Frosino di Ser Giovanni da Vinci[1][2]. The findings, first reported by Science Magazine, represent a milestone in the decade-long effort to reconstruct Leonardo's genetic profile[4].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Bseen2ke--/t_thumbnail/https://cff2.earth.com/uploads/2025/12/03112053/leonardo-da-vinci-living-descendants-genetic-footprint-search.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US forces seize Russian-flagged oil tanker after Atlantic chase</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-pursues-russian-flagged-ven-e7V6Rra3R6yLQeMaq._OmQ</link>
      <description>US military and Coast Guard personnel successfully boarded the Marinera, a Russian-flagged oil tanker linked to Venezuela, in the North Atlantic on January 7 before Russian naval escorts could arrive, according to US officials[1][2][3]. The seizure caps a dramatic two-week chase across the Atlantic and marks a significant escalation in tensions between Washington and Moscow over Venezuela's shadow fleet oil trade.

The operation was conducted by US special operations forces using MH-6 Little Bird helicopters from the elite 160th Special Operations Aviation Regiment, with imagery released by Russian state media showing the aircraft operating near the vessel[1][4]. US officials confirmed that boarding personnel, including Coast Guard members, secured the tanker before Russian surface vessels and a submarine dispatched to escort it could reach the scene[1][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--d3EV0YA6--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/02/06/multimedia/06us-venezuela-russia-submarine-zbvm/06us-venezuela-russia-submarine-zbvm-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela stocks surge on Maduro ouster, US oil deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuelan-stocks-surge-after-ckhwKD2QSe.PnmkfcWHSVw</link>
      <description>Venezuela's stock market soared in the days following the January 3 capture of President Nicolás Maduro by US forces, with the Caracas Stock Exchange's IBC index surging 50% on Tuesday and adding another 16% on Monday—a combined gain of roughly 73% since the military operation[1][2][3]. The rally reflects investor optimism about potential economic reforms, though skeptics warn meaningful opportunities remain distant without political transition.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--EOEK64FQ--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108248430-17676476452026-01-05t210851z_1141386342_rc25viabdpif_rtrmadp_0_usa-venezuela.jpeg%3Fv%3D1767647717%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese software flags possible B-21 bomber flaws</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-finds-flaws-in-us-b-21-b-te_hNXqcQWe69BWf1pn.XA</link>
      <description>Chinese researchers have developed advanced simulation software that suggests potential aerodynamic and stability shortcomings in publicly available designs of the United States' B-21 Raider stealth bomber, according to a study published last month in a peer-reviewed aerospace journal.

The software system, called PADJ-X, was detailed in December 2025 by researchers led by Huang Jiangtao from the China Aerodynamics Research and Development Centre in a paper published in Acta Aeronautica et Astronautica Sinica[1][2][3][4]. Using the platform to analyze a B-21-type configuration with 288 parameters, the team found that aerodynamic optimization could increase the aircraft's lift-to-drag ratio by approximately 15 percent and improve the pitching moment from -0.2 to nearly zero, suggesting the current design may not achieve optimal stability for level flight[1][2][4].

The research comes as the B-21 Raider, built by Northrop Grumman, undergoes intensive flight testing at Edwards Air Force Base in California[4][5][6]. A second test aircraft joined the program in September 2025, marking what Air Force Secretary Troy Meink called "substantial momentum" for the sixth-generation stealth bomber[5][6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--iox-2cWw--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/06/0190ad0b-5172-44f6-b4be-0ff692ce86d5_44821b34.jpg%3Fitok%3DA2OBQgKX%26v%3D1767686387" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China orders tech firms to halt Nvidia H200 chip purchases</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-halts-nvidia-h200-chip-o-7EouWXq_SC2.wfcP3HkbaA</link>
      <description>Just one day after Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang touted "very high" Chinese demand for the company's H200 AI chips, Beijing has instructed tech companies to temporarily halt orders for the processors, according to multiple reports[1][2].

The directive, reported by Reuters and The Information on January 7, marks an abrupt reversal following the Trump administration's December decision to allow sales of the advanced chips to China[1][2]. The move underscores Beijing's push for semiconductor self-sufficiency even as US export licenses remain pending approval.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767801849/url_uploads/CLHswNNmLJVCzbL7mYDgNS_akbjcj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morocco fossils illuminate split between humans, Neanderthals</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/773000-year-old-moroccan-fossi-2.BkisHTSjKasX5_P618xw</link>
      <description>Scientists unveiled Wednesday the discovery of 773,000-year-old hominin fossils in Morocco that may represent populations living near the evolutionary crossroads where modern humans, Neanderthals, and Denisovans diverged—filling a critical gap in the African fossil record and reinforcing Africa as the birthplace of our species[1][2][3][4].

The fossils, published in Nature, were unearthed from Grotte à Hominidés, a cave at the Thomas Quarry I site near Casablanca[1][2][3]. An international research team led by Jean-Jacques Hublin of the Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology in Germany analyzed three partial jawbones—including one from a child—along with several vertebrae and teeth[1][2][5][6][3]. The remains display a mosaic of primitive features resembling Homo erectus and more modern traits seen in later humans[1][5][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--e2x9sa-A--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/07/multimedia/07HS-sci-missing-link-03-gcmw/07HS-sci-missing-link-03-gcmw-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US seizes second Venezuelan oil tanker in Caribbean</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-seizes-second-venezuelan-oi-pKUhOZAbQJy2j0EYN9vPuQ</link>
      <description>U.S. forces seized a second sanctioned oil tanker linked to Venezuela on Wednesday, conducting back-to-back operations in the Caribbean and North Atlantic as President Donald Trump escalates enforcement of his blockade on Venezuelan oil exports.

The M/T Sophia, described by U.S. Southern Command as a "stateless, sanctioned dark fleet motor tanker," was apprehended in a predawn operation in international waters of the Caribbean Sea[1][2]. The Panama-flagged supertanker had departed Venezuelan waters in early January, operating with its transponder turned off in "dark mode" as part of a fleet carrying Venezuelan oil to China[3][4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--oaxG6wtN--/t_thumbnail/https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2026-01/260107-Marinera-tanker-rs-034378.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds aviation emissions could be cut by up to 75%</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/study-finds-aviation-emissions-q2uwe4JlSWipY0MS5WqrQw</link>
      <description>Global aviation emissions could be reduced by 50 to 75 percent through three efficiency strategies already within reach: deploying the most fuel-efficient aircraft, eliminating premium cabin seating, and filling more seats on each flight, according to a study published Tuesday in Nature Communications Earth &amp; Environment[1][2][3].

The research, co-led by the University of Oxford and Linnaeus University, analyzed more than 27 million commercial flights in 2023, revealing that airlines could achieve an 11 percent reduction in emissions immediately by better allocating their existing efficient aircraft on routes they already operate[1][2][3].

"Our results clearly show that efficiency-focused policy could swiftly reduce aviation emissions by more than half, without reducing flight numbers or waiting for future fuels," said co-author Dr. Milan Klöwer of Oxford's Department of Physics[2][3]. "These are tools that we can use right now."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--_QSXtN26--/t_thumbnail/https://www.greenairnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Heathrow-Airport-aircraft-landing-hi-res.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet releases water far from sun</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/interstellar-comet-3iatlas-sho-b4ndjZ_ERcijL3zxnRaB9A</link>
      <description>Astronomers have confirmed that the rare interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS is a natural comet, not an alien spacecraft, following the most comprehensive radio signal search ever conducted on an object from beyond the solar system. The confirmation comes as new observations reveal the comet is releasing water at extraordinary rates and may be among the oldest objects ever observed, potentially dating back 7 to 14 billion years[1][2][3].

Results published this week from the Breakthrough Listen initiative show that multiple radio telescopes, including the Green Bank Telescope, detected no artificial signals during observations conducted as the comet made its closest approach to Earth on December 19, 2025[1][4]. The Green Bank facility, the world's largest fully-steerable radio telescope, ruled out transmitters down to 0.1 watts—ten times weaker than a typical cell phone—during observations on December 18[1][5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--uB5GG23d--/t_thumbnail/https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/05135917/SEI_276769933.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI home robots and autonomous cars debut at CES 2026</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-showcases-ai-innovati-VyY3GQvIQKiu6_IlFwlfTQ</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence dominated CES 2026 as tech giants unveiled home robots, entertainment-focused electric vehicles, and autonomous driving systems during the four-day event that opened January 6 in Las Vegas[1]. NVIDIA CEO Jensen Huang declared at Monday's keynote that AI is "scaling into every domain and every device," signaling a shift from data centers to physical applications in daily life[2].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--no6MHHX2--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/iv.Avvt2mFJu43EEqo.Xaw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://d29szjachogqwa.cloudfront.net/images/user-uploaded/2026_CES_Sony_Honda_Mobility_006.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 nations pledge Ukraine security guarantees at Paris summit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/coalition-of-willing-summit-pr-dT_oHcNmTy.wbgf00yb_ww</link>
      <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy hailed "concrete results" from a historic Paris summit where over 30 nations agreed to provide robust security guarantees in the event of a ceasefire with Russia, though critical issues including territorial disputes remain unresolved[1][2][3][4].

At Tuesday's Coalition of the Willing meeting, France and the United Kingdom signed a declaration committing to deploy troops and establish military hubs across Ukraine if a peace deal is reached[2][5][6]. French President Emmanuel Macron announced that Paris could deploy "several thousand" troops to monitor the Russia-Ukraine border and help regenerate Ukrainian armed forces, emphasizing these would not be combat forces[7][8][9].

The summit marked the first time the United States directly backed the coalition's security framework, with US envoy Steve Witkoff declaring that President Donald Trump "strongly, strongly stands behind security protocols"[2][10][11]. The American delegation, which included Trump's son-in-law Jared Kushner and Gen. Alexus Grynkewich, reported "significant progress on several critical workstreams, including our bilateral security guarantee framework"[1][12][13].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--DWlOq_KM--/t_thumbnail/https://img.lemde.fr/2026/01/06/1/0/6978/4652/1440/960/60/0/65d3359_ftp-1-1apt7ehyu5wu-2caa8964198a4822a42e5e29b0b66dff-0-335456495c7647b3862ebec0947a0692.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU to suspend fertiliser tariffs and carbon levy</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-considers-tariff-changes-an-Vf75zFH_SACVvNvIAugkCw</link>
      <description>The European Commission announced measures Wednesday to temporarily suspend tariffs and carbon levies on fertiliser imports following pressure from France and Italy to ease costs for struggling farmers.

EU Trade Commissioner Maros Sefcovic told agriculture ministers at a meeting in Brussels that the Commission will propose to temporarily suspend remaining most favored nation tariffs on ammonia, urea and other fertilisers[1][2]. The tariffs currently stand at 6.5% for ammonia and 5.5% for urea[1]. Additionally, the Commission will issue guidance allowing temporary suspension of the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism on fertilisers, retroactive to January 1, 2026[3][4][5].

"Keeping fertilisers affordable is vital for farmers' incomes and Europe's food security," Sefcovic said at a press conference[1]. "While prices have stabilised, fertiliser costs remain around 60% higher than in 2020 and that is simply not sustainable."[1]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--VrDcdNhq--/t_thumbnail/https://media.zenfs.com/en/euronews_us_articles_576/88bd3f07c97a00b0c7e20de429707cf9" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>60,000-year-old poisoned arrows found in South Africa</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/60000-year-old-poisoned-arrows-Eq1C4uFaRD2XgeOIM18rcQ</link>
      <description>Researchers have identified poison residues on 60,000-year-old arrowheads from South Africa, marking the earliest direct evidence of humans using poisoned weapons and pushing back this hunting practice by more than 50,000 years, according to a study published Tuesday in Science Advances[1][2][3].

The discovery at Umhlatuzana Rock Shelter in KwaZulu-Natal province reveals that early *Homo sapiens* possessed sophisticated knowledge of plant toxins and advanced cognitive abilities far earlier than previously documented[1][2][3]. Before this finding, the oldest confirmed poisoned arrows dated to approximately 7,000 years ago during the mid-Holocene period[1][4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--HiEbumiQ--/t_thumbnail/https://assets.iflscience.com/assets/articleNo/75972/aImg/78893/poison-arrow-o.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
