<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:36:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese researchers report perovskite solar efficiency record</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-scientists-boost-solar-aGdyZdHyTz2Y7zsd_CVmAg</link>
      <description>A cluster of Chinese-led research results published and announced in January points to rapid progress on two long-running solar challenges: pushing conversion efficiency higher while keeping cells and panels stable under heat, humidity and uneven real-world conditions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In one of the latest headline-grabbers, trade outlets reported that Shenzhen-based perovskite developer SolaEon said it reached 27.87% power-conversion efficiency on a single-junction perovskite cell, with the measurement certified by China’s National Photovoltaic Industry Metrology and Testing Center (NPVM). The reports described the result as a laboratory-scale device, underscoring that the road from record cells to mass-produced modules still runs through durability testing and manufacturing scale-up.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/CVTEjYL7w_2v66ng1XgeOg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_cool_down_737/0c2dd0b8e8ae69a0dff9e8ae72d6ac81" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Webb confirms most distant galaxy ever observed</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-maps-dark-wl.4RV2iSGGzE6_AsX8acw</link>
      <description>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope has delivered two landmark discoveries this week, producing the most detailed map of dark matter ever created and confirming the most distant galaxy ever observed, offering new windows into the universe's invisible architecture and earliest moments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dark matter map, published January 26 in the journal Nature Astronomy, captures nearly 800,000 galaxies in the constellation Sextans and reveals the universe's hidden scaffolding with twice the resolution of any previous map. Just two days later, astronomers announced the confirmation of galaxy MoM-z14, which existed just 280 million years after the Big Bang—making it the most distant known object in the universe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/VKw2siavwce_5UrGje.JbQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD01MDA-/https://d29szjachogqwa.cloudfront.net/images/user-uploaded/Webb_Telescope_MoM-z14.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds water can survive near Earth's core in superionic state</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/superionic-state-enables-long-4HyRAmdWTZ.pRBFR49vX2g</link>
      <description>New research published January 28 in Science Advances reveals that water can survive the extreme conditions of Earth's deep lower mantle by entering a superionic state, challenging the long-held assumption that most hydrous minerals release their water at high temperatures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Scientists from the Institute of Geochemistry of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (IGCAS) used molecular dynamics simulations combining ab initio and deep-learning potential methods to study how water behaves near Earth's core-mantle boundary. The findings suggest that ancient water from Earth's early stages may have been preserved over geological timescales, accumulating as a long-term reservoir near the base of the mantle.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.thebrighterside.news/uploads/2026/01/water-3.webp?format=auto&amp;optimize=high&amp;width=1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford, Osaka teams advance light-based quantum computing</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/researchers-advance-light-base-BOUmB9KbRrStVyzSAuYRgw</link>
      <description>Two research teams are using light to tackle one of quantum computing’s core hurdles: how to scale fragile atomic systems from laboratory demonstrations into machines with enough qubits to do useful work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In results published over the past week, Stanford researchers reported an optical-cavity “readout” platform designed to pull information quickly from many atom-based qubits at once, while a University of Osaka group detailed a nanophotonic routing scheme aimed at delivering multiple laser colors across trapped-ion chips without a tangle of free-space optics.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/new-light-based-platfo-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China unveils plans for space tourism and orbital AI data centers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-plans-space-tourism-and-4LbkB1KkQTiaJh.5VQ2dfA</link>
      <description>China unveiled ambitious plans this week to develop space tourism and launch orbiting artificial intelligence data centers within five years, escalating competition with the United States in what both nations see as the next frontier for commercial and strategic dominance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;State media reported on Thursday that China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC), the country's primary space contractor, has committed to establishing gigawatt-class "space digital intelligence infrastructure" as part of its 15th Five-Year Plan spanning 2026-2030. The initiative aims to process Earth-generated data in orbit by combining computing power, storage capabilities, and transmission bandwidth, according to CCTV.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_%21RWlT%21%2Cw_1200%2Ch_675%2Cc_fill%2Cf_jpg%2Cq_auto:good%2Cfl_progressive:steep%2Cg_auto/https%253A%252F%252Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fpublic%252Fimages%252F7e49472c-3117-4edf-8029-3ad11db7d91a_3746x2082.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP shares tumble after cloud backlog growth misses expectations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sap-shares-plunge-11-percent-a-_9in.bjsStqUWHZBrKMJ9w</link>
      <description>SAP SE, Europe's largest software company, suffered its steepest single-day drop since October 2020 on Thursday after reporting cloud contract backlog growth that fell short of investor expectations, extending a selloff that has erased approximately $150 billion from its market capitalization since its 2025 peak.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shares of the German enterprise software giant fell as much as 14% in early European trading before settling around an 11% decline, hitting their lowest level since June 2024. The selloff came despite strong full-year operating profit and record free cash flow, underscoring how closely investors are scrutinizing cloud metrics amid growing concerns about AI disruption in the software sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iAjAj3jDg9p0/v0/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper hits record high as speculation and weak dollar drive rally</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/copper-prices-hit-record-highs-DGOKFQesRTWBoT7iHnyeHQ</link>
      <description>Copper surged past $14,000 per metric ton on Thursday, posting its largest single-day gain in over 16 years as a wave of speculative trading in China and a persistently weak U.S. dollar fueled a broader rally across global metals markets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Futures on the London Metal Exchange rose as much as 7.9% to reach a record $14,125 per ton before pulling back slightly in early European trading. The most-active contract on the Shanghai Futures Exchange jumped 6.35% to 108,740 yuan ($15,652) per metric ton, also setting an all-time high.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/qHMzUBfWaiu5XWhoBuyGfg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/5ab527b5ba79f84b09e3aaeaff194d6a" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyundai Q4 profit drops 40% as US tariffs cost $2.87B</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hyundai-q4-profit-drops-40-per-lfpf5guuTTioXQp6S96F7g</link>
      <description>Hyundai Motor reported a worse-than-expected 40 percent fall in fourth-quarter operating profit on Thursday, as U.S. tariffs cost the South Korean automaker an estimated 4.1 trillion won ($2.87 billion) last year. The company warned of continued challenges in 2026 but forecast improved sales and profit margins despite looming threats of higher levies from Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The October-December results mark the third consecutive quarterly profit decline for the world's third-largest automaking group by sales. Hyundai booked operating profit of 1.7 trillion won ($1.19 billion) for the quarter, down from 2.8 trillion won in the same period a year earlier, missing the 2.7 trillion won consensus estimate from analysts surveyed by LSEG.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4DZJ5FHR6ZIGXNUGXACCKTXK24.jpg?auth=a1f67ef66144ea8890982ba5dc72152122baf4a849a061ad5eeffc0049faab9c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canal Plus shares surge after projecting synergies from MultiChoice deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canal-plus-targets-over-400-mi-L36v1aZwQ7WqMjaleaM23w</link>
      <description>Canal+ on Thursday announced it expects to deliver over 400 million euros in annual cost synergies and over 300 million euros in free cash flow synergies from 2030 following its $3 billion acquisition of South African broadcaster MultiChoice Group, sending shares to a record high.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Paris-based media company's stock rose approximately 14% after executives outlined synergy targets that analysts described as exceeding expectations. Bank of America raised its price target to 450 pence from 400 pence, calling the projected savings "meaningfully above expectations" of 100 million to 200 million euros.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/76G2TQJCHZO7DDFNOIDQWOM5FY.jpg?auth=4441cde2003e4c28e8a9162af2cfee1f4fe65ec34ea66820a78f66f24b765f56&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold snap threatens to delay NASA's Artemis II moon mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/artemis-ii-faces-possible-laun-CHtr_vsFQFCNgyUV1nFJKQ</link>
      <description>NASA is watching an unusual Florida cold snap that could complicate final preparations for Artemis II, the agency’s first crewed mission around the Moon since Apollo. Forecasts calling for overnight lows near freezing along the Space Coast have raised the risk that temperature constraints could interrupt a key prelaunch fueling test—and potentially push back a launch planned no earlier than early February.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Artemis II Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft, now on the pad at Kennedy Space Center, must complete a “wet dress rehearsal” before NASA sets an official liftoff date. The test involves loading the rocket with cryogenic propellants and running a full countdown without actually launching.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/QnXhKmI0No05ggLPdtkGQA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/usa_today_news_641/f0a8e3a565f6fbe758afbac4d396454c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian researchers report advances in solar panel cooling, perovskite efficiency</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hydrogel-coating-and-perovskit-icvPRfSgQC6BMUMswfPPsw</link>
      <description>Two research teams in Asia have reported advances aimed at squeezing more electricity from solar hardware in the real world: one by cooling conventional silicon panels at their hottest failure-prone points, the other by pushing perovskite technology closer to scalable, high-efficiency modules.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In Hong Kong, researchers at The Hong Kong Polytechnic University said a hydrogel-based layer can reduce “hot spot” temperatures on panels while raising output, a result they argue could be especially relevant for dense cities with rooftop and building-integrated solar. In South Korea, a team led by Gwangju Institute of Science and Technology (GIST) reported a perovskite mini-module with 22.56% efficiency, addressing a key hurdle in making perovskites perform reliably as device area increases.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.polyu.edu.hk/-/media/department/home/media-release/2026/0120/photo-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists propose quantum batteries to power quantum computers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-unveil-quantum-batt-Y4m309cWQvy4._VJkUTeEA</link>
      <description>Researchers from Australia and Japan have proposed an approach to powering quantum computers using quantum batteries, a development they say could make future machines faster, more energy efficient, and easier to scale. The theoretical framework, published January 28 in Physical Review X, suggests quantum batteries could quadruple the number of qubits that fit within current cryogenic systems while reducing the infrastructure demands that have long stymied the technology's commercial progress.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Quantum computers rely on delicate quantum states to perform calculations far beyond the reach of classical machines, but sustaining those states typically requires room-sized, energy-intensive cryogenic cooling systems and complex room-temperature electronics. These constraints remain among the biggest barriers to scaling quantum computing technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.csiro.au/-/media/Newsletters/RI-FSP/Quantum-computer-dark-close-up.jpeg?mw=1200&amp;hash=497C029C5C77D357917DBCDB88C147FD" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China, Netherlands, Australia all set renewable energy records in 2025</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-netherlands-australia-se-Ma8WjjXVRfu.iDsfH5y52w</link>
      <description>Three nations on three continents achieved milestones in clean energy last year, demonstrating the global momentum of the renewable transition even as challenges remain. China installed record amounts of wind and solar capacity, the Netherlands met 57% of its electricity needs from renewables, and Australia's grid crossed the 50% renewable threshold for the first time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://courthousenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/china-wind-turbine-aerial-shot-800x600.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK and China announce trade deals during Starmer's Beijing visit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starmer-secures-closer-uk-chin-JKJjh36jRgKMrkZVK6G9SQ</link>
      <description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and Chinese President Xi Jinping announced a series of agreements on Thursday aimed at revitalizing economic ties between their nations, including a $15 billion investment pledge from AstraZeneca and reduced tariffs on Scotch whisky, during the first visit by a UK leader to China in eight years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The meeting, held at Beijing's Great Hall of the People and lasting approximately 80 minutes, produced what Starmer called "concrete outcomes" that put the bilateral relationship in a "strong place." Xi acknowledged the relationship had experienced "twists and turns" but expressed China's readiness to cultivate a long-term partnership.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/IC3OKWMI3VLHPKMA3JA7BNTORY.jpg?auth=b6ad4dc85a8eb4e872ba64dd5f6def4877ace350058d16d8e89c210868211846&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds microplastics in one third of fish off Pacific islands</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/microplastics-found-in-one-thi-TpJYsgOPQ2G6Kzl2mSUHsA</link>
      <description>A third of fish living off the coasts of remote Pacific Island nations contain microplastics, according to a study published this week, providing new evidence that plastic pollution has reached even the most isolated marine ecosystems on Earth.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, published Wednesday in PLOS One, examined 878 fish from 138 species caught by fishing communities in Fiji, Tonga, Tuvalu, and Vanuatu. While the overall contamination rate was lower than the global average of 49 percent, researchers found stark disparities between islands—with nearly 75 percent of fish sampled in Fiji containing microplastics, compared to just 5 percent in Vanuatu.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.oceanographicmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/07104818/Hawaii-ocean-plastics-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists detect dark matter clump near the Sun for the first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-uncovers-BdtaBO1lQbuKCx32izRjyQ</link>
      <description>New observational evidence is reshaping scientists' understanding of two of the universe's greatest enigmas: the origins of supermassive black holes and the hidden distribution of dark matter in our galaxy. Both breakthroughs rely on innovative techniques to detect objects that cannot be seen directly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a paper published January 29 in Physical Review Letters, astronomers led by Sukanya Chakrabarti at the University of Alabama in Huntsville report finding a massive dark matter clump lurking in the galactic neighborhood of the Sun. The suspected subhalo has a mass roughly 10 million times that of the Sun and is located about 3,260 light-years away.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/08151826/dark_matter_galaxy_pr_final.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google dismantles massive Chinese cyber network linked to malware</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/google-takes-down-chinese-cybe-CK17i_l6Qa6ZA4mP15crSA</link>
      <description>Google used a federal court order on Wednesday to dismantle what it describes as one of the largest residential proxy networks in the world, seizing dozens of domains belonging to the Chinese firm IPIDEA and cutting millions of devices from its infrastructure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The coordinated action, led by Google's Threat Intelligence Group, targeted a network that cybersecurity researchers say covertly installed malicious software on smartphones, computers, and Android devices worldwide. The operation is expected to disconnect more than nine million Android devices from IPIDEA's network.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769701756/getty_uploads/2258008476_idc1bo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold, silver, palladium retreat sharply as investors take profits</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-and-palladium-prices-plun-4Br4rpDrST2aGEybNaE1sw</link>
      <description>Gold, palladium, and silver retreated sharply on Thursday as investors locked in profits following a historic rally that pushed precious metals to record highs. The selloff came a day after the Federal Reserve held interest rates steady and as traders reassessed positions after weeks of gains.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spot gold fell as much as 4% during Thursday's trading to around $5,150 per ounce, pulling back from record highs above $5,500 reached earlier in the week. Palladium tumbled 5% to approximately $1,969 per ounce, while silver dropped more than 5% to around $110 per ounce after briefly touching $120 earlier in the session.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/NTC6CLJUJVINBIZVPODMLDGVAU.jpg?auth=b9b4d5481988eda4144420b19965daf3d15bd9357bcb89947ed78cfd26388828&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump orders Venezuelan airspace reopened for commercial travel</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-reopening-of-v-TtOLAWJ5R7arsuyMQGlfUA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump said Thursday he has instructed U.S. officials to reopen Venezuelan airspace for commercial travel, a move that could ease flight planning across northern South America and, he suggested, clear the way for Americans to visit Venezuela again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump said he relayed the decision to Venezuela’s acting leader, Delcy Rodríguez, and directed Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy and U.S. military leaders to open “all commercial airspace over Venezuela” by the end of the day. “American citizens will be very shortly able to go to Venezuela, and they’ll be safe there,” Trump said, according to an Associated Press account carried by multiple outlets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.tribuneindia.com/sortd-service/imaginary/v22-01/jpg/large/high?url=dGhldHJpYnVuZS1zb3J0ZC1wcm8tcHJvZC1zb3J0ZC9tZWRpYTM1NDE3ZDgwLWNkNDQtMTFmMC1hNWYzLWU1NWZlMzk3YzBhZi5qcGc=" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU approves new Iran sanctions, moves to designate IRGC as terrorist group</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-approves-new-iran-sanctions-BgHOlLpESsmCAfpowS2X9w</link>
      <description>European Union foreign ministers on Jan. 29 approved a new round of sanctions against Iran over a lethal crackdown on nationwide protests and moved toward listing the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) as a terrorist organisation—an escalation EU officials said would put the force in the same category as groups such as al-Qaeda and ISIS.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The measures come amid mounting international pressure on Tehran, as activists and rights groups report thousands killed since demonstrations erupted in late December, while Iranian authorities cite a far lower death toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2026/01/AFP__20260129__94DQ3MC__v1__HighRes__BelgiumEuCouncilPoliticsDiplomacy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
