<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:33:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Gold tops $4,900 per ounce for first time amid global turmoil</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-hits-4900-and-platinum-re-rg6hTKHXRj29h3.uCLkJxA</link>
      <description>Spot gold crossed the $4,900-per-ounce threshold for the first time on Thursday, while platinum surged to an all-time high, as investors piled into precious metals amid escalating geopolitical tensions and turmoil in global bond markets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The historic rally extends gold's extraordinary run into 2026, with the metal gaining 11% since the start of the year and approximately 75% over the past 12 months. Platinum, meanwhile, rose 3% to reach a record $2,558.20 per ounce, having climbed nearly 160% over the past year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/RLUKIFYVOZPSBGC6KLJWR4DTAE.jpg?auth=57b2cc53f61b9725bba86f78eb624aef64cb010cc3e49656baa52154adcae4f1&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU suspends trade deal approval amid Trump's Greenland push</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-pushes-greenland-deal-am-LyWThW0sTmW.UwImtHWd1w</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared Thursday that the United States would have "total access" to Greenland under a framework agreement reached with NATO, even as the European Union suspended approval of a bilateral trade deal in response to weeks of tariff threats tied to the Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump's announcement, made from the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, marked an apparent de-escalation after he withdrew his threat to impose 10% tariffs on eight European nations beginning February 1. But the deal's specifics remain unclear, and Denmark has firmly stated its sovereignty is not up for negotiation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2025-07/250728-donald-trump-ursula-von-der-leyen-se-458p-e99056.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earthquake monitors can track falling space debris, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/earthquake-monitors-track-spac-0X9HrvrLRv2.tmakxEFY8w</link>
      <description>Scientists have demonstrated that earthquake monitors can track falling space debris through sonic booms, offering a new method to pinpoint where dangerous fragments land as the skies become increasingly crowded with satellites.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers reported Thursday that seismic readings from sonic booms generated when a discarded Chinese crew capsule module reentered over Southern California in 2024 allowed them to place the object's path nearly 20 miles farther south than radar had predicted from orbit, according to findings published in the journal Science.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The problem at the moment is we can track stuff very well in space," said Benjamin Fernando of Johns Hopkins University, the lead researcher. "But once it gets to the point that it's actually breaking up in the atmosphere, it becomes very difficult to track."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.euronews.com/articles/stories/05/62/56/22/1024x538_cmsv2_118857d7-4194-5c59-ab85-6cc0ef834fdb-5625622.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and China offer dueling visions on trade at Davos</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-and-china-clash-at-2026-71Kleb18TVydmWXZlC2Izw</link>
      <description>The 2026 World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, became a stage for clashing economic worldviews this week as President Donald Trump defended his aggressive tariff policies while Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng championed multilateralism and free trade—a split that is accelerating the reshaping of global economic alliances.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump addressed the forum on Wednesday, touting what he called an "economic miracle" achieved through tariffs that he said slashed the U.S. monthly trade deficit by 77 percent in one year. "Virtually all of the so-called experts predicted my plans to end this failed model would trigger a global recession and runaway inflation. But we have proven them wrong," he declared. He criticized European economic policies, stating that "certain places in Europe are not even recognizable, frankly, anymore."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/C5KTZJJFMBNC7FLTIKNL2PSOGQ.jpg?auth=c7bb614cdf5f36bf8403f42defe9cebdefbcb7e771bdbab3eebe43b0aa89c1dc&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shell weighs sale of Argentina shale assets, sources say</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/shell-weighs-sale-of-argentina-jpb95p8qTla8ncRw0t0mPA</link>
      <description>Shell is considering selling some or all of its assets in Argentina's Vaca Muerta shale formation, a move that would mark a surprise exit by one of the region's earliest backers just as international interest in the massive play intensifies, according to a Reuters report citing three sources familiar with the matter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The oil major has approached potential buyers in recent weeks to gauge interest in the holdings, which are likely to be valued in the billions of dollars, two of the sources said. However, a sale is not guaranteed, and Shell could still choose to retain the assets. The company declined to comment.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/2SLM2434PFOGNF4BSZ2OM7MHGA.jpg?auth=ec104202ac309ca68467e8e7afb8239d8e3c359e576932821b5bca1d3c045dc5&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope solves mystery of how crystals form in icy comets</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-reveals-helix-nebul-3btx4NZPQJGuu_UGLZ2BAQ</link>
      <description>The James Webb Space Telescope has delivered a striking one-two punch of cosmic discoveries this week, capturing the clearest infrared images ever taken of the Helix Nebula while also solving a decades-old puzzle about how crystals found in comets formed in the frozen reaches of space.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;NASA unveiled the new Helix Nebula images on Tuesday, offering an unprecedented look at one of the most photographed planetary nebulas in the sky. Located 650 light-years from Earth in the constellation Aquarius and often called the "Eye of God," the nebula has never appeared with such detail.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/7j2WiyM0za8/maxresdefault.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS reaches rare opposition today</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-makes-rare-final-appea-49hOb2mtT6yE1FdP2ydmCA</link>
      <description>The interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS reaches a rare and fleeting celestial alignment today, positioning itself directly opposite the sun from Earth's perspective and offering scientists a once-in-decades opportunity to study material from another star system before the enigmatic visitor departs forever.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At 13:00 UTC on January 22, 2026, 3I/ATLAS will align to within just 0.69 degrees of the Earth-Sun axis—an exceptionally small angle that creates ideal conditions for what astronomers call an "opposition surge," a phenomenon that will cause the object to appear brighter and reveal more about its composition. Unlike typical cometary oppositions that last only hours, this alignment will keep 3I/ATLAS within two degrees of the axis for approximately one week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.euronews.com/articles/stories/09/60/64/93/1536x864_cmsv2_2be77f64-d1d9-5b05-8742-78ac2865aced-9606493.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin meets US envoys in Kremlin as Ukraine talks near final stretch</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/putin-meets-us-envoys-witkoff-U4Z6O8h8QLy4XdM_VV7EmA</link>
      <description>Russian President Vladimir Putin began late-night talks with US envoys Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner at the Kremlin on Thursday, January 22, 2026, as diplomatic efforts to end the nearly four-year Ukraine war enter what negotiators describe as a final stretch.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The meeting, which started shortly before midnight Moscow time, brought together three American representatives—Witkoff, Kushner, and newly appointed senior adviser Josh Gruenbaum—with Putin's team, including foreign policy aide Yuri Ushakov and special envoy Kirill Dmitriev, according to the Kremlin's official account. A brief video released by Russian state media showed Putin shaking hands with the American delegation and inviting them to a long oval table.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/NUU5GV7C4FKQTPZXQ5577BN4TE.jpg?auth=4a43002e507a321df62a7698b58c6efb56e4c644a6e1221cc7f9500f1bc68666&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Parliament freezes U.S. trade deal over Trump tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-greenland-tariff-threats-n2BU1kFDSQWxJNIo8Uswag</link>
      <description>European lawmakers have frozen work on an EU-U.S. trade agreement after President Donald Trump tied threatened tariffs on key U.S. allies to his push for greater U.S. control and access in Greenland, reopening a geopolitical dispute that had already rattled markets this week.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The standoff escalated after Trump said he would impose new duties on eight European countries beginning Feb. 1 unless an arrangement was reached over Greenland—then reversed course in Davos, saying he would not use force and that a “framework” with NATO was in view, prompting a relief bounce in equities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2025-07/250728-donald-trump-ursula-von-der-leyen-se-458p-e99056.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds climate adaptation can curb migration in Africa</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/study-finds-climate-adaptation-LJicBfKnT2Wu6cHbTEirFg</link>
      <description>Investments that help communities withstand drought and conflict—especially by boosting farm productivity and basic services—may also curb displacement pressures across Africa, according to a new peer‑reviewed study published in the journal Sustainable Development.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, led by Hyun Kim of Chungnam National University, analyzes African country- and grid-level data spanning 1995–2015 and finds that **stronger “adaptive capacity”** is associated with **lower migration during periods of drought or armed conflict**, acting as a buffer when shocks hit.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.cimmyt.org/content/uploads/2019/03/1-Mary-Munini.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump, Zelenskyy hold talks in Davos as peace deal nears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-and-zelenskyy-hold-talks-U0JlaJ4UQni3yUIXriyTDw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy met for approximately one hour behind closed doors at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, on Thursday, with both leaders describing the discussions as productive amid signs of progress toward a potential end to the nearly four-year war with Russia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump told reporters the meeting was "good" and reiterated his message: "The war has to end." Zelenskyy described the talks as "productive and meaningful," thanking Trump for his efforts to "stop the bloodshed and bring the war to an end."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/QMdTIv.aeoXrT8oyZJiV1g--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyNDI7aD04Mjk7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/dpa_international_526/7066904b9ea88cb57bd652d142278864" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland Ice Sheet could vanish by 2300 under high emissions, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/greenland-s-melting-ice-sheet-6rwkEdh8RmKzV2tUC2JDLg</link>
      <description>New research has revealed that under high-emission scenarios, the Greenland Ice Sheet could largely disappear over the coming centuries, threatening to raise global sea levels by more than seven meters and reshape coastlines worldwide. Scientists warn that accelerating ice loss and newly identified feedback mechanisms may be pushing Greenland's ice toward a point of no return.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.snexplores.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2022/11/110822_no_greenland_feat.jpg?w=1030" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists revive 3.2-billion-year-old enzyme to study early life on Earth</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uw-madison-team-revives-32-bil-7EHSBP5aQpS93TTsef61SA</link>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Wisconsin–Madison have resurrected a 3.2-billion-year-old enzyme and studied it inside living microbes, creating a new way to understand the origins of life on Earth and potentially recognize signs of life on other planets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The NASA-funded study, published in Nature Communications on January 22, uses synthetic biology to reverse-engineer modern enzymes and rebuild their ancient ancestors. The research team, led by Betül Kaçar, a professor of bacteriology, and Holly Rucker, a PhD candidate in Kaçar's lab, focused on nitrogenase, an enzyme essential for converting atmospheric nitrogen into a form usable by living organisms.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We picked an enzyme that really set the tone of life on this planet and then interrogated its history," Kaçar says. "Without nitrogenase, there would be no life as we know it."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 01:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://news.wisc.edu/content/uploads/2026/01/Kacar-Betul-lab-2025-01-03JM_6564-1200x800.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds AI image generators converge on 12 generic themes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/study-finds-ai-drives-cultural-JzUhg1zVQEKDKCXXjdtksg</link>
      <description>When artificial intelligence systems are left to create and interpret their own outputs, they converge on just 12 generic visual themes regardless of how diverse or creative the original prompts were, according to new research that provides the first empirical evidence of AI-driven cultural homogenization.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, published this month in the journal Patterns, demonstrates that generative AI systems naturally tend toward bland, commercially safe aesthetics when used autonomously—a finding researchers describe as "visual elevator music."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 01:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/art-museum.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US seeks to eliminate all restrictions on Greenland military access</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-seeks-to-renegotiate-1951-g-7knuh9B0Rca8pqG6FdfjiQ</link>
      <description>The United States is pushing to rewrite its seven-decade-old defense agreement with Denmark to remove all restrictions on its military presence in Greenland, according to people familiar with the negotiations, as American negotiators seek to satisfy President Donald Trump's demands for control over the strategic Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The original 1951 agreement, which was amended in 2004, requires the US to "consult with and inform" Denmark and Greenland before making "any significant changes to United States military operations or facilities in Greenland." American negotiators now want to eliminate this language entirely to ensure the US faces no restrictions in its military planning, according to sources who spoke to Bloomberg on condition of anonymity.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769134033/url_uploads/-1x-1_oilfqf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China launches high-efficiency lithium extraction facility</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/new-lithium-extraction-methods-35UTFDWMSdyHSeEEcJAn8g</link>
      <description>Researchers in the United States and China have announced advances in lithium extraction technology that could address supply chain bottlenecks for electric vehicle batteries and renewable energy storage systems. The developments, revealed within days of each other, promise faster and cleaner methods for recovering lithium from brine sources that traditional techniques struggle to exploit.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.asiafinancial.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/chaerhan_salt_lake_trip.com_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump revokes Canada's invitation to Board of Peace</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-revokes-canada-s-invitat-7xwElXikSGGiLQQeVY8WXA</link>
      <description>U.S. President Donald Trump withdrew Canada's invitation to join his Board of Peace initiative on Thursday, marking an escalation in the diplomatic clash between Washington and Ottawa following Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney's critique of American dominance at the World Economic Forum in Davos.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a message posted on Truth Social, Trump addressed Carney directly: "Please let this Letter serve to represent that the Board of Peace is withdrawing its invitation to you regarding Canada's joining, what will be the most prestigious Board of Leaders ever assembled, at any time."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://foreignpolicy.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/BoardofPeaceGettyImages-2256946872-1.jpg?w=1000" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold nears $5,000 record as Trump announces naval fleet heading to Iran</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-nears-5000-dollar-record-8C9PhkZISUeIV8FKqFjy3Q</link>
      <description>Gold surged to an unprecedented high just shy of $5,000 an ounce on Friday, as escalating geopolitical tensions and a weakening dollar propelled the precious metal toward a historic milestone. Spot gold rose to a record $4,967.48 per ounce, marking a nearly 15% gain since the start of 2026 and extending a rally that saw the metal climb roughly 64% last year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The rally gained fresh momentum after President Donald Trump announced that a "massive" U.S. naval force is heading toward Iran, reigniting Middle East tensions that had briefly cooled following his retreat from Greenland tariff threats. "We have an armada. We have a massive fleet heading in that direction, and maybe we won't have to use it," Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One returning from the World Economic Forum in Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108234177-1764563718395-gettyimages-2240539484-AUSTRALIA_GOLD.jpeg?v=1767720612&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US control of Venezuela oil threatens China's debt repayment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-control-of-venezuela-oil-th-RfG.Kj4CTkO2.towhtlNdw</link>
      <description>The United States' takeover of Venezuela's oil exports has ensnared crude shipments that were servicing debt to China, setting the stage for a potential showdown between the two superpowers that could further complicate the South American nation's path out of default.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Around a tenth of Venezuela's $150 billion foreign debt pile is estimated to be loans from China that the OPEC member was paying in oil cargoes — until the US seized Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro earlier this month. The Trump administration has announced that proceeds from Venezuelan oil sales will be directed to a Qatar-based account under Washington's control, potentially giving the US president substantial leverage over which creditors get paid and when.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/13/b2321471-b443-4ec2-a28e-e63714007433_5b304890.jpg?itok=1XX8bwow&amp;v=1768270302" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bank of Japan holds rates steady, boosting Asian and US markets</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/boj-holds-rates-steady-boostin-oVDXGVqkR2qPLqhsbfj4Ag</link>
      <description>The Bank of Japan kept its benchmark interest rate unchanged at 0.75% on Friday, as expected, while raising its economic growth and inflation forecasts. The decision provided a stabilizing force for markets still recovering from a historic bond selloff earlier in the week triggered by Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi's snap election announcement.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Asian equities edged higher following the decision, with Japan's Nikkei 225 rising 0.2% to 53,800.28. U.S. futures also gained modestly, with S&amp;P 500 futures up 0.2%. South Korea's Kospi climbed 0.6%, trading just below the 5,000 milestone it crossed for the first time on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769156840/getty_uploads/2257127325_vrrkur.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
