<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:28:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says military operation against Colombia 'sounds good'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-military-opera-jUCIrsEkQreCs.BO2is5kw</link>
      <description>U.S. President Donald Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One on Sunday that a military operation against Colombia "sounds good to me," hours after threatening the country's leader to "watch his ass" following the capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro[1][2][3][4].

The remarks, made as Trump returned from Florida, represent an escalation of tensions with Colombian President Gustavo Petro and raised alarm across Latin America that Washington's military intervention in the region may expand beyond Venezuela. Secretary of State Marco Rubio separately suggested Cuba could be the next target, describing the Cuban government as "a huge problem" and saying they are "in a lot of trouble"[5][6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767573254/getty_uploads/2254496060_roj4nj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portland astronomer captures rare interstellar comet</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/amateur-astronomer-captures-in-J9xyBKtMRwud2DUCj3zgoA</link>
      <description>As professional observatories tracked an ancient visitor from beyond our solar system, a Portland amateur astronomer achieved what many scientists struggle to capture: a clear image showing the distinct separation between the comet's nucleus and its tail.

Patrick Finney photographed interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS in early January using a consumer smart telescope from his backyard, documenting the rare celestial object as it departs after a months-long journey through the solar system[1][2]. The comet, only the third interstellar object ever detected, made its closest approach to Earth on December 19, passing at a distance of 270 million kilometers[1][2][3]. It remained invisible to the naked eye throughout its visit.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--XcUwJhEa--/t_thumbnail/https://www.universetoday.com/article_images/Screenshot_2025-10-28_124658_20251028_165401.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's acting president proposes US cooperation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-rodriguez-shifts-ton-Uj8huSpzS9a22RVjSk4.sw</link>
      <description>Venezuelan acting President Delcy Rodriguez made a notable shift in tone on Sunday, extending an invitation to the United States for a "cooperation agenda" just one day after condemning Washington's military operation that captured President Nicolás Maduro.

Rodriguez, who was named acting president by Venezuela's Supreme Court on Saturday following Maduro's detention, called for a "balanced and respectful relationship" between the two nations in a statement posted on Telegram[1][2][3]. "We extend an invitation to the US government to work together on an agenda for cooperation that is aimed toward shared development," she wrote, emphasizing that such cooperation should occur "within the framework of international law."[4][5]

Addressing President Donald Trump directly, Rodriguez said Venezuelans "deserve peace and dialogue, not war," adding that "this has always been the principle championed by President Maduro."[6][7][8] The statement marked a dramatic departure from her televised address on Saturday, when she surrounded herself with military leaders and declared "there is only one president in this country, and his name is Nicolás Maduro," while condemning the US operation as "barbaric."[9][10][11]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Qbq7ga4S--/t_thumbnail/https://d3lzcn6mbbadaf.cloudfront.net/media/details/ANI-20260104051120.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung to double Gemini-equipped devices to 800M</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/samsung-to-double-gemini-ai-de-wWzDbpA2R4Cn0Rf83iSL1A</link>
      <description>Samsung Electronics plans to double the number of its mobile devices equipped with Google's Gemini AI features to 800 million units this year, co-CEO TM Roh told Reuters in an exclusive interview, marking a major escalation in the global artificial intelligence race. The South Korean tech giant, which deployed Gemini-backed AI features to approximately 400 million smartphones and tablets by the end of 2025, aims to apply AI "to all products, all functions, and all services as quickly as possible," Roh said[1][2][3][4].

The aggressive expansion gives Google a significant advantage as the world's largest Android device manufacturer deepens its AI partnership. Samsung is striving to reclaim its market leadership from Apple, which Counterpoint Research projects will be the top smartphone maker for 2025—the first time since 2011[5][6][7][8]. Samsung's surveys show awareness of its Galaxy AI brand surged to 80% from roughly 30% within just one year, signaling growing consumer adoption[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--104CAYDk--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/G4WNPGNLCNKWHKUQW67DWWJXNE.jpg%3Fauth%3Ddb29ea9f2e498b64a26ca5626d9cb6378b8a00f71b36535dfb27a19cc85babea%26height%3D1005%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80%26smart%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung warns memory chip shortage to raise tech prices</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/samsung-warns-unprecedented-me-J3To0bdKTSSQn95ADXOw9w</link>
      <description>Samsung co-CEO TM Roh warned that an "unprecedented" memory chip shortage is hitting the technology industry, with price increases for smartphones and TVs now "inevitable" as manufacturers grapple with surging costs driven by insatiable demand from artificial intelligence data centers[1][2][3].

"As this situation is unprecedented, no company is immune to its impact," Roh told Reuters in an interview published January 4, adding that the crisis affects not only mobile phones but other consumer electronics, from TVs to home appliances[1][2]. He did not rule out raising product prices, saying some impact was "inevitable" from a surge in memory chip prices[3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--gY_xPMr5--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/WD6GKO75AZNOZA5IZCG6BO3WKI.jpg%3Fauth%3D38e9ef5d331592f779efd09368a44572b9dbf7bb346a79572203f92b06cb2137%26height%3D1005%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80%26smart%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech giants' $400B AI spending spree raises inflation fears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-spending-boom-sparks-inflat-9oHMaZuaRrWwO3Ah64KZlw</link>
      <description>Global stock markets are riding high on artificial intelligence euphoria at the start of 2026, but investors may be overlooking a significant threat: a surge in inflation driven partly by the technology investment boom, coupled with mounting power constraints that could derail ambitious AI buildout plans[1].

Tech giants including Microsoft, Alphabet, Meta, and Amazon are projected to spend more than $400 billion combined in 2026 on AI infrastructure, up from approximately $380 billion in 2025[2][3][4]. Alphabet disclosed in its third-quarter 2025 earnings that capital expenditures for 2025 would reach around $85 billion, with expectations of further increases in 2026[5][6]. Microsoft spent $34.9 billion on capital expenditures in the first quarter of its fiscal 2026, with half allocated to short-lived assets like GPUs and CPUs[5][4].

Yet this spending spree is raising concerns among fund managers about inflation pressures that could force central banks to halt interest rate cuts. "You need a pin to burst the bubble, and it will likely come through tighter monetary conditions," said Trevor Greetham, head of multi-asset at Royal London Asset Management[7][1]. Morgan Stanley strategist Andrew Sheets projects U.S. consumer price inflation will remain above the Federal Reserve's 2% target until late 2027, partly due to substantial corporate investments in AI[7][1].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--tM08qj6l--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/631605a86f78cea4454ab295/68c1bb90fcb139f220bdf3a1_SA%2520industry%2520news%2520feature%2520sept%252012th%2520.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI safety advances lag behind rapid capability growth, experts warn</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/experts-warn-world-unprepared-LtE8r4w0T3y3kTxYvOD11Q</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence safety experts are sounding urgent alarms that rapid technological advances could outpace global efforts to manage emerging risks, with several researchers warning that humanity may be "sleepwalking" into a major transition without adequate safeguards in place.

David Dalrymple, an AI safety expert at the UK government's Advanced Research and Invention Agency, told The Guardian that the world "may not have time" to prepare for safety risks posed by rapidly advancing AI systems[1][2]. "We will be outcompeted in all of the domains that we need to be dominant in, in order to maintain control of our civilisation, society, and planet," he said, projecting that within five years most economically valuable tasks will be performed by machines at higher quality and lower cost than humans[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--EC0bdIpO--/t_thumbnail/https://www.computerworld.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/4111872-0-40553300-1767000048-mojahid-mottakin-xS83vCmnWog-unsplash.jpg%3Fquality%3D50%26strip%3Dall%26w%3D1024" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump claims US in charge of Venezuela after Maduro arrest</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-claims-us-control-over-v-jlr1s9n6SDScmNQrX.lDcw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared the United States is "in charge" of Venezuela following a military operation that captured longtime leader Nicolás Maduro, outlining plans to rebuild the country's oil infrastructure before eventual elections[1][2][3].

"Don't ask me who's in charge because I'll give you an answer, and it'll be very controversial," Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One. When pressed to clarify, he replied, "It means we're in charge"[1][3].

The stunning announcement came after U.S. special forces captured Maduro and his wife, Cilia Flores, in the early morning hours of January 3 during Operation Absolute Resolve, which involved more than 150 aircraft and strikes across northern Venezuela[4][5]. Maduro is scheduled to appear in Manhattan federal court on January 5 to face narco-terrorism, cocaine importation conspiracy, and weapons charges[6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--KWex0kr8--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/be7c1ce/2147483647/strip/true/crop/6000x3150%2B0%2B425/resize/1200x630%21/quality/90/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fcf%252F81%252Fa2ed6e084b93b46c8e0e8d75376c%252Fnicolas-maduro-091525.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian stocks hit record highs as tech rally continues</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/markets-react-to-us-capture-of-f2ByDZg.RjuelkDt5uliaQ</link>
      <description>Asian stock markets climbed to record highs Monday, led by a powerful rally in technology shares, as investors largely looked past geopolitical turmoil following the weekend US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro. Gold prices surged while oil fluctuated in early trading.

South Korea's Kospi jumped 3.43% to close at 4,457.52 points, breaking through 4,400 for the first time[1]. Japan's Nikkei 225 soared 2.97% to near its record high[1], while Taiwan's benchmark rose 2.57% past 30,000 points for the first time[1]. The rallies extended last year's artificial intelligence boom, with MSCI's Asia-Pacific stock index climbing as much as 1.7% to an all-time high[2].

Samsung Electronics led gains with a 7.47% surge[1], while Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing rocketed more than 5% after Goldman Sachs raised its price target by 35%[3]. SK Hynix climbed 2.81%[1]. US stock futures rose modestly, with S&amp;P 500 futures up 0.1%[4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--xg3vtbXn--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/21HbWItgJ4mP7qblsf.zhA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/ap.org/8f16639fe7ff8aa412498215bf177b2b" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech stocks drive global markets higher after Venezuela operation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tech-stocks-boost-global-marke-XdKj_rMgRxCEHW5N.QQc3g</link>
      <description>Global stock markets climbed Monday, led by a technology rally in Asia, as investors shrugged off geopolitical uncertainty following the weekend U.S. military operation that captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro. Oil prices drifted lower despite the upheaval in the OPEC nation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--StXF-8xO--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108229168-17636514422025-10-28t100019z_1226650128_rc2z28a7uakr_rtrmadp_0_nvidia-developers.jpeg%3Fv%3D1764596799%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump warns Venezuela of second strike if cooperation fails</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-second-strike-CGHvZ5cdQXSOhDgwdJytww</link>
      <description>Oil prices edged lower Monday as President Donald Trump threatened another military operation against Venezuela while his administration doubled down on an oil embargo aimed at forcing sweeping changes in the South American nation.

Brent crude fell 1.4% to $59.91 per barrel by the close of trading Monday, while West Texas Intermediate declined to $56.56, as markets weighed the fallout from the weekend capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro against concerns about global supply surplus[1][2][3]. Trump told reporters Sunday he could order a second strike if Venezuela's interim government fails to cooperate with US efforts to reshape the country's oil industry and halt drug trafficking[4][5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--d5oC7spM--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2026-01-04T040106Z_1581451739_RC2IADARCY8V_RTRMADP_3_USA-VENEZUELA-POWER-1767594531.jpg%3Fresize%3D1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markets rise as US captures Venezuelan President Maduro</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/markets-rise-after-us-captures-129XXryCQa6Yjla1zjv_dg</link>
      <description>Global stock markets climbed Monday as investors absorbed the dramatic weekend US military operation in Venezuela that resulted in the capture of President Nicolás Maduro, with traders weighing geopolitical risks against potential long-term economic opportunities[1][2][3].

US stock futures rose in early trading, with the S&amp;P 500 gaining 0.2%, the Nasdaq 100 jumping 0.5%, and the Dow Jones Industrial Average edging up 0.1%[1][2]. European markets also advanced, with London's FTSE 100 rising 0.2%, Germany's DAX climbing 1%, and France's CAC 40 up 0.6%[3].

The subdued market reaction reflected analysts' assessment that Venezuela's limited oil production—currently below 1 million barrels per day, or less than 1% of global supply—constrains the potential for major disruptions[1][3][4]. "Venezuela accounts for less than 1% of global oil, and at best a political outcome restoring production will take years," said Lale Akoner, a global market analyst at eToro[3].

Gold prices surged 2.3% to $4,433.71 per ounce as investors sought safe-haven assets amid heightened geopolitical uncertainty[3][5][6]. Meanwhile, oil futures fluctuated in early trading, with Brent crude falling 0.4% to $60.60 per barrel and West Texas Intermediate declining 0.5% to $56.97[3][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--aI_Z3Faz--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/jTifiM7pTRI7xbwRbtMwdA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/f1bd6b30-e9c4-11f0-b76b-2da2c09c4452" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investors shift to value stocks amid AI inflation fears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/investors-shift-focus-amid-202-BU7v.4w0TFmaUZD6s9mlKQ</link>
      <description>As global stock markets enter 2026 riding high on artificial intelligence enthusiasm, a growing chorus of investors and strategists warn that surging AI-related spending could reignite inflation and derail the rally, prompting a strategic shift toward undervalued assets.

Money managers are increasingly concerned that the multi-trillion-dollar race among tech giants Microsoft, Meta, and Alphabet to build AI data centers is driving up costs for chips and energy, creating inflationary pressures that markets may be underestimating. Deutsche Bank projects AI data center capital expenditure could reach $4 trillion by 2030[1][2][3], while Morgan Stanley strategist Andrew Sheets notes that "costs are going up not down in our forecast, because there's inflation in chip costs and inflation in power costs"[1][2][4].

"What keeps us awake at night is that inflation risk has resurfaced," said Julius Bendikas, European head of economics and dynamic asset allocation at Mercer, which manages $683 billion in assets[1][2]. Trevor Greetham, head of multi-asset at Royal London Asset Management, warned that while he continues holding tech stocks for now, he "would not be surprised to see inflation booming worldwide by the end of 2026"[5][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--zmiS1L_j--/t_thumbnail/https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/L7MQGNFG3FDHPNXGWN4X46VY34.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists track single sunspot for record 94 days</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/solar-orbiter-sets-record-with-H1iK_OvrQBqcc8D9ER6vAA</link>
      <description>Scientists have achieved the longest continuous observation of a single active solar region, tracking sunspot NOAA 13664 for 94 days as it evolved from birth to decay. The research, published this week in the journal Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, offers insights into solar storm formation that could improve space weather forecasting[1][2][3].

An international team led by ETH Zurich combined data from the European Space Agency's Solar Orbiter and NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory to monitor the region from April 16 to July 18, 2024. "This is the longest continuous series of images ever created for a single active region: it's a milestone in solar physics," said Ioannis Kontogiannis, a physicist at ETH Zurich and Istituto ricerche solari Aldo e Cele Daccò in Locarno[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--0KXzeS8B--/t_thumbnail/https://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2024/06/solar_orbiter_s_view_of_active_region_ar36642/26171236-1-eng-GB/Solar_Orbiter_s_view_of_active_region_AR3664_pillars.gif" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin climbs above $92,000 as whales return</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/bitcoin-surges-past-92000-to-s-OmuIs0XyRzK8dV1ttlPuUw</link>
      <description>Bitcoin climbed above $92,000 on Monday, signaling a potential shift in momentum as cryptocurrency markets shake off a difficult end to 2025 with renewed institutional interest and a surge in large-holder activity.

The world's largest cryptocurrency rose as much as 2.3% to $93,323 in early Asian trading, its highest level in three weeks, according to Bloomberg[1]. The rally pushed the total cryptocurrency market capitalization back above $3 trillion[2][3], marking a sharp reversal from the fourth quarter sell-off that saw Bitcoin fall roughly 35% from its October peak above $126,000[4][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--djWZjEwP--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/PIFUeAXchweNl.VUnJ8zBA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/decrypt_157/ed263d878990672315ba2a665fbb0664" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu vows to block Iran's missile program rebuild</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/netanyahu-vows-israel-will-not-FbrYTuqiTcWg3HhZLGb_og</link>
      <description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu declared Monday that Israel will not permit Iran to rebuild its ballistic missile industry, stating he and President Donald Trump are aligned on preventing Tehran from reconstituting weapons programs damaged during last year's conflict[1][1].

Speaking during a Knesset debate, Netanyahu said he and Trump "will not allow Iran to rebuild its ballistic missile industry, and we certainly won't let it renew its nuclear program," emphasizing their shared position that Iran must have zero enrichment capability[1][1]. The statement follows Netanyahu's late December meeting with Trump at Mar-a-Lago, where the two leaders discussed the possibility of launching additional strikes on Iran in 2026[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767628607/getty_uploads/2253970255_tiawh6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protests death toll hits 20 as crackdown enters ninth day</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-protests-enter-second-wee-KV46_hRbThi3pj22aJT2jw</link>
      <description>Nationwide demonstrations in Iran have entered a ninth consecutive day, with at least 20 protesters killed and nearly 1,000 arrested as what began as economic grievances has evolved into broader calls for regime change.

Unrest has been recorded at 222 locations across 78 cities in 26 provinces, according to the U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency[1][2][3]. The protests, initially sparked by Tehran bazaar merchants on December 28, have spread to universities and provincial cities, with demonstrators chanting "Death to the Dictator" and "Death to Khamenei"[4][5]. Security forces have responded with live ammunition, tear gas, and mass arrests, marking the largest demonstrations since the 2022 protests following Mahsa Amini's death[6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--SENUHeju--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/5472x3078%2B0%2B103/resize/1400/quality/100/format/jpeg/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fc8%252F1a%252Fe2564b484bd49e0d0fb79bd9284e%252Fap25363522315836.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump sets two-month timeline for Greenland as Denmark warns of NATO collapse</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-greenland-anne-QYrJ7VuPRgetT_eYY72UBA</link>
      <description>US President Donald Trump escalated threats to seize Greenland on Sunday, telling reporters aboard Air Force One that America "needs" the Danish territory for national security and setting a timeline of roughly two months to address the issue[1][2][3]. The declaration followed a military operation in Venezuela that captured President Nicolás Maduro, raising alarm that Greenland could be Trump's next target[4][5].

Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen delivered her strongest rebuke yet, stating that "it makes absolutely no sense to talk about the need for the United States to take over Greenland"[1][2]. According to Bloomberg, she warned that a US attack on the NATO ally would spell the end of the alliance itself[6]. "The US has no right to annex any of the three nations in the Danish kingdom," Frederiksen said, urging Washington to "stop the threats against a historically close ally"[7][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--s79PKcQ3--/t_thumbnail/https://d3i6fh83elv35t.cloudfront.net/static/2025/03/GettyImages-2203426391-768x500.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy cluster burns five times hotter than predicted</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-discover-unexpecte-Wc_5xRMQSzK1wDO2URtVSQ</link>
      <description>Astronomers have discovered a galaxy cluster blazing with gas at least five times hotter than predicted, just 1.4 billion years after the Big Bang, challenging fundamental assumptions about how these colossal cosmic structures form and evolve[1][2][3].

The finding, published in Nature on January 4, describes a cluster named SPT2349-56 whose gas temperatures exceed 10 million Kelvin—hotter and more energetic than many present-day galaxy clusters[1][2][4]. The discovery suggests that the birth of galaxy clusters is far more explosive than cosmologists previously believed, potentially requiring a rethink of galaxy cluster formation models[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--QVCpwhuo--/t_thumbnail/https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/02212909/SEI_279435215.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dollar hits two-week high after Maduro's capture</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-arrests-maduro-markets-reac-FGxtZzUWTgWI1mi7XdLhhg</link>
      <description>Financial markets displayed a measured reaction Monday as Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro arrived at a Manhattan federal courthouse to face drug trafficking charges, following his weekend capture by US special forces. The dollar strengthened to its highest level in two weeks while oil prices remained surprisingly stable, defying expectations of significant market turbulence.

The Bloomberg Dollar Spot Index climbed 0.3% to reach its strongest level since December 22, as the greenback outperformed nearly all major currencies[1][2]. The Mexican peso declined 0.7%, and the euro dropped 0.3%[2]. However, the overall market response suggested investors were treating the geopolitical shock as a contained event rather than a systemic crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--jxfb275l--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/rFe6uuwVItSh5Wc6QxCTjQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/d6aba55a89915ff351ba3a3bf045703c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
