<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:38:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Trump weighing Iran strike within 24 hours, officials say</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-weighs-iran-military-str-GVGF9t9wTWqEqEyRJFyhbQ</link>
      <description>US military intervention in Iran could occur within the next 24 hours, two European officials told Reuters on Wednesday, as President Donald Trump appears poised to authorize strikes amid protests that have killed more than 2,500 people in what French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot called "the most violent repression in Iran's contemporary history."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;An Israeli official also told Reuters that Trump appears to have decided to intervene, though the scope and timing remain unclear. A Washington source close to the administration told The Independent that strikes could be imminent. "President Trump is ready to push the button on Iran," the source said. "It will be a surgical removal of the regime."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2254867320.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860%2Cc_fill" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran shuts airspace as tensions with US escalate</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-closes-airspace-amid-fear-K_Illv8vTnml2PkC3.O7lA</link>
      <description>Iran issued a NOTAM late on Wednesday night, shutting its airspace to all flights except international flights with special permission, as Western military officials warned that US military intervention could be imminent. The airspace closure, valid for just over two hours, sparked widespread flight diversions and cancellations across the Middle East amid escalating tensions between Washington and Tehran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;FlightRadar24 announced on X that airspace over Iran began emptying rapidly before the notice was officially issued, with the flight-tracking platform noting: "New NOTAM just issued by Iran closing airspace to all flights except international flights to/from Iran with permission."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.bssnews.net/assets/news_photos/2025/06/14/image-282271-1749890663.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI rehires key researchers who left for Thinking Machines Lab</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-rehires-key-researchers-5.ZUox1WTbOEJJwVg8oqOQ</link>
      <description>OpenAI has secured the return of several high-profile researchers who departed the ChatGPT maker in 2024 to join former CTO Mira Murati's rival startup Thinking Machines Lab, according to industry reports. The move comes amid a significant shakeup at Murati's venture and as OpenAI continues to expand its research capabilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768436885/url_uploads/GettyImages-2198164367-e1742569013723_mwjpfw.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says Iran has stopped killing protesters, halted executions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-says-iran-stopped-killin-_JR4cF2STQ6.DuKVZD5ueA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced Wednesday that he received information suggesting Iran has ceased its violent crackdown on anti-government protesters and canceled planned executions, an apparent step back from the brink of military conflict between Washington and Tehran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We've been told that the killing in Iran is stopping. It has stopped, it's stopping, and there's no plan for executions or an execution or executions," Trump told reporters in the Oval Office on January 14. The president attributed the information to "very important sources on the other side," though he acknowledged uncertainty, adding, "I hope it's true. Who knows, right?"</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/5G723T74DNLNHIG3YVKJA4TGFQ.jpg?auth=475b0a14384d6a466c677be9d01e183c49680e1205d1c971ae0b554fbf4469a9&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musk's xAI disables Grok's sexualized image feature amid global backlash</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/musk-restricts-grok-ai-after-b-gDWy3ZshQJ2GYbyY5hI5Tg</link>
      <description>Elon Musk's xAI announced Wednesday it has disabled Grok's ability to create sexualized images of real people, following weeks of global outcry over the chatbot generating nonconsensual deepfakes of women and children. The policy shift comes as the Pentagon simultaneously moves to integrate Grok into military networks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We have implemented technological measures to prevent the Grok account from allowing the editing of images of real people in revealing clothing such as bikinis," X's safety team said in a statement. "This restriction applies to all users, including paid subscribers."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768440867/getty_uploads/2255514345_ovrej6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google's Gemini to tap Gmail, photos for personalized AI responses</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/google-expands-gemini-ai-with-xShbPoU.RjKFPjrohKMDYA</link>
      <description>Google is making its biggest push yet to transform its Gemini AI assistant into both a personal shopper and a deeply personalized assistant, announcing two major features this week that integrate with leading retailers and tap into users' Gmail, photos, and search history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The tech giant on Wednesday launched Personal Intelligence, a new beta feature that allows Gemini to access and analyze data across Gmail, Google Photos, YouTube watch history, and Search to deliver tailored responses. The feature is rolling out to Google AI Pro and AI Ultra subscribers in the United States, with plans to expand internationally and to free-tier users in the future.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/07/STK255_Google_Gemini_A.webp?quality=90&amp;strip=all&amp;crop=0%252C10.732984293194%252C100%252C78.534031413613&amp;w=1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arctic wildfires reach highest intensity in 3,000 years</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/arctic-wildfires-reach-record-uRKbaBc.SQqvi7nPs4fMow</link>
      <description>Wildfires scorching the Arctic have reached levels unseen in 3,000 years, as rising temperatures transform the frozen north into an increasingly flammable landscape, according to a new NASA report and recent scientific studies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The number of wildland fires burning in the Arctic is on the rise, with blazes burning larger, hotter, and longer than in previous decades, researchers say. The burned area in the North American Arctic has roughly doubled compared to the mid-20th century, and the mid-2010s ushered in what scientists describe as a novel fire regime.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Fire has always been a part of boreal and Arctic landscapes, but now it's starting to act in more extreme ways that mimic what we've seen in the temperate and the tropical areas," said Jessica McCarty, Deputy Earth Science Division Chief at NASA's Ames Research Center and lead author of a 2025 Arctic Monitoring and Assessment Programme report.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets3.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2020/07/21/9e7a0ff3-93f0-43fe-afbc-aadc2ca92f3a/thumbnail/1200x630/7355bf6fffd72f28101dc2436465894b/gp1su5ix-pressmedia.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly poison may have sparked life's building blocks, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/frozen-hydrogen-cyanide-crysta-BwpvPcwVR.uYvRSYUUwnRg</link>
      <description>A substance deadly to humans may have been instrumental in creating the very first ingredients for life on Earth. New computer simulations reveal that frozen hydrogen cyanide crystals possess highly reactive surface facets capable of triggering chemical reactions at extremely low temperatures, according to research published this week in ACS Central Science.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings could reshape scientific understanding of how life's essential building blocks, including amino acids and components of DNA, might have formed in the frigid environments of early Earth or on distant icy worlds like Saturn's moon Titan.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.encyclopedie-environnement.org/app/uploads/2017/05/chimie-ocean-terrestre_couverture2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oil prices fall as Trump signals pause on Iran military action</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/oil-prices-drop-as-trump-pause-3mYZqtIgSkeTVnMzRc7VqA</link>
      <description>Oil prices fell for the first time in six trading sessions on Thursday after President Donald Trump indicated the United States would hold off on military action against Iran, easing fears of supply disruptions in the Middle East.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brent crude slid more than 3% to around $64 per barrel, while West Texas Intermediate dropped to approximately $60, erasing much of the 11% gain the benchmarks had accumulated over the previous week.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The retreat came after Trump said Wednesday that he had received assurances Iran would cease killing anti-government protesters. "The killing has stopped. The executions have stopped," Trump said from the Oval Office, without identifying the source of his information.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108252742-1768441771952-gettyimages-2072711942-935a53715.jpeg?v=1768441780&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China calls Carney visit a 'turning point' in relations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/carney-visits-beijing-for-firs-jIN6zhUpScintsza_n9Qcw</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney arrived in Beijing on Wednesday for a four-day state visit, marking the first trip by a Canadian leader to China since 2017 and signaling both nations' desire to repair ties strained by years of diplomatic tensions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/VHIF5DCJBFIVFJJFUKV4HNQJMQ.jpg?auth=2f4bded5ee3150cfe689c7e4cbcbf0cfb43e729d57348b60cdf7966b4dbf8831&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate report warns warming may hit catastrophic levels by 2050</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/reports-warn-climate-change-ri-N.QCdjFCTvmgzLwET8ICLg</link>
      <description>Governments and financial institutions have underestimated climate change risks that could undermine the global economy, according to a new report warning that temperatures are rising faster than predicted and could hit catastrophic levels by 2050.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Parasol Lost report, jointly produced by the Institute and Faculty of Actuaries (IFoA) and the University of Exeter, was released on Tuesday as new data from the European Union's Copernicus Climate Change Service confirmed 2025 was the third-warmest year on record. For the first time, the three-year average from 2023 to 2025 has exceeded 1.5°C above pre-industrial levels — the threshold nations pledged not to breach under the 2015 Paris Agreement.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/en/euronews_ca_articles_409/7e8da80c62309a8a92cbe728b53ae17b" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon opens sovereign cloud in Germany to ease EU data fears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/amazon-launches-aws-european-s-2T4Do5ojRo6UkSo.LKGmoQ</link>
      <description>Amazon on Thursday launched its AWS European Sovereign Cloud, a new independent cloud infrastructure designed specifically for Europe that is physically and legally separate from the company's other data centers worldwide. The move addresses growing European concerns about data sovereignty and the dominance of U.S. technology companies in the region's cloud computing market.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first AWS Region of the sovereign cloud opened in the German state of Brandenburg, which surrounds Berlin. Amazon plans to invest more than €7.8 billion in the AWS European Sovereign Cloud in Germany through 2040, according to the company, with the investment expected to support an average of 2,800 full-time equivalent jobs annually and add approximately €17.2 billion to Germany's GDP.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://eu-images.contentstack.com/v3/assets/blt3d4d54955bda84c0/blte0590d16dc6b5044/684029e4a0396a587e543b72/aws_european_soveraign_cloud.jpg?disable=upscale&amp;width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;fit=crop" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark says White House talks failed to shift Trump's Greenland stance</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/greenland-s-harsh-terrain-bloc-hMeP1MDfQT6CC0VTQa.l3A</link>
      <description>Despite President Donald Trump's intensifying push to gain control of Greenland, experts warn that the Arctic territory's severe climate, remote geography, and absent infrastructure pose obstacles that no change in sovereignty could overcome. The island's vast mineral wealth remains locked beneath ice and rock that have defied extraction efforts for decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If you're going to go to Greenland for its minerals, you're talking billions upon billions upon billions of dollars and extremely long time before anything ever comes of it," mineral industry analyst Louis Marchese told Fortune, offering a sobering assessment of the mining reality.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/2OTT6ITHEJKHLANKLGUJGNPN3A.jpg?auth=dd0487a03c448d02e7575305125368c4c67d9a59e316f1b9cf03408349468cea&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds ocean damage nearly doubles climate cost estimates</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ocean-damage-doubles-climate-c-JbqmWa9lRcu9w4EAJ5OqMA</link>
      <description>The economic toll of climate change on the world's oceans has been vastly underestimated, according to new research that for the first time puts a price tag on marine ecosystem degradation—findings that emerge alongside a separate study warning that proposed climate engineering solutions carry their own risks to ocean life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Research published Wednesday in the journal Nature Climate Change by scientists at Scripps Institution of Oceanography at UC San Diego found that factoring ocean damage into climate calculations nearly doubles the global cost of carbon dioxide emissions. The study introduces what researchers call the "blue" social cost of carbon, adding $46.2 per ton of CO2 to existing estimates, bringing the total to $97.2 per ton—a 91% increase.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://today.ucsd.edu/teaser_uploads/_social/Octavio_AburtoDJI_0966_DxO_%25283%2529.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New self-healing composite could extend aircraft lifespans to centuries</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/self-healing-composite-promise-qPjURPXiT5enCj5K5e3Z0Q</link>
      <description>Researchers at North Carolina State University have developed a self-healing composite material capable of repairing itself more than 1,000 times, a breakthrough that could extend the lifespan of aircraft wings, wind turbine blades, and spacecraft components from decades to centuries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, published this week in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, demonstrates what researchers call "century-scale fracture recovery" in fiber-reinforced polymer composites—materials prized for their high strength-to-weight ratio but long plagued by a failure mode known as delamination.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://ccee.ncsu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/banner-3.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI pioneer Bengio says he's confident safe AI is possible</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/bengio-launches-lawzero-to-tac-tco3fQGjSBOfvjb10B8Vqg</link>
      <description>Yoshua Bengio, the Turing Award-winning AI pioneer often called one of the "godfathers" of artificial intelligence, says his latest research has dramatically shifted his outlook on the future of superintelligent AI. In a recent interview with Fortune, Bengio expressed renewed optimism about humanity's ability to build safe AI systems, citing progress at his nonprofit organization LawZero.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Because of the work I've been doing at LawZero, especially since we created it, I'm now very confident that it is possible to build AI systems that don't have hidden goals, hidden agendas," Bengio told Fortune, adding that his optimism has increased "by a big margin" over the past year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/ngg8KYB5rX471iJCe.tPaQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/fortune_175/b7dca8c38161a59323faab7d4f460f5b" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus claims new process cuts synthetic jet fuel costs by 80%</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/prometheus-unveils-cost-cuttin-oPyUdPu8SIaBVG1cITCTPA</link>
      <description>Santa Cruz-based Prometheus Fuels has announced what it calls a revolutionary method to produce synthetic jet fuel and diesel from electricity and air, claiming the process reduces e-fuel production costs by more than 80 percent compared to century-old Fischer-Tropsch technology.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement, made on January 14, marks the first public disclosure of the company's proprietary electrochemical pathway for producing synthetic paraffinic kerosene, the basis for sustainable aviation fuel and e-diesel. According to the company, the process is the first in history to produce kerosene from electricity and atmospheric CO2 without using hydrogen.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/v2/D5612AQHqib5ar3sKdw/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/B56ZkMHku1HQAU-/0/1756844936550?e=2147483647&amp;v=beta&amp;t=TjAftScUh2FatOLJlIcrBFArIwyaX3JA94Xi36CF2Q4" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSMC posts record profit as AI chip demand surges</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tsmc-reports-record-q4-earning-UI_eIHdAQye11sAjPeCpIg</link>
      <description>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, the world's largest contract chipmaker, reported record fourth-quarter results on Thursday, with net profit surging 35% year-over-year to NT$505.74 billion ($16 billion), exceeding analyst expectations and fueling a rally across global semiconductor stocks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Taiwanese chipmaker announced revenue of NT$1.046 trillion ($33.7 billion) for the quarter ending December 31, marking a 20.5% increase from the previous year. TSMC also revealed plans to substantially increase capital expenditure to between $52 billion and $56 billion in 2026, up from $40.9 billion last year, and projected approximately 30% revenue growth for the full year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/QFTV3OC3TRJNFJM5EDSPXOGT5Y.jpg?auth=50cdfedc9acba2c4977d1d2c379246cd2c2b230cf146b31a6dbd0eb304592af3&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space economy markets forecast to double by 2030</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/space-economy-markets-set-for-Lvi9_e77TkudwdwHpt6Lvw</link>
      <description>Multiple sectors of the space economy are projected to surge over the next five years as governments and private investors pour unprecedented funding into satellite services, orbital manufacturing, space habitats, and rescue operations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;New market research reports released January 15, 2026, by ResearchAndMarkets.com detail growth trajectories across several emerging space economy segments. The space currency and economy market is forecast to grow from $1.91 billion in 2026 to $3.8 billion by 2030, while in-space manufacturing, servicing, and transportation is expected to expand from $2.6 billion to $5.23 billion during the same period. Space habitat development is projected to reach $11.54 billion by 2030, growing at a compound annual growth rate of 20.8%.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/LIEYDAVLLZOYBDFKK3JW4UELVQ.jpg?auth=f10d36d9c643805f579b9d8e1b7b4a030792ad83a170f3d47f42840251e238e9&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice quantum simulator reveals how vibrations drive energy flow in molecules</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/rice-quantum-simulator-tracks-sulyVHbeTuyV38HcGM2hPw</link>
      <description>Researchers at Rice University have built a quantum device capable of simulating molecular vibrations and directly observing how energy moves from one part of a molecule to another, findings that could deepen understanding of natural processes like photosynthesis and improve designs for solar energy technology.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The work, published Dec. 5 in Nature Communications, marks the first time scientists have used trapped-ion technology to simulate a two-mode molecular system while independently controlling energy loss to the environment, according to the research team.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/quantum-simulator-shed.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
