<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:35:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Japan's 40-year bond suffers historic selloff amid fears over tax cut plan</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/japan-s-40-year-bond-suffers-h-8FkkmP0TRHqi4hRjsfJuFQ</link>
      <description>Japanese government bonds experienced a historic meltdown on Tuesday as fiscal concerns over Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi's unfunded tax cut promises sent long-dated yields surging to levels not seen in decades, triggering a selloff that spread across global financial markets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The yield on Japan's 40-year government bond rocketed past 4%, the highest since this maturity was introduced in 2007 and a first for any sovereign debt instrument in the country in more than three decades. The 30-year yield climbed to a record 3.875%, while the benchmark 10-year yield rose above 2.3%, its highest level since 1999.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768920171/getty_uploads/2256505371_qi0dwf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump intensifies pressure on European allies over Greenland demands</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-intensifies-pressure-on-Xr5JJffvQyickDNoBdZCbg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump intensified his campaign to acquire Greenland on Tuesday, posting AI-generated images of himself planting an American flag on the Arctic territory while threatening European allies with tariffs unless they relent on what he called an "imperative" matter of national security. The escalating pressure comes as European leaders prepare for tense meetings at the World Economic Forum in Davos, with EU officials vowing an "unflinching" response to what they describe as coercion against a longtime ally.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.newindianexpress.com/newindianexpress/2026-01-13/g2ccrao4/AP26012117241272.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=900&amp;auto=format%252Ccompress&amp;fit=max&amp;enlarge=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine's Chornobyl plant reconnected to grid after Russian strikes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chornobyl-nuclear-plant-restor-Yl.Hx2jKRF.Nje8DR_t5.w</link>
      <description>Ukraine's Chornobyl Nuclear Power Plant has been reconnected to the country's power grid following a massive overnight Russian drone and missile assault that temporarily knocked out all external power to the facility, with officials confirming radiation levels remain normal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The International Atomic Energy Agency confirmed early Tuesday that the plant, site of the world's worst civil nuclear disaster, had lost all off-site power after Russian forces targeted energy infrastructure across Ukraine. "Several Ukrainian electrical substations vital for nuclear safety were affected by widespread military activity this morning," IAEA Director General Rafael Grossi said on X.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ukraine's energy ministry announced later Tuesday that power had been restored and radiation levels posed no threat.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.kyivindependent.com/content/images/2025/10/GettyImages-2211635249.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump, NATO chief agree to Davos meeting on Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-calls-nato-secretary-gen-dulYBbb8Q2qXS5Zt_KfySQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced on Monday that he had a "very good" telephone call with NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte about Greenland and agreed to convene "various parties" at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, escalating a diplomatic crisis that has strained transatlantic relations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"As I expressed to everyone, very plainly, Greenland is imperative for National and World Security. There can be no going back — On that, everyone agrees!" Trump wrote on Truth Social.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.assettype.com/deccanherald%252F2026-01-20%252Fxh0j0n96%252Ffile818bb60nmp2ivih92bm.jpg?w=undefined&amp;auto=format%252Ccompress&amp;fit=max" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Board of Peace meets resistance from key allies</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trumps-board-of-peace-meets-re-IhJv.LHyRJCzurtBtRF1jw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's newly established Board of Peace is encountering resistance from key allies as world leaders grapple with a controversial charter requiring $1 billion for permanent membership and granting Trump near-total control over the international body.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The initiative, originally conceived to oversee Gaza's reconstruction following the October 2025 ceasefire, has evolved into a far more ambitious enterprise. According to the charter, which has been reviewed by multiple news outlets, the board aims to "promote stability, restore dependable and lawful governance, and secure enduring peace in areas affected or threatened by conflict"—language that makes no mention of Gaza.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108202970-17586558142025-09-23t192938z_180443073_rc2vxgajz9r6_rtrmadp_0_un-assembly-trump.jpeg?v=1758655901&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland PM tells residents to prepare for possible invasion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/greenland-leaders-warn-residen-ZGu.11hTS3GxxwbjoH6BNQ</link>
      <description>Greenland's Prime Minister Jens-Frederik Nielsen on Tuesday told residents to prepare for a possible military invasion, delivering a stark warning as tensions between the United States and European allies over the Arctic territory escalate to unprecedented levels.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It's not likely there will be a military conflict, but it can't be ruled out," Nielsen said at a press conference in the capital Nuuk. "The leader on the other side, US President Donald Trump, has said very clearly that it is not out of the question, and we should of course be prepared for all possible scenarios."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The warning comes as Greenlanders grapple with the reality of life at the center of an international crisis, with residents stockpiling supplies and planning escape routes while refusing to bow to American pressure.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.euronews.com/articles/stories/09/50/21/18/1536x864_cmsv2_b7261d25-f4fb-52df-b6d7-ae5f0403f0b7-9502118.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel demolishes UNRWA headquarters in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/israel-demolishes-unrwa-headqu-D_A1pzFKTCWnXfLesVfJwA</link>
      <description>Israeli bulldozers tore down buildings at the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) headquarters in occupied East Jerusalem on Tuesday morning, in what the UN agency condemned as an "unprecedented attack" and a serious violation of international law.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shortly after 7 a.m. local time, Israeli forces entered the compound in the Sheikh Jarrah neighborhood, expelled security personnel, confiscated staff equipment, and began demolishing structures with heavy machinery, according to UNRWA spokesperson Jonathan Fowler. An Israeli flag was raised over the premises, replacing the UN flag.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Far-right National Security Minister Itamar Ben-Gvir arrived at the scene to observe the demolition. "This is a historic day, a day of celebration, and a very important day for governance in Jerusalem," Ben-Gvir said in a statement. "For years, these supporters of terrorism were here, and today they are being removed from here along with everything they built."</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/ECOS4VVJAVJF3AIUQPA6EFRAHE.jpg?auth=9ba74bcc802e614a7078c32405963991f358400d15614843647add158f835057&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky cancels Davos trip as Russian strike cripples Kyiv heat</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/zelensky-cancels-davos-trip-to-zwTgE41KR2KIB4HWbHQpTA</link>
      <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky announced on January 20 that he is canceling his planned trip to the World Economic Forum in Davos, choosing to remain in Kyiv to coordinate the response to a severe energy crisis following Russia's latest mass aerial attack on the country's power infrastructure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Undoubtedly, I choose Ukraine in this case, rather than the economic forum, but everything can change at any moment," Zelensky told journalists, adding that helping people with the energy situation is his "top priority" right now.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://kyivindependent.com/_next/image?url=https%253A%252F%252Fassets.kyivindependent.com%252Fcontent%252Fimages%252F2026%252F01%252FGettyImages-2256588810-1.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=75" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia invests $150M in AI startup Baseten at $5B valuation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-and-baseten-announce-30-cbqoP2xeQ8C.e8JwmVdAWQ</link>
      <description>Nvidia is pouring $150 million into AI inference startup Baseten as part of a $300 million funding round that more than doubles the company's valuation to $5 billion, according to a report from The Wall Street Journal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The round was led by venture capital firm IVP and CapitalG, Alphabet's independent growth fund, signaling continued confidence in the AI infrastructure market despite concerns about whether the sector is overheating.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/e4aqoIrg72Ky7NvmMlljKw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD03MjM-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/fortune_175/3df635a5b6da5176e1b5578fead5e796" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Parliament set to suspend US trade deal over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/europe-prepares-to-suspend-us-SiSdubsMRs6j5LswXNGUog</link>
      <description>The European Parliament is set to halt approval of the trade agreement reached with the United States last July, according to sources close to its international trade committee, as transatlantic tensions over Greenland threaten to unravel months of diplomatic negotiations. An official announcement is expected Wednesday in Strasbourg, France.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decision marks a rebuke to Washington after President Donald Trump on Saturday announced escalating tariffs on eight European nations—Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland—unless the US is allowed to purchase Greenland, a semi-autonomous Danish territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img.lemde.fr/2026/01/20/3/0/3782/2521/1440/960/60/0/0f207e8_ftp-1-xlk7xnlh9anx-2026-01-20t122332z-1577463871-rc2z4jakn9kp-rtrmadp-3-eu-parliament.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexico transfers 37 cartel suspects to US amid pressure from Trump</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mexico-delivers-37-drug-cartel-nm9SA2VfS52dViJW8Qcsew</link>
      <description>Mexico has transferred another 37 drug cartel members to the United States, the country's security minister announced Tuesday, as the Trump administration continues to pressure governments to crack down on criminal networks smuggling drugs across the border.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mexican Security Minister Omar García Harfuch confirmed the transfer in a social media post on X, describing the individuals as "high impact criminals" who "represented a real threat to the country's security." The handover brings the total number of cartel operatives and leaders sent to the United States under President Claudia Sheinbaum's administration to 92.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4HWUZCRXIJPMLC4EUKZVIYANMA.jpg?auth=69fa12cb229c08bf4d1c22c57e625d09a7998e17787038d0ab6e66b16b60113f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran's parliament warns of jihad if Supreme Leader attacked</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-warns-jihad-if-supreme-le-Y7zKpa_kR_aKdUUy1mTiGA</link>
      <description>Iran's parliament issued a stark warning on Tuesday that any attack on Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei would trigger a declaration of jihad, or holy war, with the mobilization of Islamic fighters worldwide. The statement, from the national security committee of Iran's parliament, raises the stakes in a rapidly escalating confrontation between Tehran and Washington following a deadly crackdown on protests.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Any aggression against the Supreme Leader signifies a declaration of war against the entire Islamic community and necessitates a Jihad proclamation from Islamic scholars, along with the mobilization of Islam's fighters worldwide," the parliamentary committee stated, according to the Iranian Students News Agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-05-20t115850z-1894412973-rc2nleacha3a-rtrmadp-3-iran-nuclear-usa-20250629150751537.JPG?c=16x9&amp;q=h_833%2Cw_1480%2Cc_fill" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European leaders call for independence from U.S. at Davos</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-attends-davos-2026-amid-zEAPXA3QSpqu_TRXXdC8jw</link>
      <description>The World Economic Forum's annual meeting in Davos, Switzerland, has become a flashpoint for rising U.S.-European tensions as President Donald Trump prepares to address global leaders on Wednesday amid an escalating dispute over Greenland and new tariff threats against longtime allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;European leaders struck a defiant tone on Tuesday, the second day of the forum, as European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen called for a "permanent" shift toward European independence from the United States and French President Emmanuel Macron warned of a dangerous "shift towards a world without rules."</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4EPO2RX5PRONTC3RDIJCXBQ6CM.jpg?auth=8e9543263e090b354d7cb131edfbf0b54f18bd0a6627113bd8fd899c6a6f94dc&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists launch deep-sea mission to validate 'dark oxygen' discovery</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-deploy-deep-sea-lan-wA2PIbC_QmKU2dj1Dh7kCw</link>
      <description>Researchers have unveiled two specially designed deep-sea landers that will descend nearly seven miles beneath the Pacific Ocean to investigate the controversial phenomenon known as "dark oxygen," a discovery that could reshape understanding of how life emerged on Earth and complicate plans for commercial seabed mining.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At a press conference in London on Tuesday, Professor Andrew Sweetman of the Scottish Association for Marine Science (SAMS) introduced the landers named Alisa and Kaia, after his daughters, which are engineered to withstand pressures 1,200 times greater than those at the surface. The expedition, funded by a £2 million grant from The Nippon Foundation over three years, marks the most detailed examination yet of a process that defies the long-held scientific consensus that oxygen requires sunlight and photosynthesis to form.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Z2_a1a8ef.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second Spanish train derails near Barcelona, multiple injured</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/second-spanish-train-derails-n-gMPKCpqgQ4GdiJqL8a4ihw</link>
      <description>A commuter train derailed near Barcelona on Tuesday after a containment wall collapsed onto the tracks, injuring 15 passengers, Spanish emergency authorities said. The incident comes just two days after a catastrophic high-speed train collision in southern Spain killed more than 40 people.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768946020/url_uploads/Spanish_20rail_yezchy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IAEA chief warns Iran may be declared in nuclear treaty violation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/analysts-warn-iran-crisis-rais-hL09SUR9Tme2NUVK1wS8Uw</link>
      <description>As tensions between Washington and Tehran continue to escalate amid a violent crackdown on nationwide protests, arms control experts are sounding alarms about the security of Iran's near-weapons-grade uranium stockpile, warning that months of blocked inspections have created a dangerous void in international oversight.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The International Atomic Energy Agency has been unable to verify the status of an estimated 440.9 kilograms of uranium enriched to 60 percent purity—close to the roughly 90 percent considered weapons-grade—since U.S. and Israeli airstrikes struck key nuclear facilities in June 2025. That stockpile, according to IAEA standards, is theoretically enough material for 10 nuclear bombs if further enriched.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54293042288_2f6eee125d_b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says NATO would be 'ash heap of history' without him</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-claims-nato-owes-existen-P.onYnffQrCPMe8hiNlKyw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared on Tuesday that NATO would be "in the ash heap of history" without his leadership, as European leaders rallied to oppose his push to acquire Greenland and his threat to impose escalating tariffs on eight allied nations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"No single person, or President, has done more for NATO than President Donald J. Trump. If I didn't come along, there would be no NATO right now!!! It would have been in the ash heap of History," Trump wrote on Truth Social. In the same post, he added, "Sad, but TRUE!!!"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The remarks came just hours before Trump departed for the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, where European leaders assembled to present a united front against his territorial ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://dxltb3n5j8l6j.cloudfront.net/788185/uploads/324b8590-f642-11f0-977e-35ab0c61e9cb_1200_630.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and Putin envoys hold first talks on Ukraine at Davos</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-and-putin-envoys-hold-co-VMKxIHBWQQ.bqtTWuSuz7Q</link>
      <description>Envoys for U.S. President Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin met for approximately two hours in Davos on Tuesday to discuss a potential peace deal for Ukraine, with both sides characterizing the discussions as positive and constructive—even as key obstacles to ending Europe's deadliest conflict since World War II remain unresolved.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The meeting at "USA House" on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum brought together Trump's special envoy Steve Witkoff and son-in-law Jared Kushner with Kremlin representative Kirill Dmitriev, marking the first time a senior Russian official has publicly engaged at the Swiss gathering since the forum froze ties with Moscow following the 2022 invasion of Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768957326/getty_uploads/2256586635_u3p6o9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope captures dying star's fate and black hole's feeding</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-reveals-n-ZEoaWyRWTySzbdniGAvp7Q</link>
      <description>NASA released stunning new images from the James Webb Space Telescope on Tuesday, including a detailed look at the Helix Nebula that offers a glimpse into the eventual fate of our own Sun. Meanwhile, separate observations captured a supermassive black hole in the Circinus Galaxy actively consuming surrounding material, overturning decades of assumptions about how such cosmic giants feed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2026/01/webb_reveals_helix_nebula_in_glistening_detail/27049912-4-eng-GB/Webb_reveals_Helix_Nebula_in_glistening_detail_pillars.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada models guerrilla warfare response to US invasion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canadian-military-simulates-us-_WgxXgVURueKc1oAvoC4JA</link>
      <description>The Canadian Armed Forces have modeled a hypothetical U.S. military invasion of Canada and potential responses employing unconventional warfare tactics, The Globe and Mail reported on Tuesday, marking the first time in approximately 100 years that such scenarios have been war-gamed by Canada's military.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to two senior government officials who spoke to The Globe and Mail, military planners are simulating a U.S. invasion from the south, anticipating American forces could overwhelm Canada's strategic defenses on land and at sea within as little as two days. The officials emphasized, however, that a U.S. invasion remains highly improbable.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.the-independent.com/2026/01/20/21/06/GettyImages-2206320029.jpeg?trim=1%252C0%252C1%252C0&amp;width=1200&amp;height=800&amp;crop=1200%253A800" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
