<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:29:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Sheinbaum rejects Trump military threats after Venezuela raid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sheinbaum-rejects-trump-threat-sWfinrG0QpW1g3m6fZOqEA</link>
      <description>Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum firmly downplayed threats of U.S. military intervention in Mexico on Monday, following President Donald Trump's warnings that Washington might act against drug cartels operating south of the border. The dispute marks the latest escalation between the two leaders after Trump's weekend military operation captured Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro.

"I don't believe in an invasion; I don't think it's something they take seriously," Sheinbaum said during her first press conference since U.S. forces seized Maduro early Saturday morning[1][2]. The Mexican leader emphasized her rejection of any U.S. military presence in her country, stating that Mexico is collaborating with Washington on security but will not accept intervention[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--sv1RV_Cl--/t_thumbnail/https://images.axios.com/F2dZLUbptGauTGe2ueqKZ-_eL4g%3D/0x473:4536x3024/1366x768/2026/01/03/1767457758866.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI capabilities doubling every 8 months, UK safety institute finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/experts-warn-world-unprepared-pE5Ys7SESZWgez8HB5iJYg</link>
      <description>A leading AI safety researcher has cautioned that rapid advances in artificial intelligence may outpace humanity's ability to implement adequate safeguards, warning that society could be "sleepwalking" into an era where machines control critical infrastructure before proper oversight is established.

David Dalrymple, a program director at the UK's Advanced Research and Invention Agency, told The Guardian that the world "may not have time" to prepare for safety risks posed by cutting-edge AI systems[1][2][3][4]. His warnings come as new data from Britain's AI Security Institute reveals that AI capabilities are advancing at an exponential pace, with performance in certain domains doubling every eight months[5][6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--EKGjs07y--/t_thumbnail/https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%252F2024-09-19%252Fidf4ebay%252Fai-71118021280.jpg%3Frect%3D0%252C14%252C1280%252C672%26w%3D1200%26auto%3Dformat%252Ccompress%26ogImage%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia unveils AI models, $3,000 desktop supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-ceo-huang-to-unveil-ai-oJmeEDlaRgO.T8DZFTobJg</link>
      <description>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang took the stage at the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas on Monday, unveiling new autonomous vehicle technology and a desktop AI supercomputer as the world's most valuable company confronts rising competition from rivals and its own customers.

In a 90-minute keynote, Huang announced Alpamayo, an open-source family of AI models designed to help autonomous vehicles navigate complex driving scenarios, and Project DIGITS, a $3,000 personal AI supercomputer set to launch in May[1][2]. The announcements come as Nvidia faces intensifying pressure from both chipmaking competitors like Advanced Micro Devices and customers including Alphabet and Meta Platforms that are developing their own AI chips[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Maxp4_Ey--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2025-11/2025-11-20T024308Z_1_LYNXMPELAJ03O_RTROPTP_4_NVIDIA-RESULTS-BUBBLE.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyundai to mass-produce Boston Dynamics Atlas robot</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hyundai-to-mass-produce-boston-DbNbUhuHRd6orYdkezDDhQ</link>
      <description>Hyundai Motor Group announced Monday at CES 2026 in Las Vegas that it will mass-produce Boston Dynamics' Atlas humanoid robot, with plans to manufacture 30,000 units annually by 2028 and deploy them across its manufacturing facilities[1][2][3][4].

The South Korean automaker revealed the production-ready version of Atlas during its keynote presentation, marking the first public demonstration of the all-electric humanoid robot outside of carefully edited videos[1][5]. The announcement signals a major shift in industrial automation, as one of the world's most advanced humanoid robots transitions from research prototype to commercial product.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--JLPo8PKs--/t_thumbnail/https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/YT-Pre-Launch-Thumbnail.jpg%3Fquality%3D90%26strip%3Dall%26crop%3D0%252C3.4613147178592%252C100%252C93.077370564282%26w%3D1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lula contacts Venezuela's interim leader after US captures Maduro</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/lula-speaks-with-venezuela-s-i-GRIct75fSsGyvMnOonmExA</link>
      <description>Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva spoke with Venezuela's interim President Delcy Rodriguez on Saturday, hours after a US military operation captured and removed Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro from power, according to Brazil's presidency[1][2][3].

Lula called Rodriguez to confirm media reports about the US military action that resulted in Maduro's detention, a Brazilian government source said[2][4][3]. The Brazilian presidency did not provide further details about the call, which marked one of the first high-level diplomatic contacts following the dramatic overnight operation[1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767652131/getty_uploads/2251924836_bngajm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, AMD CEOs unveil AI roadmaps as CES 2026 opens</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-opens-with-ai-and-rob-sRTuki20QiCQNjt5uNF7HQ</link>
      <description>The annual Consumer Electronics Show opened Monday in Las Vegas with artificial intelligence and robotics dominating the event's first day, as Nvidia and AMD CEOs outlined their visions for AI's future while manufacturers unveiled a new generation of home robots designed to handle everyday household tasks.

Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang kicked off the show's keynote presentations at 1 p.m. PT, focusing on what he called the "Physical AI" era—artificial intelligence that can understand and operate in the real world[1][2][3][4]. The company unveiled Alpamayo, an open-source autonomous driving platform featuring a 10-billion parameter vision language action model designed to help self-driving cars reason through complex scenarios[2][3][4]. "The ChatGPT moment for physical AI is here, when machines begin to understand, reason and act in the real world," Huang said during his presentation[3][5].

Later Monday evening, AMD CEO Lisa Su took the stage at 6:30 p.m. PT to present her company's roadmap for delivering AI solutions "from cloud to enterprise, edge and devices"[6][7][8]. The keynote, held at the Palazzo Ballroom at the Venetian, highlighted AMD's position in the competitive AI chip market as the company works to challenge Nvidia's dominance[9][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MeB1pmYM--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2026-01/2026-01-05T220947Z_1_LYNXMPEM0416L_RTROPTP_4_TECH-CES-NVIDIA.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive early galaxies took different paths, astronomers find</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-uncover-early-univ-n5Oz8Og7QOCsbDo2Ei5O4Q</link>
      <description>Astronomers have discovered that the universe's most massive galaxies followed strikingly different evolutionary paths in their infancy, with some shutting down star formation early while others remained vigorously active but cloaked in dust.

The findings, presented today at the 247th meeting of the American Astronomical Society in Phoenix, reveal that ultramassive galaxies containing more than 100 billion stars exhibited diverse behaviors less than 2 billion years after the Big Bang[1][2]. The research challenges assumptions that galaxy evolution proceeded uniformly in the early universe.

"What is striking is not just that we can detect hidden activity, but that we see such diversity among galaxies with similar masses at the same epoch," said Gillian Wilson, vice chancellor for research at UC Merced and professor of physics, who mentored the study[1]. "That tells us that the shutdown of star formation in the most massive galaxies was neither uniform nor simple."</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ab7oZDAb--/t_thumbnail/https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/distant-red-galaxies-black-hole-stars.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel and AMD unveil competing AI laptop chips at CES</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/intel-and-amd-launch-new-chips-99b3fWTUS.ab5hN3FlZrkA</link>
      <description>Intel and Advanced Micro Devices unveiled competing laptop processors at CES 2026 in Las Vegas on Monday, as both chipmakers push to capture market share in the AI-powered PC market with new technologies designed to boost performance and efficiency.

Intel officially launched its Panther Lake processors, branded as Intel Core Ultra Series 3, marking the first high-volume production chips built on the company's new 18A manufacturing process[1][2][3]. The stakes are high for Intel, which has struggled with yields and lost market share to AMD in recent years[1]. Intel CEO Lip-Bu Tan said the company delivered on its promise to ship products with 18A in 2025[1].

Intel claims the new chips deliver 60% better multithread performance than its previous Lunar Lake Series 2 processors[1][2]. The flagship feature is the new Arc B390 integrated graphics chip, which Intel says offers up to 77% faster gaming performance than Lunar Lake and can match Nvidia's discrete RTX 4050 mobile GPU[1][4]. Pre-orders for laptops with the new processors begin January 6, with systems shipping globally starting January 27[3][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--NHeS5NWD--/t_thumbnail/https://helios-i.mashable.com/imagery/articles/07nIqAUXPBbwULfbJEDtUrF/hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.v1767648980.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, Hyundai, Intel unveil AI chips and robots at CES</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-highlights-ai-innovat-qGYvFhlPR.i_nyZjZt5l_w</link>
      <description>The world's leading technology companies converged on Las Vegas Monday to showcase groundbreaking artificial intelligence innovations at the Consumer Electronics Show, with Nvidia, Hyundai, and Intel each debuting major new products aimed at advancing AI capabilities across data centers, factories, and personal computers.

Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang opened CES with the announcement of the Vera Rubin AI platform, the company's next-generation chip architecture that promises to deliver five times the artificial intelligence inference performance and 3.5 times the training performance of its current Blackwell chips[1][2][3][4]. The platform, comprising six integrated chips including the Rubin GPU with 336 billion transistors and 288GB of HBM4 memory, is expected to become available through partners in the second half of 2026[1][2][4].

"The timing of Rubin's launch is perfect, as the demand for AI computing, both for training and inference, is skyrocketing," Huang said during his keynote[2]. The announcement comes as Nvidia faces intensifying competition from rivals including Advanced Micro Devices and customers like Alphabet's Google developing their own AI chips[5].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MeB1pmYM--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2026-01/2026-01-05T220947Z_1_LYNXMPEM0416L_RTROPTP_4_TECH-CES-NVIDIA.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian stocks hit record highs on tech, chip gains</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-stocks-hit-record-highs-KgbXbJdXStyx0PNdULmPtA</link>
      <description>Asian stock markets surged to fresh record highs on Tuesday, powered by technology and semiconductor shares as investors continued to bet on surging artificial intelligence demand, while oil prices steadied following a brief spike over geopolitical tensions.

The MSCI Asia-Pacific index climbed 0.4% to its highest level on record, marking a fourth consecutive day of gains[1][2][3]. Japan's TOPIX index jumped 1.3% to a record peak, while the Nikkei 225 hovered near record levels with a 0.7% gain[4][5][2]. Hong Kong's Hang Seng advanced between 0.7% and 1.2%, with the Hang Seng TECH sub-index climbing nearly 2%[4][5][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--RXYOIJYn--/t_thumbnail/https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/cdn-cgi/image/quality%3D80%2Cformat%3Dauto%2Cfit%3Dscale-down%2Cdpr%3D1%2Cwidth%3D1600%2Cheight%3D1000/https://media.freemalaysiatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/a8eeefdb-kospi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, AMD unveil AI and gaming chips at CES</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-and-amd-unveil-advanced-khw1eo.4R4.gbuogXVQY4g</link>
      <description>Nvidia and AMD kicked off CES 2026 with major chip announcements on Monday, as the chipmakers battle for dominance in the booming artificial intelligence and gaming markets. Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang confirmed its next-generation Vera Rubin AI platform is already in full production, while AMD CEO Lisa Su unveiled new processors spanning gaming, mobile, and embedded AI applications[1][2][3].

Huang announced that Vera Rubin, the successor to Nvidia's Blackwell architecture, delivers five times the AI inference performance of its predecessor while using a quarter of the GPUs for training complex AI models[1][4][5]. The platform comprises six integrated chips—including the Vera CPU and Rubin GPU—and is slated for deployment in the second half of 2026[1][6]. According to Nvidia, major cloud providers including Amazon, Microsoft, and Google have already committed to adopting the platform[1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--iOJpcKiC--/t_thumbnail/https://helios-i.mashable.com/imagery/articles/05n5hW0RYeCjcLmuPTZdOue/hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.v1767649490.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia unveils Rubin AI platform, robotaxi pilot</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-surpasses-5-trillion-at-7m_2RWFhQ5.KRrWbuTnWxw</link>
      <description>Nvidia used its CES 2026 keynote in Las Vegas to argue that the next phase of artificial intelligence will be built less around chatbots and more around machines that can perceive, reason and act in the real world—while the company supplies the underlying compute stack.[1][2][3]

The presentation came after Nvidia’s historic run in 2025, when it became the first publicly traded company to top a $5 trillion market capitalization.[4][5][6] By early January 2026, its valuation had slipped back to roughly the mid-$4 trillion range, underscoring how quickly the numbers can swing even for the market’s biggest AI beneficiary.[7][8][9]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--XNovnA-n--/t_thumbnail/https://sm.mashable.com/t/mashable_me/article/3/3-major-ta/3-major-takeaways-from-nvidia-live-at-ces-2026_97y3.1200.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD unveils AI chips, gaming processors at CES</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/amd-unveils-new-ai-and-gaming-kvUaDZWLT1.a4932nojSdw</link>
      <description>AMD CEO Lisa Su took the stage at CES 2026 in Las Vegas on January 5, unveiling a comprehensive lineup of processors spanning data centers, consumer PCs, embedded systems, and gaming, as the chipmaker intensifies its competition with rival Nvidia in the AI computing market.

The announcements included the Ryzen 7 9850X3D desktop gaming processor, new AI-powered laptop and desktop chips, advanced data center accelerators, and embedded processors designed for automotive and industrial applications[1][2][3]. OpenAI president Greg Brockman joined Su on stage to discuss the companies' partnership, which was announced in October 2025[4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ZzzBZJX3--/t_thumbnail/https://media.zenfs.com/en/reuters-finance.com/34033ef663fd719bbce53b1e8610bb2a" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA's Artemis II to roll out to launch pad within two weeks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/2026-sees-surge-in-moon-missio-KxFVzVCWTPKr3236RDepbg</link>
      <description>NASA announced Friday that its Artemis II mission is less than two weeks away from rolling out to the launch pad, marking the first step toward returning astronauts to lunar orbit after more than five decades[1]. The announcement signals the beginning of what industry observers are calling an unprecedented year for moon missions, with at least five commercial lunar landers also targeting 2026 launches alongside NASA's flagship program[2].

NASA Press Secretary Bethany Stevens confirmed that the agency's Space Launch System rocket will move to the launch pad by mid-January, with a launch window opening February 6 and extending through April[1][3]. The mission will send four astronauts—NASA's Reid Wiseman, Victor Glover, and Christina Koch, along with the Canadian Space Agency's Jeremy Hansen—on a roughly 10-day journey around the moon[4][5]. It will mark the first time humans have traveled beyond low-Earth orbit since Apollo 17 in 1972[5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--tQ63ystR--/t_thumbnail/https://media.zenfs.com/en/whnt_huntsville_articles_930/caba5b2f2989c52485f59b52b5b1b034" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikkei 225 closes at record high in historic Asian rally</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nikkei-225-hits-record-high-as-HQFGoKSlR0mY866tfmo.gw</link>
      <description>Tokyo's benchmark Nikkei 225 closed at a record high on Tuesday, capping a historic opening to 2026 for Asian equities as investors pivoted away from U.S. markets toward regional tech stocks and AI-related investments[1][2].

The Nikkei 225 gained 1.3% to close at 52,518.08, surpassing its previous record set on October 31[1][3]. The rally was led by technology-related shares, including precision tools maker Disco Corp., which surged 6.1%[1]. The broader TOPIX index also reached an all-time high[4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--NkaPhkwb--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/Wxyy4oHYdZ3TeZx7CSq8Uw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/e75cf85e8232b9a5cd0f592c3ca7ffca" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, AMD, Intel unveil AI chips at CES 2026</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-and-chip-innovations-domina-sxGm3DHTSKez5MYAA4ZxCQ</link>
      <description>The opening day of CES 2026 delivered a cascade of artificial intelligence and semiconductor announcements as industry giants Nvidia, AMD, and Intel unveiled new chips and AI platforms targeting everything from data centers to laptops.

In keynote presentations on Monday, January 5—a day before CES officially opened its doors—the three chipmakers outlined their visions for what Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang called "physical AI," signaling a shift from cloud-based systems to AI that powers robots, autonomous vehicles, and everyday devices.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--sWQ0C0Xt--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/JuDPqcxBIbF4nQMBWykv0g--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2025-12/b0333b00-dcee-11f0-a993-97c527ebca4b" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN condemns US military operation in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-criticizes-us-intervention-wKZ3s8khTAm950ANwJy6ow</link>
      <description>The United Nations Human Rights Office issued a sharp rebuke Tuesday of the US military operation in Venezuela, warning that the intervention undermines international law and makes "all states less safe around the world."[1][2][3][4]

Speaking at a media briefing in Geneva, Ravina Shamdasani, spokesperson for UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Turk, said the operation "violated a fundamental principle of international law" that prohibits states from using force against the territorial integrity or political independence of another state.[1][5][2] "It sends a signal that the powerful can do whatever they like," Shamdasani told reporters.[2][4][6]

The criticism follows the January 3 US military strike on Venezuela that resulted in the capture of President Nicolas Maduro and his wife, Cilia Flores. More than 150 US aircraft bombed military installations across Caracas in the predawn operation, codenamed "Absolute Resolve," before special forces extracted Maduro from the Venezuelan capital.[7][8] Venezuelan officials reported at least 80 people were killed, including civilians.[8]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--QMdTvCK6--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/05/multimedia/05us-venezuela-unsc-sub-kjzw/05us-venezuela-unsc-sub-kjzw-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boston Dynamics unveils Atlas robot, partners with Google DeepMind</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/boston-dynamics-unveils-atlas-LZ94fdalTsW2Xb7ToLIgRg</link>
      <description>Boston Dynamics publicly demonstrated its Atlas humanoid robot for the first time on Monday at CES 2026 in Las Vegas, marking a milestone in the company's decades-long effort to bring industrial robots from laboratory prototypes to factory floors[1][2][3][4].

"For the first time ever in public, please welcome Atlas to the stage," said Zachary Jackowski, Boston Dynamics' vice president and general manager for humanoid robots, as the 5-foot-9, 200-pound machine rose from the floor of a Las Vegas hotel ballroom[1][3][4]. The robot walked fluidly across the stage for several minutes, waving to the crowd and swiveling its head in owl-like motions[1][3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--FDsITjQ---/t_thumbnail/https://metrology.news/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Hyundai-Motor-Group-To-Accelerate-Human%E2%80%93Robot-Collaboration-in-Smart-Manufacturing-1.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia AI boom drives laptop prices up 15-20%</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-unveils-rubin-ai-platfo-3rBY8INFToutEGRM4hsFRQ</link>
      <description>Nvidia unveiled its most powerful AI computing platform yet at CES 2026 on Monday, even as the chip giant's insatiable demand for memory components drives laptop prices to unprecedented heights, leaving consumers caught in the crossfire of the artificial intelligence boom.

The company's Rubin platform, announced by CEO Jensen Huang in Las Vegas, promises five times the AI performance of its predecessor while slashing computing costs[1][2][3][4]. But the same AI revolution powering Nvidia's dominance is creating a global memory shortage that has forced major PC makers to implement steep price increases starting this week[5][6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--eWmub_YE--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/cZ.A2i8c94ZsFbUfOpDN6w--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzY-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/b3e6e620-ea81-11f0-bffe-5b3879265f0c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One in five solar panels degrades twice as fast as expected, UNSW study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/unsw-study-finds-20-percent-of-n5ni8eJ0T8uzqEg5PEng1Q</link>
      <description>Researchers at the University of New South Wales have uncovered a troubling pattern in solar panel performance, finding that approximately 20% of panels examined degrade much more rapidly than industry expectations, potentially lasting only half their anticipated 25-year lifespan.

The study, published in IEEE and released January 5, analyzed data from nearly 11,000 photovoltaic systems worldwide to investigate what scientists call the "long tail" problem—where a subset of panels fails far more quickly than the average degradation rate[1][2][3].

"Most solar systems are designed to last around 25 years, based on their warranty period," said Yang Tang, a PhD student at UNSW's School of Photovoltaic and Renewable Energy Engineering and co-author of the paper[1][3][4]. "For the entire dataset, we observed that system performance typically declines by around 0.9% per year. However, at least one in five systems degrade at least 1.5 times faster than this typical rate, and roughly one in 12 degrade twice as fast."

For operators of solar farms where hundreds of thousands of panels are installed, the findings represent a hidden financial risk that challenges the economic models underpinning the industry's growth[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--M5NbVlVw--/t_thumbnail/https://www.exponent.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image/public/media/images/GettyImages-1170098138%25281%2529.jpg%3Fitok%3DHEPmV6pk" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
