<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:35:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Canal Plus shares surge after projecting synergies from MultiChoice deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canal-plus-targets-over-400-mi-L36v1aZwQ7WqMjaleaM23w</link>
      <description>Canal+ on Thursday announced it expects to deliver over 400 million euros in annual cost synergies and over 300 million euros in free cash flow synergies from 2030 following its $3 billion acquisition of South African broadcaster MultiChoice Group, sending shares to a record high.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Paris-based media company's stock rose approximately 14% after executives outlined synergy targets that analysts described as exceeding expectations. Bank of America raised its price target to 450 pence from 400 pence, calling the projected savings "meaningfully above expectations" of 100 million to 200 million euros.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/76G2TQJCHZO7DDFNOIDQWOM5FY.jpg?auth=4441cde2003e4c28e8a9162af2cfee1f4fe65ec34ea66820a78f66f24b765f56&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold snap threatens to delay NASA's Artemis II moon mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/artemis-ii-faces-possible-laun-CHtr_vsFQFCNgyUV1nFJKQ</link>
      <description>NASA is watching an unusual Florida cold snap that could complicate final preparations for Artemis II, the agency’s first crewed mission around the Moon since Apollo. Forecasts calling for overnight lows near freezing along the Space Coast have raised the risk that temperature constraints could interrupt a key prelaunch fueling test—and potentially push back a launch planned no earlier than early February.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Artemis II Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft, now on the pad at Kennedy Space Center, must complete a “wet dress rehearsal” before NASA sets an official liftoff date. The test involves loading the rocket with cryogenic propellants and running a full countdown without actually launching.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/QnXhKmI0No05ggLPdtkGQA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/usa_today_news_641/f0a8e3a565f6fbe758afbac4d396454c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian researchers report advances in solar panel cooling, perovskite efficiency</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hydrogel-coating-and-perovskit-icvPRfSgQC6BMUMswfPPsw</link>
      <description>Two research teams in Asia have reported advances aimed at squeezing more electricity from solar hardware in the real world: one by cooling conventional silicon panels at their hottest failure-prone points, the other by pushing perovskite technology closer to scalable, high-efficiency modules.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In Hong Kong, researchers at The Hong Kong Polytechnic University said a hydrogel-based layer can reduce “hot spot” temperatures on panels while raising output, a result they argue could be especially relevant for dense cities with rooftop and building-integrated solar. In South Korea, a team led by Gwangju Institute of Science and Technology (GIST) reported a perovskite mini-module with 22.56% efficiency, addressing a key hurdle in making perovskites perform reliably as device area increases.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.polyu.edu.hk/-/media/department/home/media-release/2026/0120/photo-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists propose quantum batteries to power quantum computers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-unveil-quantum-batt-Y4m309cWQvy4._VJkUTeEA</link>
      <description>Researchers from Australia and Japan have proposed an approach to powering quantum computers using quantum batteries, a development they say could make future machines faster, more energy efficient, and easier to scale. The theoretical framework, published January 28 in Physical Review X, suggests quantum batteries could quadruple the number of qubits that fit within current cryogenic systems while reducing the infrastructure demands that have long stymied the technology's commercial progress.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Quantum computers rely on delicate quantum states to perform calculations far beyond the reach of classical machines, but sustaining those states typically requires room-sized, energy-intensive cryogenic cooling systems and complex room-temperature electronics. These constraints remain among the biggest barriers to scaling quantum computing technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.csiro.au/-/media/Newsletters/RI-FSP/Quantum-computer-dark-close-up.jpeg?mw=1200&amp;hash=497C029C5C77D357917DBCDB88C147FD" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China, Netherlands, Australia all set renewable energy records in 2025</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-netherlands-australia-se-Ma8WjjXVRfu.iDsfH5y52w</link>
      <description>Three nations on three continents achieved milestones in clean energy last year, demonstrating the global momentum of the renewable transition even as challenges remain. China installed record amounts of wind and solar capacity, the Netherlands met 57% of its electricity needs from renewables, and Australia's grid crossed the 50% renewable threshold for the first time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://courthousenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/china-wind-turbine-aerial-shot-800x600.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK and China announce trade deals during Starmer's Beijing visit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starmer-secures-closer-uk-chin-JKJjh36jRgKMrkZVK6G9SQ</link>
      <description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and Chinese President Xi Jinping announced a series of agreements on Thursday aimed at revitalizing economic ties between their nations, including a $15 billion investment pledge from AstraZeneca and reduced tariffs on Scotch whisky, during the first visit by a UK leader to China in eight years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The meeting, held at Beijing's Great Hall of the People and lasting approximately 80 minutes, produced what Starmer called "concrete outcomes" that put the bilateral relationship in a "strong place." Xi acknowledged the relationship had experienced "twists and turns" but expressed China's readiness to cultivate a long-term partnership.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/IC3OKWMI3VLHPKMA3JA7BNTORY.jpg?auth=b6ad4dc85a8eb4e872ba64dd5f6def4877ace350058d16d8e89c210868211846&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds microplastics in one third of fish off Pacific islands</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/microplastics-found-in-one-thi-TpJYsgOPQ2G6Kzl2mSUHsA</link>
      <description>A third of fish living off the coasts of remote Pacific Island nations contain microplastics, according to a study published this week, providing new evidence that plastic pollution has reached even the most isolated marine ecosystems on Earth.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, published Wednesday in PLOS One, examined 878 fish from 138 species caught by fishing communities in Fiji, Tonga, Tuvalu, and Vanuatu. While the overall contamination rate was lower than the global average of 49 percent, researchers found stark disparities between islands—with nearly 75 percent of fish sampled in Fiji containing microplastics, compared to just 5 percent in Vanuatu.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.oceanographicmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/07104818/Hawaii-ocean-plastics-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists detect dark matter clump near the Sun for the first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-uncovers-BdtaBO1lQbuKCx32izRjyQ</link>
      <description>New observational evidence is reshaping scientists' understanding of two of the universe's greatest enigmas: the origins of supermassive black holes and the hidden distribution of dark matter in our galaxy. Both breakthroughs rely on innovative techniques to detect objects that cannot be seen directly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a paper published January 29 in Physical Review Letters, astronomers led by Sukanya Chakrabarti at the University of Alabama in Huntsville report finding a massive dark matter clump lurking in the galactic neighborhood of the Sun. The suspected subhalo has a mass roughly 10 million times that of the Sun and is located about 3,260 light-years away.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/08151826/dark_matter_galaxy_pr_final.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google dismantles massive Chinese cyber network linked to malware</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/google-takes-down-chinese-cybe-CK17i_l6Qa6ZA4mP15crSA</link>
      <description>Google used a federal court order on Wednesday to dismantle what it describes as one of the largest residential proxy networks in the world, seizing dozens of domains belonging to the Chinese firm IPIDEA and cutting millions of devices from its infrastructure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The coordinated action, led by Google's Threat Intelligence Group, targeted a network that cybersecurity researchers say covertly installed malicious software on smartphones, computers, and Android devices worldwide. The operation is expected to disconnect more than nine million Android devices from IPIDEA's network.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769701756/getty_uploads/2258008476_idc1bo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold, silver, palladium retreat sharply as investors take profits</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-and-palladium-prices-plun-4Br4rpDrST2aGEybNaE1sw</link>
      <description>Gold, palladium, and silver retreated sharply on Thursday as investors locked in profits following a historic rally that pushed precious metals to record highs. The selloff came a day after the Federal Reserve held interest rates steady and as traders reassessed positions after weeks of gains.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spot gold fell as much as 4% during Thursday's trading to around $5,150 per ounce, pulling back from record highs above $5,500 reached earlier in the week. Palladium tumbled 5% to approximately $1,969 per ounce, while silver dropped more than 5% to around $110 per ounce after briefly touching $120 earlier in the session.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/NTC6CLJUJVINBIZVPODMLDGVAU.jpg?auth=b9b4d5481988eda4144420b19965daf3d15bd9357bcb89947ed78cfd26388828&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump orders Venezuelan airspace reopened for commercial travel</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-reopening-of-v-TtOLAWJ5R7arsuyMQGlfUA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump said Thursday he has instructed U.S. officials to reopen Venezuelan airspace for commercial travel, a move that could ease flight planning across northern South America and, he suggested, clear the way for Americans to visit Venezuela again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump said he relayed the decision to Venezuela’s acting leader, Delcy Rodríguez, and directed Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy and U.S. military leaders to open “all commercial airspace over Venezuela” by the end of the day. “American citizens will be very shortly able to go to Venezuela, and they’ll be safe there,” Trump said, according to an Associated Press account carried by multiple outlets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.tribuneindia.com/sortd-service/imaginary/v22-01/jpg/large/high?url=dGhldHJpYnVuZS1zb3J0ZC1wcm8tcHJvZC1zb3J0ZC9tZWRpYTM1NDE3ZDgwLWNkNDQtMTFmMC1hNWYzLWU1NWZlMzk3YzBhZi5qcGc=" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU approves new Iran sanctions, moves to designate IRGC as terrorist group</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-approves-new-iran-sanctions-BgHOlLpESsmCAfpowS2X9w</link>
      <description>European Union foreign ministers on Jan. 29 approved a new round of sanctions against Iran over a lethal crackdown on nationwide protests and moved toward listing the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) as a terrorist organisation—an escalation EU officials said would put the force in the same category as groups such as al-Qaeda and ISIS.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The measures come amid mounting international pressure on Tehran, as activists and rights groups report thousands killed since demonstrations erupted in late December, while Iranian authorities cite a far lower death toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2026/01/AFP__20260129__94DQ3MC__v1__HighRes__BelgiumEuCouncilPoliticsDiplomacy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran refuses talks with US while Trump issues military threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-rejects-us-negotiations-u-.HcREmk0RI.q5f6esf2fyA</link>
      <description>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi declared on Wednesday that Tehran will not negotiate with the United States while Washington continues to issue military threats, as President Donald Trump announced a "massive armada" heading toward the Islamic Republic. The diplomatic standoff comes amid a significant US military buildup in the Middle East and heightened regional fears of a wider conflict.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"There can be no negotiations in an atmosphere of threats," Araghchi said in remarks carried by Iran's state news agency IRNA. "Conducting diplomacy through military pressure is neither effective nor useful. If they want negotiations, they must abandon threats, excessive demands, and illogical issues."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.ncr-iran.org/en/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/iran-abbas-araghchi-regime-proposed-foreign-minister.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump officials met with Alberta separatists, Financial Times reports</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-officials-meet-alberta-s-19gOxhXDRTWmu3FtGByJsw</link>
      <description>The Trump administration has held at least three meetings with a fringe separatist group advocating for Alberta to break away from Canada, a report in the Financial Times said, adding a volatile new element to already strained U.S.-Canada relations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Leaders tied to the Alberta Prosperity Project (APP) met U.S. State Department officials in Washington three times since April 2025, according to people familiar with the discussions. The group is seeking another meeting in February with State and U.S. Treasury officials to pitch a proposed $500 billion credit facility that it says would help finance an independent Alberta if a referendum succeeds.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/1ZzJd49p2d0icrx0ITrynA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD05MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/national_post_articles_198/d9cef49a28baf2736d03fd6402a2e1a0" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX and xAI in merger talks ahead of potential IPO, Reuters reports</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-and-xai-plan-merger-ahe-fnAdyFbWSP2EKNYm5y8QGw</link>
      <description>Elon Musk’s SpaceX and his artificial-intelligence company xAI are in talks to merge ahead of a planned public offering, a move that would combine rockets, satellites, social media and AI products inside one corporate structure, according to a Reuters report citing a person briefed on the matter and corporate filings.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discussions, first reported by Reuters, would bring SpaceX’s launch business and Starlink satellite network together with xAI’s Grok chatbot and the X social-media platform, which xAI controls. Under the proposed structure, xAI shares would be exchanged for SpaceX shares, the source said, with some xAI executives potentially offered cash instead of SpaceX stock. No final agreement has been signed, and the timing and structure remain fluid, Reuters reported.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2026-01/2026-01-12T073019Z_1_LYNXMPEM0B098_RTROPTP_4_SPACE-EXPLORATION-SPACEX.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold hits record high, oil surges as Trump threatens Iran strike</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-hits-record-oil-surges-on-hd28SZjpSUKjtpz9RiQhyw</link>
      <description>Gold surged past $5,500 per ounce for the first time Thursday, while oil prices climbed to multi-month highs as President Donald Trump escalated military threats against Iran over its nuclear program. The precious metal touched an intraday record of $5,608 before pulling back sharply amid volatile trading, while Brent crude topped $70 a barrel for the first time since late summer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The commodity rallies came as Trump warned Iran that "time is running out" to negotiate a nuclear deal, posting on Truth Social that a "massive armada" was heading toward the region "with speed and violence, if necessary."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://qz.com/cdn-cgi/image/width=1200%2Cquality=85%2Cformat=auto/https://assets.qz.com/media/Gold%2520bars%2520bullion.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio says Donetsk is final obstacle in Ukraine peace talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-leads-peace-talks-as-donets-CqCLI0K3SCyZFkKavycoSQ</link>
      <description>Territorial disputes over Donetsk have emerged as the final barrier to ending the nearly four-year war in Ukraine, US Secretary of State Marco Rubio said Wednesday, as trilateral negotiations between Washington, Kyiv, and Moscow prepare to resume this weekend amid concerns about the preparedness of American negotiators.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The one remaining item … is the territorial claim on Donetsk. There is active work going to try to see if both sides' views on this can be reconciled," Rubio told a US Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing on January 28. "It's still a bridge we haven't crossed. It's still a gap, but at least we've been able to narrow down the issue set to one central one, and it will probably be a very difficult one."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Russia currently occupies roughly 70 percent of Donetsk and demands Ukraine cede the remaining territory it controls. Kyiv has refused to surrender land that Russian forces have not captured on the battlefield, with polls showing little Ukrainian public support for territorial concessions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/B4XZJZRLGBOYJBOFEMUYXK4F2E.jpg?auth=dcf0ee9f8992ddd461b90ee842aa93c9f12dd4616bfae11b96ede2e46960e0e0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX and xAI in merger talks ahead of potential record IPO</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-and-xai-in-merger-talks-nIiFhNf4Qh2WWuT9UW9ddA</link>
      <description>Elon Musk's SpaceX and xAI are in negotiations regarding a potential merger ahead of what could become the largest initial public offering in history, according to exclusive reporting by Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The merger would unite Musk's aerospace empire with his artificial intelligence venture, consolidating the Starlink satellite network, the X social media platform, and the Grok AI chatbot under a single corporate structure. Reuters reported that two Nevada entities were established on January 21 to facilitate the transaction, with SpaceX Chief Financial Officer Bret Johnsen listed as a managing member in corporate filings.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769714274/url_uploads/GettyImages-2246892016_ki7bsw.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba's oil reserves down to 15-20 days as U.S. pressure mounts</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/cuba-faces-critical-oil-shorta-RmS89jOkQDWR7wQjCfBiUg</link>
      <description>Cuba's oil reserves have dwindled to a level that will sustain the island for only 15 to 20 days, according to data from energy analytics firm Kpler, as U.S. pressure on traditional suppliers threatens to push the nation toward economic collapse.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crisis has deepened rapidly following the Trump administration's January 3 military operation that captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro, effectively severing Cuba's primary oil lifeline. Venezuela, which supplied roughly a third of Cuba's oil at approximately 26,500 barrels per day in 2025, has not shipped any crude or fuel to the Caribbean island since early January.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/PLNAJVZ4I5P4VIQ7F6CMDIJWN4.jpg?auth=c991b9e0c150e19da297dcb1b6aa800ebadf7c3aeb66f0268d8477bfe3b82b9d&amp;width=1080&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, Microsoft and Amazon in talks to invest $60B in OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tech-giants-in-talks-to-invest-5daBeu84Q9mqlyhbqHDyww</link>
      <description>Nvidia, Microsoft and Amazon are in discussions to invest up to $60 billion in OpenAI, according to a report by The Information published Wednesday. The talks, if they lead to a deal, would be one of the largest private financings ever for an AI company and would further entangle the world’s biggest technology suppliers in the scramble for computing power and market share in generative AI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The negotiations are ongoing and terms could change, and Reuters said it could not immediately verify The Information’s reporting. Still, the report fits a widening fundraising push around OpenAI that has drawn in major strategic backers and deep pools of global capital.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108202500-17585857512025-02-07t115613z_865237367_rc2npcauossb_rtrmadp_0_openai-germany.jpeg?v=1758585772&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
