<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:33:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine sends youngest recruits to front lines as troop shortage deepens</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ukraine-sends-youngest-recruit-pHrsO_8nT16KhNE9e6ihsw</link>
      <description>As Ukraine enters the fourth year of its war with Russia, the country is grappling with a deepening manpower crisis that has forced young recruits barely out of their teens onto the deadliest parts of the front line, while units across the battlefield operate at a fraction of their intended strength.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scale of the crisis was laid bare this month when newly appointed Defense Minister Mykhailo Fedorov told parliament that two million Ukrainians are wanted for evading military service, while 200,000 soldiers have gone absent without leave. The 34-year-old Fedorov, who took over the ministry with what he described as a 300 billion hryvnia ($6.9 billion) budget deficit, called for urgent reforms to address problems "that have accumulated over the years".</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/cae2a4dc-9b95-4d18-bffc-5a92d4b1be00/Ukraine-soldiers-3-gty-jm-240731_1722442986484_hpEmbed_3x2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns of 'imminent financial collapse' by July</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-faces-imminent-collapse-aft-e4rZDKFpT_yTyMYYOnSwHQ</link>
      <description>The United Nations is on the brink of "imminent financial collapse" and could run out of cash by July, Secretary-General António Guterres warned in a letter to ambassadors dated January 28, marking the most severe funding crisis in the organization's 80-year history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The crisis is deepening, threatening programme delivery and risking financial collapse. And the situation will deteriorate further in the near future," Guterres wrote in the correspondence, obtained by Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The alarm comes weeks after President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on January 7 directing the withdrawal of the United States from 66 international organizations, including 31 UN entities, deeming them "contrary to the interests of the United States".</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CFSJJ7WOTZJ5BB3FKZ3LJ37ZCE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic stuns Sinner in five sets to reach Australian Open final</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/djokovic-defeats-sinner-in-epi-uff7gEbFRGarUi0YfJexCw</link>
      <description>Novak Djokovic turned back the clock in the early hours of Saturday morning in Melbourne, outlasting two-time defending champion Jannik Sinner in a grueling five-set semifinal to reach his 11th Australian Open final. The 38-year-old Serbian prevailed 3-6, 6-3, 4-6, 6-4, 6-4 in four hours and nine minutes, finishing at 1:32 a.m. local time, to become the oldest man in the Open Era to reach the championship match at Melbourne Park.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The victory snapped Djokovic's five-match losing streak against Sinner, his first win over the Italian since November 2023, and propelled him one match away from a record-extending 25th Grand Slam title that would surpass Margaret Court's all-time mark of 24 major singles championships.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://live-production.wcms.abc-cdn.net.au/352f20784daee52a365324e2c0eb63f3?impolicy=wcms_crop_resize&amp;cropH=2002&amp;cropW=3559&amp;xPos=0&amp;yPos=82&amp;width=862&amp;height=485" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says he's in talks with Iran as US warships mass in Gulf</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-deploys-massive-armada-t-8J_2wo3DS4S65pWp2r7bFg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has confirmed he is in talks with Iranian leaders while deploying a major naval fleet to the Persian Gulf, escalating pressure on Tehran to accept U.S. demands on its nuclear program or face military action he warns will be "far worse" than last year's strikes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I have had, and I am planning on it," Trump said Friday when asked about recent conversations with Iran, adding that he conveyed two conditions: "No nukes. And two, stop killing protesters." Ten U.S. warships, including the nuclear-powered aircraft carrier USS Abraham Lincoln and six guided-missile destroyers, are now positioned within striking range of Iran, according to U.S. Navy officials.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769794527/getty_uploads/2258052690_ud2k5o.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump deploys massive US naval force as Iran nuclear deadline nears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-deploys-massive-us-naval-SWF2K3JsQ8G2zw6DzdWKwg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has dispatched a substantial U.S. naval fleet to the Persian Gulf in an escalating standoff with Iran, warning Tehran on Thursday that "time is running out" to negotiate a nuclear agreement or face military action he described as "far worse" than the June 2025 strikes that targeted Iranian nuclear facilities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The deployment, which Trump has repeatedly called a "massive Armada," is led by the aircraft carrier USS Abraham Lincoln and now includes at least six guided-missile destroyers in the region, with the USS Delbert D. Black crossing into the Red Sea on January 29 and docking at Israel's port of Eilat on Friday. The carrier strike group entered the Middle East region on January 26 after departing the South China Sea earlier this month.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/F9jGLqvEViqZyD6VATdlGg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bbc_us_articles_995/61c93e342955bdfe37d3defcbfed04c8" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satellite images show Iran building roofs over bombed nuclear sites</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-rebuilds-bombed-nuclear-s-tdSvIDAESUO_JLX95_m6lw</link>
      <description>New satellite imagery reveals Iran is placing roofs over two nuclear facilities bombed by Israel and the United States last year, raising concerns that Tehran is attempting to shield salvage operations from outside observation as the regime continues to block international inspectors from the sites.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Images from Planet Labs PBC show that Iran completed construction of roofs over damaged buildings at its Natanz and Isfahan nuclear facilities in late December 2025 and early January 2026, according to an Associated Press report published Thursday. The activity marks the first major construction visible by satellite at any of Iran's stricken nuclear sites since Israel's 12-day war with the Islamic Republic in June 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://imengine.public.prod.dur.navigacloud.com/?uuid=d51db679-1da5-5745-895a-ba4cb29c932f&amp;function=original&amp;type=preview" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA probe data reveals origins of solar wind heating</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/parker-solar-probe-reveals-sol-wVONvsMNQ2ancHdfztMuVQ</link>
      <description>Using measurements from NASA's Parker Solar Probe during its record-breaking closest approach to the sun, scientists have mapped the dynamic "shell" of hot gas where the solar wind is born, shedding new light on one of the most enduring mysteries in heliophysics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, led by University of Arizona associate professor Kristopher Klein and published this week in Geophysical Research Letters, offers the first detailed analysis of how energy moves through the sun's outer atmosphere at distances never before measured, with implications for predicting space weather events that affect Earth's satellites, communications systems, and power grids.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2023/durable-parker-solar-p.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky backs energy truce, says Ukraine will halt strikes if Russia reciprocates</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/zelensky-voices-support-for-u-QA_w7OKQSg2YGtSFXtaU5Q</link>
      <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky endorsed a U.S.-proposed pause on strikes targeting energy infrastructure on Friday, pledging that Kyiv would halt attacks on Russian energy facilities if Moscow reciprocates—though he emphasized that no formal agreement exists between the two nations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If Russia does not strike our energy infrastructure—generation facilities or any other energy assets—we will not strike theirs," Zelensky told reporters on January 30, characterizing the arrangement as "an opportunity, not an agreement."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The development follows President Donald Trump's announcement Thursday that Russian President Vladimir Putin had agreed to suspend attacks on Kyiv and other Ukrainian cities for one week amid extreme cold weather. Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov confirmed Friday that Trump "did indeed make a personal request to President Putin to refrain from striking Kyiv for a week until February 1 in order to create favorable conditions for negotiations."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/XO2D623IMJOHFBKHPCVOAPWPII.jpg?auth=20e228e0da5e806f0b767fd17edf82740d9093e7d06f14e6c43826718e25fbdd&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's Greenland threats halt US-Danish climate research</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-s-greenland-moves-disrup-MgMj.CU0QrmMDtiI_htCng</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's escalating pressure on Greenland has begun to chill scientific ties between American and Greenlandic researchers, with at least one climate program halted and future collaborations cast into uncertainty. The diplomatic strain comes just days after the United States officially exited the Paris Agreement, further isolating the country from global climate efforts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ross Virginia, a professor emeritus of environmental studies at Dartmouth College, said a climate program he ran with Greenlandic colleagues was halted by "mutual agreement" due to the tensions, according to Bloomberg News. "Direct cooperation is paused while we determine what a future vision for collaborative science diplomacy — particularly involving education and younger students — could look like," he said.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Another US scientist, speaking anonymously for fear of jeopardizing relationships, said some research partnerships had been affected by the political climate.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i3mI08XqNv2g/v1/1200x800.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New electrode converts exhaust CO2 into formic acid in one step</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-create-device-to-co-30CiRXlCQ6.eaPw68ipn_A</link>
      <description>Researchers in South Korea have developed a new electrode capable of capturing carbon dioxide directly from exhaust gases and converting it into formic acid in a single step, an advancement that could simplify industrial carbon recycling.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, published January 21 in ACS Energy Letters and selected as an official press release by the American Chemical Society, introduces a three-layer electrode design that functions under realistic conditions rather than requiring purified carbon dioxide.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://interestingengineering.com/_next/image?url=https%253A%252F%252Fcms.interestingengineering.com%252Fwp-content%252Fuploads%252F2025%252F12%252Fcarbon-capture-and-storage74c90d3cf61044b29c45e3c3ee4df1b3.jpeg&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin envoy to meet Trump officials in Miami Saturday</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/putin-envoy-dmitriev-to-meet-t-obfYEo2mTpSJ6V2Fm7iwnw</link>
      <description>Kirill Dmitriev, Russian President Vladimir Putin's special envoy, is scheduled to travel to Miami on Saturday for meetings with members of the Trump administration, according to two sources familiar with the plans, Reuters reported on Thursday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The visit marks the latest in a series of diplomatic engagements between Moscow and Washington as the two sides work toward a resolution to the war in Ukraine. Dmitriev, who heads the Russian Direct Investment Fund (RDIF), has emerged as a central figure in the Trump administration's efforts to broker peace between Russia and Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/PHIJGKFNIVPBFLAQKMECGARI6Q.jpg?auth=bf541580f7c05e624b64e6ce8c73b2efced5bbac8908dba3515a75746cf59ba1&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oil prices ease as Trump signals openness to Iran talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/oil-prices-ease-as-us-iran-ten-yGvXR_DeQzi6zL9vjgGBgw</link>
      <description>Crude oil prices retreated from multi-month highs on Friday after President Donald Trump signaled he was open to talks with Iran over its nuclear program, tempering fears of an imminent military strike that had driven a sharp rally earlier in the week.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brent crude fell nearly 1% on Friday, pulling back from the $70 level it had breached the day before for the first time since July, according to CNBC. West Texas Intermediate also declined more than 1%, dropping from the four-month highs reached Thursday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"President Trump's readiness to consider diplomacy with Iran appears to make a U.S. military action less probable than it was yesterday," said Tamas Varga, an analyst at PVM Oil Associates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/NQCTFX7TSBN5VNJKWTOJ2WP5M4.jpg?auth=d6d8a7009dfdfb83484086242e95b936d4eb8307f0b8546599a209dc0aec174f&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini telescope reveals comet ATLAS crumbling after solar pass</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-study-comet-atlas-UtdBBvzXTPaMy2B_3NMgZg</link>
      <description>Astronomers this week released new images documenting two distinct celestial objects bearing the ATLAS name: one a solar system comet that fragmented after its close solar approach, and the other an interstellar visitor that continues to puzzle scientists with its unusual jet structures and delayed detection in archival data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Gemini North telescope in Hawaii captured high-resolution footage of Comet C/2025 K1 (ATLAS) breaking apart, with images released Thursday showing the comet's nucleus splintering into multiple fragments following its closest approach to the Sun on October 8, 2025. Meanwhile, NASA confirmed that the interstellar object 3I/ATLAS had been present in archived TESS satellite data from May 2025—nearly two months before its official discovery on July 1, 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QrqFdH6v6HfBTmPaE8t8db-1920-80.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX earned $8 billion profit in 2025, sources say</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-earns-8-billion-profit-zH23hvsjQOSwwGR5JaUkrg</link>
      <description>SpaceX generated approximately $8 billion in profit on revenue of $15 billion to $16 billion last year, according to a Reuters exclusive published Thursday, offering a rare glimpse into the financial performance of Elon Musk's aerospace company as it prepares for what could be the largest initial public offering in history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The profit figure represents earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA), a key measure of operational performance. Musk's satellite internet service Starlink drives the company's finances, accounting for 50 to 80 percent of total revenue, according to people familiar with the company's results.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.brimco.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Elon-Musk-Relocates-SpaceX-and-X-Headquarters.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bob Iger plans early exit as Disney board nears new CEO decision</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/bob-iger-plans-early-departure-0kaZCjOxTxqBdibo.VSK6A</link>
      <description>Bob Iger has informed associates he intends to step down as chief executive of the Walt Disney Company before his contract expires at the end of 2026, according to The Wall Street Journal. The entertainment giant's board of directors is scheduled to convene next week at Disney's headquarters in Burbank, California, where they are expected to select Iger's successor.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement signals a turning point in a succession process that has shadowed one of Hollywood's most influential executives. For Disney, the stakes are especially high after the company's 2020 leadership transition ended with the dismissal of Bob Chapek and the forced return of the 74-year-old Iger.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://blooloop.com/media-library/bob-iger-disney.jpg?id=56468061&amp;width=1245&amp;height=700&amp;coordinates=0%252C46%252C0%252C46" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bomb cyclone targets Southeast as Australia's record heat persists</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-snow-storms-and-australia-h-tpsBwDFrTwicGsGydqkoMA</link>
      <description>As the United States reels from its deadliest winter storm in years, with at least 117 deaths confirmed and another bomb cyclone bearing down on the East Coast, Australia is simultaneously enduring its most severe heatwave since the 2019-20 Black Summer. Scientists say both events bear the unmistakable fingerprint of a warming planet.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Winter Storm Fern, which swept across the nation from January 23-26, brought catastrophic ice and snow from Northern Mexico to New England, causing over a million power outages and preliminary damage estimates exceeding $1 billion. Meanwhile, southeastern Australia has recorded temperatures approaching 50 degrees Celsius (122 degrees Fahrenheit), setting all-time records across multiple states.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/c_fit%2Cq_auto:eco%2Cw_1250/rockcms/2026-01/260123-Columbus-rs-9c8073.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexico warns of humanitarian crisis after Trump tariffs on Cuba oil</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mexico-seeks-diplomatic-soluti-snTeYf.EQVSEiK1uoHBqAg</link>
      <description>Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum warned Friday that US tariffs targeting countries that supply oil to Cuba could trigger a "far-reaching humanitarian crisis," as she announced her government would pursue diplomatic channels while seeking alternatives to assist the Caribbean island.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came one day after President Donald Trump signed an executive order authorizing tariffs on goods from any nation that directly or indirectly provides oil to Cuba, declaring the island "an unusual and extraordinary threat" to US national security. The decree did not specify tariff rates or which countries would be affected.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/N5FST77MGFJPZKVK4WFC674WFE.jpg?auth=747c87f9c49dd0f8e53f1ffbfa3901631aaec0a92c42f66efba7532703a2c59c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top AI models score below 40% on new expert-level benchmark</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-struggles-with-new-2500-que-R2Rl.sqxSvOZ2eqEjBhUrQ</link>
      <description>A new benchmark designed to push the limits of artificial intelligence has been formally published in the journal Nature, revealing that even the most advanced AI systems score below 40% on questions that probe the frontier of human knowledge.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Humanity's Last Exam" comprises 2,500 expert-level questions spanning more than 100 academic subfields, from interpreting ancient Palmyrene script on Roman tombstones to analyzing hummingbird skeletal structures. The benchmark represents a global collaboration of nearly 1,000 professors and researchers from over 500 institutions across 50 countries, including contributors from KAIST and Yonsei University in South Korea.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769809662/getty_uploads/2258944768_pqejrr.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carlyle in talks with UAE investors over Lukoil asset deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/carlyle-seeks-uae-partners-for-xIRp8DIiTECf7aM6l6lEMQ</link>
      <description>Carlyle Group has begun exploratory talks with Abu Dhabi investors about bringing in partners should its preliminary agreement to acquire Russian oil producer Lukoil's international assets proceed, according to Reuters, which cited three sources with knowledge of the process.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discussions come just one day after Carlyle and Lukoil announced the provisional deal on Thursday, which would transfer a sweeping portfolio of oilfields in Iraq and refineries in Eastern Europe to the U.S. private equity firm, pending approval from U.S. sanctions authorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/J2YZIUOAEJO4FNPTAUFXM7DMIQ.jpg?auth=4d89107cebe61e1ee777a20b035c24454bc8e4d8e2be32a61d8347868f569ab8&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela frees all known US detainees, announces amnesty law</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-announces-general-am-bsbuf5NYTzCtZDKEI3tA8g</link>
      <description>Venezuela's interim president, Delcy Rodríguez, announced Friday a general amnesty law covering political prisoners detained since 1999, a measure that could benefit hundreds of detainees as the South American nation moves to satisfy U.S. demands nearly a month after Nicolás Maduro's capture by American forces.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement, made during an event at the Supreme Court of Justice in Caracas, comes as the U.S. Embassy confirmed it had secured the release of all known American citizens detained in Venezuela.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 01:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thehill.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/697d4ae0f39a91.01972194.jpeg?w=1280" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
