<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:04:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>NASA rolls Artemis II rocket to launch pad ahead of moon mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jeremy-hansen-prepares-for-his-C_VG_cHPT6uOOdcO9ugD1Q</link>
      <description>Canadian astronaut Jeremy Hansen stood at NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Saturday morning, watching as the rocket that will carry him around the moon began its slow journey to the launch pad. Hansen, a 49-year-old from London, Ontario, is set to become the first non-American to travel beyond low Earth orbit when Artemis II lifts off as early as next month.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The four-mile rollout of NASA's Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft began at 7:04 a.m. EST on January 17, with the 11-million-pound stack creeping toward Launch Complex 39B at about one mile per hour. The journey to the launch pad is expected to take up to 12 hours.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/17/multimedia/17HS-ARTEMIS-II-stillpromo-cglm/17HS-ARTEMIS-II-stillpromo-cglm-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump held secret talks with Venezuela's Cabello before Maduro capture</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-administration-engaged-i-s2h87isSQEGo.DrBd1jjsA</link>
      <description>The Trump administration held months of quiet discussions with Venezuela's interior minister Diosdado Cabello before the January 3 military operation that captured President Nicolás Maduro, and communications have continued since, according to multiple sources familiar with the matter in an exclusive Reuters report published Friday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;U.S. officials warned Cabello, 62, against deploying security services or militant ruling-party supporters to target Venezuela's opposition, four sources told Reuters. The talks also addressed U.S. sanctions imposed on him and his federal drug-trafficking indictment. Despite being named in the same indictment that justified Maduro's arrest—with a $25 million bounty on his head—Cabello was not apprehended during the operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768678583/getty_uploads/2256293839_ubjgqt.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran's Khamenei admits thousands killed in protests blaming US</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-s-khamenei-admits-thousan-K9CrD2QdQgmd5Oft27VfNQ</link>
      <description>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on Saturday accused U.S. President Donald Trump of being a "criminal" responsible for casualties, destruction, and spreading falsehoods against the Iranian people, as the country emerges from its deadliest unrest in decades with thousands reported killed in a brutal crackdown.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We consider the U.S. president a criminal for the casualties, damages, and the slander he inflicted on the Iranian nation," Khamenei said during a speech marking Eid al-Mab'ath, the anniversary of the Prophet Muhammad's mission, according to Iranian media. He described the protests as an "American sedition" designed to "devour Iran."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2026/01/AP26003388650698-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron slams Trump's Greenland tariff threats, vows united EU response</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/macron-calls-trump-greenland-t-v9FG.Uj1Sgqsihmx2zB7wA</link>
      <description>French President Emmanuel Macron responded forcefully on Saturday to U.S. President Donald Trump's announcement of sweeping tariffs on eight European countries, declaring that "no intimidation or threat will influence us" and promising a united European response to what he called an unacceptable escalation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The sharp rebuke came hours after Trump announced on Truth Social that Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland would face a 10 percent tariff on all goods exported to the United States starting February 1, rising to 25 percent on June 1. The levies would remain in place "until such time as a Deal is reached for the Complete and Total purchase of Greenland," Trump said.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 20:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/Q275TYSCINN2TAXAT5BFEEVKHU.jpg?auth=cd71b39a44d76a4acdf3a0d092311bf61aaf02c57d682c0bfaf0baaec61fa4db&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands protest Trump's Greenland push in Denmark, Arctic</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mass-protests-erupt-in-denmark-XkvSYtmpQJGgxPwEjQ.tUw</link>
      <description>Thousands of demonstrators took to the streets across Denmark and Greenland on Saturday, January 17, 2026, in a forceful rejection of President Donald Trump's escalating campaign to acquire the Arctic territory. The protests came hours after Trump announced sweeping tariffs on eight European nations opposing his push, deepening an unprecedented diplomatic rift between NATO allies.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/2RVQDW52LFKXXCGL4SQEWUU73Q.jpg?auth=26a90eab0c3121481607a96bef3fbf016fee107b66b32a8d917136810da0180c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump asks countries to pay $1 billion for permanent peace board seats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-wants-nations-to-pay-1-b-juzl8dT9Sj2TkEURIgx_zA</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is asking countries that want a permanent spot on President Donald Trump's new Board of Peace to contribute at least $1 billion, according to a draft charter of the body sent to world leaders this weekend.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The provision, outlined in the charter distributed alongside invitation letters on Friday, effectively creates a two-tier membership structure. Countries that contribute $1 billion or more in cash funds to the Board of Peace would be exempt from the standard three-year membership term, securing them a permanent seat on the panel.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thehill.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/10/Leading-Trump-and-Milei_101425_Greg-Nash.jpg?w=1280" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU lawmakers move to freeze US trade deal after Trump tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-halts-us-trade-deal-approva-Ibq3iLbcSzGJ54hUAhhSug</link>
      <description>European Union lawmakers are poised to freeze approval of the EU-US trade deal after President Donald Trump announced tariffs on eight NATO allies Saturday in his latest bid to acquire Greenland. The move marks a dramatic escalation in transatlantic tensions, jeopardizing the landmark agreement struck just six months ago.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Manfred Weber, president of the European People's Party—the largest political faction in the European Parliament—declared that proceeding with the trade deal is no longer feasible. "The EPP is in favor of the EU-US trade deal, but given Donald Trump's threats regarding Greenland, approval is not possible at this stage," Weber posted on social media Saturday, adding that "zero tariffs on US products must now be put on hold."</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i73poNj8ag5I/v1/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU calls emergency meeting after Trump tariff threat over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-calls-emergency-meeting-ove-jwin0js5SYeLM5aYJMMJGg</link>
      <description>Ambassadors from the European Union's 27 member states will convene for an emergency meeting on Sunday after U.S. President Donald Trump announced a wave of escalating tariffs on European allies over their opposition to the American acquisition of Greenland, an unprecedented move that threatens to fracture the transatlantic alliance and ignite a new trade war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Cyprus, which holds the EU's six-month rotating presidency, called the urgent session late Saturday, with diplomats indicating it is scheduled to begin at 5 p.m. GMT. European Council President António Costa confirmed he is coordinating a collective response from member states, stating, "The EU will maintain its stance on upholding international law, wherever it is applicable".</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/35TURRJKS5OOPAB6Q2NLOWITQA.jpg?auth=9357ab30f7046186c9c8ae998283aae191725346ad13be364fabcc03d3224df7&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN report: Global power demand to surge by 2035 as AI strains grids</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ai-drives-surge-in-nuclear-pow-YxgCtQmZSGeDVK9oVP3SxQ</link>
      <description>The artificial intelligence revolution is reshaping the global energy landscape, with tech giants racing to secure nuclear power contracts as data center electricity consumption threatens to strain power grids worldwide.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Global electricity demand is expected to increase by more than 10,000 terawatt-hours by 2035, a figure equivalent to the total consumption of all advanced economies today, according to a UN report released this week. The International Energy Agency estimates that data center electricity demand grew by more than 75 percent between 2023 and 2024, and the sector is expected to account for over 20 percent of electricity-demand growth in advanced economies by 2030.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/7LW1A6_DDv4h2DZHdIjaIQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/techcrunch_finance_785/f565ee5eb4f18ff7b28f7cd896251f31" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran confirms 5,000 dead in crackdown as protests subside</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-crackdown-kills-thousands-hYFd_ZThSVSRVI_zuqnNpA</link>
      <description>An Iranian official acknowledged on Sunday that authorities have verified at least 5,000 deaths during three weeks of nationwide protests, the first such confirmation from within the government as the Islamic Republic's deadliest crackdown in decades appears to have temporarily suppressed street demonstrations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The figure, which includes approximately 500 security personnel, was disclosed by a regional official speaking to Reuters on condition of anonymity. The official blamed "terrorists and armed rioters" for the casualties, while attributing support for protesters to "Israel and armed groups abroad." The acknowledgment follows Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's admission on Saturday that "several thousand" had died during the unrest.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768753913/getty_uploads/2255940586_a3gbzc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China blocks Nvidia H200 chip imports, halting supplier production</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-blocks-nvidia-h200-chip-yXOGGZmSQHib_Bdaw9dmcA</link>
      <description>Chinese customs authorities have blocked shipments of NVIDIA Corporation's H200 artificial intelligence processors, prompting suppliers of specialized components to halt production amid what industry analysts describe as a sudden and unexpected reversal in trade relations between the world's two largest economies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The move, first reported by the Financial Times on January 16, came after customs officials in Shenzhen summoned logistics companies on January 7 and instructed them not to accept customs clearance applications for H200 chips. Early shipments of H200s were already arriving in Hong Kong when the blockade took effect, catching Nvidia off guard, according to sources familiar with the matter.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/N4EQEEV44FIZ7H3VF4A2QX72D4.jpg?auth=4f562fe44f1fc2c439a3aad5363a0f184ab320b60679f9cbe7dd2d729607a1dc&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran president warns attack on Khamenei means 'all-out war'</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-president-warns-strikes-o-_Yk45mnwSxCHdtrv9fmNgg</link>
      <description>Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian declared Sunday that any attack on Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei would be "tantamount to all-out war against the Iranian nation," escalating a war of words with Washington after President Donald Trump called for "new leadership" in Tehran.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Any aggression against the supreme leader of our country is tantamount to all-out war against the Iranian nation," Pezeshkian wrote on the social media platform X. The Iranian president also blamed Washington for his country's economic struggles, citing "longstanding enmity and inhumane sanctions" imposed by the United States and its allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pezeshkian's warning followed a sharp exchange between Trump and Khamenei on Saturday. In an interview with Politico, Trump said "it's time to look for new leadership in Iran," calling the 86-year-old supreme leader "a sick man who should run his country properly and stop killing people". Trump added that Iran under Khamenei's rule was "the worst place to live anywhere in the world because of poor leadership".</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/6NIVAA3SJNJL3PEAG6GKW6SAMQ.jpg?auth=7f4b461c6ded2f95a4509294c72e2c1a51ca5d9578bf5d9cd433d7a3f3c286bc&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU weighs $108 billion in retaliatory tariffs after Trump targets Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-plans-108-billion-tariffs-a-cAv03h1NS_aq8fHeKawKVA</link>
      <description>European capitals are considering imposing up to 93 billion euros ($108 billion) in retaliatory tariffs or market restrictions on American companies in response to President Donald Trump's threat to levy escalating duties on eight European nations until the United States is allowed to purchase Greenland, according to the Financial Times.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The retaliatory measures are being drawn up to give European leaders leverage in pivotal meetings with Trump at the World Economic Forum in Davos this week, the FT reported Sunday, citing officials involved in preparations for the Switzerland meetings.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets3.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2026/01/18/bb537ea0-0a30-4db8-b4a0-16f1b9722d13/thumbnail/1200x630/595af83aff67b134f9eb4a672c9540ea/gettyimages-2256239117.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starmer tells Trump tariffs on NATO allies over Greenland are wrong</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starmer-tells-trump-greenland-NUHKRiOaSJKzQjbZRJcg4w</link>
      <description>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer directly challenged President Donald Trump on Sunday, telling him in a phone call that imposing tariffs on NATO allies over Greenland is "wrong." The conversation came one day after Trump announced sweeping tariffs against eight European nations in his latest effort to pressure Denmark into selling the Arctic territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to an official Downing Street statement, Starmer spoke with Trump after first coordinating with Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen, and NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte. "He said that security in the High North is a priority for all NATO allies in order to protect Euro-Atlantic interests," Downing Street said. "He also said that applying tariffs on allies for pursuing the collective security of NATO allies is wrong."</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://e3.365dm.com/25/10/768x432/skynews-donald-trump-keir-starmer_7050224.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syrian government, Kurdish forces agree ceasefire after rapid advance</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/syrian-government-and-sdf-agre-gUTQ3bTgRmOQuE.Dp_3GjQ</link>
      <description>The Syrian government and the U.S.-backed Syrian Democratic Forces reached a ceasefire agreement on Sunday following days of intense combat that saw government troops rapidly advance through Kurdish-held territories in the country's north and east, seizing strategic oil fields and key cities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and SDF commander Mazloum Abdi signed the 14-point accord, which state media described as an "immediate and comprehensive" halt to hostilities across all fronts. The agreement marks a watershed moment in Damascus's efforts to reassert control over nearly all of Syria following the toppling of Bashar Assad in December 2024.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 22:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2026-01-18T151711Z_2030713871_RC2P3JAXM7RY_RTRMADP_3_SYRIA-SECURITY-KURDS-1768750044.jpg?resize=730%252C410&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequoia backs Anthropic, breaking VC tradition on rival bets</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sequoia-invests-in-anthropic-a-3HiplfiWQauaZofLG9Fk_w</link>
      <description>Sequoia Capital is joining a blockbuster funding round for Anthropic that values the AI startup at $350 billion, according to the Financial Times. The move breaks with long-standing venture capital tradition by backing a direct competitor to OpenAI and xAI, both of which are already in Sequoia's portfolio.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The funding round is led by Singapore's sovereign wealth fund GIC and U.S. investor Coatue, with each contributing $1.5 billion. Anthropic is targeting a total raise of $25 billion or more, which would close to double its $183 billion valuation from September's Series F round.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/tcdisrupt_ny16-5284.jpg?w=1024" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU weighs €93B tariffs in response to Trump's Greenland threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-prepares-eur93-billion-reta-vLr0OF39RHKf1IvBr1BP3w</link>
      <description>European Union capitals are considering imposing €93 billion ($108 billion) in retaliatory tariffs against the United States and restricting American companies from accessing the bloc's market in response to President Donald Trump's tariff threats targeting NATO allies who oppose his campaign to acquire Greenland, according to the Financial Times.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The escalating standoff marks one of the most serious crises in transatlantic relations in recent memory, with European leaders abandoning what officials described as an "appeasement" strategy toward the Trump administration.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 01:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/resizer/v2/77ZZNUKB5RANVD7JFPWK4CMCJQ.jpg?auth=eae3a171c3a6a739ce76c5c8fef3378f7d85900ed491a89cdbc9fa9023d9929f&amp;width=1500&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two trains collide in Spain, killing at least 21</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spain-train-crash-kills-21-in-QLAfyx4OTze_otHnVJEOZA</link>
      <description>At least 21 people were killed and up to 100 injured when two high-speed trains collided in southern Spain on Sunday evening after one derailed and crossed into the path of an oncoming service, prompting authorities to suspend all rail traffic between Madrid and the Andalusia region.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crash occurred at approximately 6:40 p.m. local time near the town of Adamuz in Córdoba province when an Iryo train traveling from Málaga to Madrid derailed and struck a Renfe train heading from Madrid to Huelva, according to Spanish rail network operator Adif. Both trains were carrying hundreds of passengers—roughly 300 on the Iryo service and around 100 to 200 on the Renfe train.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spain's Transport Minister Óscar Puente confirmed the death toll after midnight, stating that all survivors had been rescued from the wreckage. Among those killed was the driver of the Renfe train, according to state broadcaster Televisión Española. Officials said 25 of the injured sustained serious wounds, with 73 passengers transported to six different hospitals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamereactor.eu/media/61/_4786153b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU holds off on trade 'bazooka' as Trump tariffs loom</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-prepares-response-to-trump-6arEsVIZRmO_MBwHFDFkow</link>
      <description>The European Union is weighing tariffs on up to €93 billion ($108 billion) worth of American goods and considering unprecedented trade countermeasures after President Donald Trump threatened to impose a 10% levy on eight European countries unless Washington is allowed to purchase Greenland.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;EU ambassadors from all 27 member states convened for an emergency meeting in Brussels on Sunday following Trump's announcement on Saturday that tariffs would take effect February 1 on Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland. The president warned the rate would rise to 25% by June 1 unless a deal is reached for the "Complete and Total purchase of Greenland."</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/5743x3230%2B0%2B31/resize/1400/quality/85/format/jpeg/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fb9%252F2e%252F542206b94db6865f90820f05eac2%252Fap25353099211791.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excitons outperform light for engineering quantum materials</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/excitons-enable-efficient-quan-8J676c_6QuKownQbJR_FMA</link>
      <description>A breakthrough in Floquet engineering demonstrates that excitons—quasiparticles formed within semiconductors—can modify material properties far more efficiently than light alone, potentially opening a new path to creating quantum materials on demand.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers from the Okinawa Institute of Science and Technology (OIST) and Stanford University have shown that exciton-driven Floquet effects in monolayer semiconductors are two orders of magnitude stronger and last longer than effects achieved with conventional light-based methods, according to findings published in Nature Physics on January 18, 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/IE-photo-ratio-19201080-21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
