<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 23:26:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Trump claims US in charge of Venezuela after Maduro arrest</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-claims-us-control-over-v-jlr1s9n6SDScmNQrX.lDcw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared the United States is "in charge" of Venezuela following a military operation that captured longtime leader Nicolás Maduro, outlining plans to rebuild the country's oil infrastructure before eventual elections[1][2][3].

"Don't ask me who's in charge because I'll give you an answer, and it'll be very controversial," Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One. When pressed to clarify, he replied, "It means we're in charge"[1][3].

The stunning announcement came after U.S. special forces captured Maduro and his wife, Cilia Flores, in the early morning hours of January 3 during Operation Absolute Resolve, which involved more than 150 aircraft and strikes across northern Venezuela[4][5]. Maduro is scheduled to appear in Manhattan federal court on January 5 to face narco-terrorism, cocaine importation conspiracy, and weapons charges[6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--KWex0kr8--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/be7c1ce/2147483647/strip/true/crop/6000x3150%2B0%2B425/resize/1200x630%21/quality/90/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fcf%252F81%252Fa2ed6e084b93b46c8e0e8d75376c%252Fnicolas-maduro-091525.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian stocks hit record highs as tech rally continues</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/markets-react-to-us-capture-of-f2ByDZg.RjuelkDt5uliaQ</link>
      <description>Asian stock markets climbed to record highs Monday, led by a powerful rally in technology shares, as investors largely looked past geopolitical turmoil following the weekend US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro. Gold prices surged while oil fluctuated in early trading.

South Korea's Kospi jumped 3.43% to close at 4,457.52 points, breaking through 4,400 for the first time[1]. Japan's Nikkei 225 soared 2.97% to near its record high[1], while Taiwan's benchmark rose 2.57% past 30,000 points for the first time[1]. The rallies extended last year's artificial intelligence boom, with MSCI's Asia-Pacific stock index climbing as much as 1.7% to an all-time high[2].

Samsung Electronics led gains with a 7.47% surge[1], while Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing rocketed more than 5% after Goldman Sachs raised its price target by 35%[3]. SK Hynix climbed 2.81%[1]. US stock futures rose modestly, with S&amp;P 500 futures up 0.1%[4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--xg3vtbXn--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/21HbWItgJ4mP7qblsf.zhA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/ap.org/8f16639fe7ff8aa412498215bf177b2b" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech stocks drive global markets higher after Venezuela operation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tech-stocks-boost-global-marke-XdKj_rMgRxCEHW5N.QQc3g</link>
      <description>Global stock markets climbed Monday, led by a technology rally in Asia, as investors shrugged off geopolitical uncertainty following the weekend U.S. military operation that captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro. Oil prices drifted lower despite the upheaval in the OPEC nation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--StXF-8xO--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108229168-17636514422025-10-28t100019z_1226650128_rc2z28a7uakr_rtrmadp_0_nvidia-developers.jpeg%3Fv%3D1764596799%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump warns Venezuela of second strike if cooperation fails</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-second-strike-CGHvZ5cdQXSOhDgwdJytww</link>
      <description>Oil prices edged lower Monday as President Donald Trump threatened another military operation against Venezuela while his administration doubled down on an oil embargo aimed at forcing sweeping changes in the South American nation.

Brent crude fell 1.4% to $59.91 per barrel by the close of trading Monday, while West Texas Intermediate declined to $56.56, as markets weighed the fallout from the weekend capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro against concerns about global supply surplus[1][2][3]. Trump told reporters Sunday he could order a second strike if Venezuela's interim government fails to cooperate with US efforts to reshape the country's oil industry and halt drug trafficking[4][5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--d5oC7spM--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2026-01-04T040106Z_1581451739_RC2IADARCY8V_RTRMADP_3_USA-VENEZUELA-POWER-1767594531.jpg%3Fresize%3D1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markets rise as US captures Venezuelan President Maduro</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/markets-rise-after-us-captures-129XXryCQa6Yjla1zjv_dg</link>
      <description>Global stock markets climbed Monday as investors absorbed the dramatic weekend US military operation in Venezuela that resulted in the capture of President Nicolás Maduro, with traders weighing geopolitical risks against potential long-term economic opportunities[1][2][3].

US stock futures rose in early trading, with the S&amp;P 500 gaining 0.2%, the Nasdaq 100 jumping 0.5%, and the Dow Jones Industrial Average edging up 0.1%[1][2]. European markets also advanced, with London's FTSE 100 rising 0.2%, Germany's DAX climbing 1%, and France's CAC 40 up 0.6%[3].

The subdued market reaction reflected analysts' assessment that Venezuela's limited oil production—currently below 1 million barrels per day, or less than 1% of global supply—constrains the potential for major disruptions[1][3][4]. "Venezuela accounts for less than 1% of global oil, and at best a political outcome restoring production will take years," said Lale Akoner, a global market analyst at eToro[3].

Gold prices surged 2.3% to $4,433.71 per ounce as investors sought safe-haven assets amid heightened geopolitical uncertainty[3][5][6]. Meanwhile, oil futures fluctuated in early trading, with Brent crude falling 0.4% to $60.60 per barrel and West Texas Intermediate declining 0.5% to $56.97[3][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--aI_Z3Faz--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/jTifiM7pTRI7xbwRbtMwdA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/f1bd6b30-e9c4-11f0-b76b-2da2c09c4452" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investors shift to value stocks amid AI inflation fears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/investors-shift-focus-amid-202-BU7v.4w0TFmaUZD6s9mlKQ</link>
      <description>As global stock markets enter 2026 riding high on artificial intelligence enthusiasm, a growing chorus of investors and strategists warn that surging AI-related spending could reignite inflation and derail the rally, prompting a strategic shift toward undervalued assets.

Money managers are increasingly concerned that the multi-trillion-dollar race among tech giants Microsoft, Meta, and Alphabet to build AI data centers is driving up costs for chips and energy, creating inflationary pressures that markets may be underestimating. Deutsche Bank projects AI data center capital expenditure could reach $4 trillion by 2030[1][2][3], while Morgan Stanley strategist Andrew Sheets notes that "costs are going up not down in our forecast, because there's inflation in chip costs and inflation in power costs"[1][2][4].

"What keeps us awake at night is that inflation risk has resurfaced," said Julius Bendikas, European head of economics and dynamic asset allocation at Mercer, which manages $683 billion in assets[1][2]. Trevor Greetham, head of multi-asset at Royal London Asset Management, warned that while he continues holding tech stocks for now, he "would not be surprised to see inflation booming worldwide by the end of 2026"[5][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--zmiS1L_j--/t_thumbnail/https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/L7MQGNFG3FDHPNXGWN4X46VY34.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists track single sunspot for record 94 days</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/solar-orbiter-sets-record-with-H1iK_OvrQBqcc8D9ER6vAA</link>
      <description>Scientists have achieved the longest continuous observation of a single active solar region, tracking sunspot NOAA 13664 for 94 days as it evolved from birth to decay. The research, published this week in the journal Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, offers insights into solar storm formation that could improve space weather forecasting[1][2][3].

An international team led by ETH Zurich combined data from the European Space Agency's Solar Orbiter and NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory to monitor the region from April 16 to July 18, 2024. "This is the longest continuous series of images ever created for a single active region: it's a milestone in solar physics," said Ioannis Kontogiannis, a physicist at ETH Zurich and Istituto ricerche solari Aldo e Cele Daccò in Locarno[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--0KXzeS8B--/t_thumbnail/https://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2024/06/solar_orbiter_s_view_of_active_region_ar36642/26171236-1-eng-GB/Solar_Orbiter_s_view_of_active_region_AR3664_pillars.gif" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin climbs above $92,000 as whales return</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/bitcoin-surges-past-92000-to-s-OmuIs0XyRzK8dV1ttlPuUw</link>
      <description>Bitcoin climbed above $92,000 on Monday, signaling a potential shift in momentum as cryptocurrency markets shake off a difficult end to 2025 with renewed institutional interest and a surge in large-holder activity.

The world's largest cryptocurrency rose as much as 2.3% to $93,323 in early Asian trading, its highest level in three weeks, according to Bloomberg[1]. The rally pushed the total cryptocurrency market capitalization back above $3 trillion[2][3], marking a sharp reversal from the fourth quarter sell-off that saw Bitcoin fall roughly 35% from its October peak above $126,000[4][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--djWZjEwP--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/PIFUeAXchweNl.VUnJ8zBA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/decrypt_157/ed263d878990672315ba2a665fbb0664" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu vows to block Iran's missile program rebuild</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/netanyahu-vows-israel-will-not-FbrYTuqiTcWg3HhZLGb_og</link>
      <description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu declared Monday that Israel will not permit Iran to rebuild its ballistic missile industry, stating he and President Donald Trump are aligned on preventing Tehran from reconstituting weapons programs damaged during last year's conflict[1][1].

Speaking during a Knesset debate, Netanyahu said he and Trump "will not allow Iran to rebuild its ballistic missile industry, and we certainly won't let it renew its nuclear program," emphasizing their shared position that Iran must have zero enrichment capability[1][1]. The statement follows Netanyahu's late December meeting with Trump at Mar-a-Lago, where the two leaders discussed the possibility of launching additional strikes on Iran in 2026[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767628607/getty_uploads/2253970255_tiawh6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protests death toll hits 20 as crackdown enters ninth day</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-protests-enter-second-wee-KV46_hRbThi3pj22aJT2jw</link>
      <description>Nationwide demonstrations in Iran have entered a ninth consecutive day, with at least 20 protesters killed and nearly 1,000 arrested as what began as economic grievances has evolved into broader calls for regime change.

Unrest has been recorded at 222 locations across 78 cities in 26 provinces, according to the U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency[1][2][3]. The protests, initially sparked by Tehran bazaar merchants on December 28, have spread to universities and provincial cities, with demonstrators chanting "Death to the Dictator" and "Death to Khamenei"[4][5]. Security forces have responded with live ammunition, tear gas, and mass arrests, marking the largest demonstrations since the 2022 protests following Mahsa Amini's death[6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--SENUHeju--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/5472x3078%2B0%2B103/resize/1400/quality/100/format/jpeg/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fc8%252F1a%252Fe2564b484bd49e0d0fb79bd9284e%252Fap25363522315836.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump sets two-month timeline for Greenland as Denmark warns of NATO collapse</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-greenland-anne-QYrJ7VuPRgetT_eYY72UBA</link>
      <description>US President Donald Trump escalated threats to seize Greenland on Sunday, telling reporters aboard Air Force One that America "needs" the Danish territory for national security and setting a timeline of roughly two months to address the issue[1][2][3]. The declaration followed a military operation in Venezuela that captured President Nicolás Maduro, raising alarm that Greenland could be Trump's next target[4][5].

Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen delivered her strongest rebuke yet, stating that "it makes absolutely no sense to talk about the need for the United States to take over Greenland"[1][2]. According to Bloomberg, she warned that a US attack on the NATO ally would spell the end of the alliance itself[6]. "The US has no right to annex any of the three nations in the Danish kingdom," Frederiksen said, urging Washington to "stop the threats against a historically close ally"[7][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--s79PKcQ3--/t_thumbnail/https://d3i6fh83elv35t.cloudfront.net/static/2025/03/GettyImages-2203426391-768x500.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy cluster burns five times hotter than predicted</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-discover-unexpecte-Wc_5xRMQSzK1wDO2URtVSQ</link>
      <description>Astronomers have discovered a galaxy cluster blazing with gas at least five times hotter than predicted, just 1.4 billion years after the Big Bang, challenging fundamental assumptions about how these colossal cosmic structures form and evolve[1][2][3].

The finding, published in Nature on January 4, describes a cluster named SPT2349-56 whose gas temperatures exceed 10 million Kelvin—hotter and more energetic than many present-day galaxy clusters[1][2][4]. The discovery suggests that the birth of galaxy clusters is far more explosive than cosmologists previously believed, potentially requiring a rethink of galaxy cluster formation models[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--QVCpwhuo--/t_thumbnail/https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/02212909/SEI_279435215.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dollar hits two-week high after Maduro's capture</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-arrests-maduro-markets-reac-FGxtZzUWTgWI1mi7XdLhhg</link>
      <description>Financial markets displayed a measured reaction Monday as Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro arrived at a Manhattan federal courthouse to face drug trafficking charges, following his weekend capture by US special forces. The dollar strengthened to its highest level in two weeks while oil prices remained surprisingly stable, defying expectations of significant market turbulence.

The Bloomberg Dollar Spot Index climbed 0.3% to reach its strongest level since December 22, as the greenback outperformed nearly all major currencies[1][2]. The Mexican peso declined 0.7%, and the euro dropped 0.3%[2]. However, the overall market response suggested investors were treating the geopolitical shock as a contained event rather than a systemic crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--jxfb275l--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/rFe6uuwVItSh5Wc6QxCTjQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/d6aba55a89915ff351ba3a3bf045703c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro pleads not guilty in Manhattan court to narco-terrorism charges</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/maduro-pleads-not-guilty-in-ma-ooztd.n.R9eEWfpjzZAxdw</link>
      <description>Deposed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife Cilia Flores pleaded not guilty Monday to federal narco-terrorism and drug trafficking charges in their first court appearance since being captured by US forces two days earlier in Caracas.

"I am innocent. I am not guilty. I am a decent president of my country," Maduro declared when 92-year-old US District Judge Alvin Hellerstein asked for his plea during the noon hearing at Manhattan federal court[1][2]. The judge then interrupted him, stating, "A not guilty plea will be entered on behalf of Mr. Maduro."[1]

The couple faces charges including narco-terrorism conspiracy, cocaine importation conspiracy, and possession of machine guns and destructive devices[3][1]. If convicted, they could face life imprisonment[3][4]. Maduro has retained Barry Pollack, the Washington, DC-based attorney who secured WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's release in 2024[3][5]. Flores is represented by Texas lawyer Mark Donnelly[6].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767632840/getty_uploads/2254194837_zgjqkl.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheinbaum rejects Trump military threats after Venezuela raid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sheinbaum-rejects-trump-threat-sWfinrG0QpW1g3m6fZOqEA</link>
      <description>Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum firmly downplayed threats of U.S. military intervention in Mexico on Monday, following President Donald Trump's warnings that Washington might act against drug cartels operating south of the border. The dispute marks the latest escalation between the two leaders after Trump's weekend military operation captured Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro.

"I don't believe in an invasion; I don't think it's something they take seriously," Sheinbaum said during her first press conference since U.S. forces seized Maduro early Saturday morning[1][2]. The Mexican leader emphasized her rejection of any U.S. military presence in her country, stating that Mexico is collaborating with Washington on security but will not accept intervention[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--sv1RV_Cl--/t_thumbnail/https://images.axios.com/F2dZLUbptGauTGe2ueqKZ-_eL4g%3D/0x473:4536x3024/1366x768/2026/01/03/1767457758866.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI capabilities doubling every 8 months, UK safety institute finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/experts-warn-world-unprepared-pE5Ys7SESZWgez8HB5iJYg</link>
      <description>A leading AI safety researcher has cautioned that rapid advances in artificial intelligence may outpace humanity's ability to implement adequate safeguards, warning that society could be "sleepwalking" into an era where machines control critical infrastructure before proper oversight is established.

David Dalrymple, a program director at the UK's Advanced Research and Invention Agency, told The Guardian that the world "may not have time" to prepare for safety risks posed by cutting-edge AI systems[1][2][3][4]. His warnings come as new data from Britain's AI Security Institute reveals that AI capabilities are advancing at an exponential pace, with performance in certain domains doubling every eight months[5][6][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--EKGjs07y--/t_thumbnail/https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%252F2024-09-19%252Fidf4ebay%252Fai-71118021280.jpg%3Frect%3D0%252C14%252C1280%252C672%26w%3D1200%26auto%3Dformat%252Ccompress%26ogImage%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia unveils AI models, $3,000 desktop supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nvidia-ceo-huang-to-unveil-ai-oJmeEDlaRgO.T8DZFTobJg</link>
      <description>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang took the stage at the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas on Monday, unveiling new autonomous vehicle technology and a desktop AI supercomputer as the world's most valuable company confronts rising competition from rivals and its own customers.

In a 90-minute keynote, Huang announced Alpamayo, an open-source family of AI models designed to help autonomous vehicles navigate complex driving scenarios, and Project DIGITS, a $3,000 personal AI supercomputer set to launch in May[1][2]. The announcements come as Nvidia faces intensifying pressure from both chipmaking competitors like Advanced Micro Devices and customers including Alphabet and Meta Platforms that are developing their own AI chips[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Maxp4_Ey--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2025-11/2025-11-20T024308Z_1_LYNXMPELAJ03O_RTROPTP_4_NVIDIA-RESULTS-BUBBLE.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyundai to mass-produce Boston Dynamics Atlas robot</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hyundai-to-mass-produce-boston-DbNbUhuHRd6orYdkezDDhQ</link>
      <description>Hyundai Motor Group announced Monday at CES 2026 in Las Vegas that it will mass-produce Boston Dynamics' Atlas humanoid robot, with plans to manufacture 30,000 units annually by 2028 and deploy them across its manufacturing facilities[1][2][3][4].

The South Korean automaker revealed the production-ready version of Atlas during its keynote presentation, marking the first public demonstration of the all-electric humanoid robot outside of carefully edited videos[1][5]. The announcement signals a major shift in industrial automation, as one of the world's most advanced humanoid robots transitions from research prototype to commercial product.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--JLPo8PKs--/t_thumbnail/https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/YT-Pre-Launch-Thumbnail.jpg%3Fquality%3D90%26strip%3Dall%26crop%3D0%252C3.4613147178592%252C100%252C93.077370564282%26w%3D1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lula contacts Venezuela's interim leader after US captures Maduro</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/lula-speaks-with-venezuela-s-i-GRIct75fSsGyvMnOonmExA</link>
      <description>Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva spoke with Venezuela's interim President Delcy Rodriguez on Saturday, hours after a US military operation captured and removed Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro from power, according to Brazil's presidency[1][2][3].

Lula called Rodriguez to confirm media reports about the US military action that resulted in Maduro's detention, a Brazilian government source said[2][4][3]. The Brazilian presidency did not provide further details about the call, which marked one of the first high-level diplomatic contacts following the dramatic overnight operation[1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767652131/getty_uploads/2251924836_bngajm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, AMD CEOs unveil AI roadmaps as CES 2026 opens</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ces-2026-opens-with-ai-and-rob-sRTuki20QiCQNjt5uNF7HQ</link>
      <description>The annual Consumer Electronics Show opened Monday in Las Vegas with artificial intelligence and robotics dominating the event's first day, as Nvidia and AMD CEOs outlined their visions for AI's future while manufacturers unveiled a new generation of home robots designed to handle everyday household tasks.

Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang kicked off the show's keynote presentations at 1 p.m. PT, focusing on what he called the "Physical AI" era—artificial intelligence that can understand and operate in the real world[1][2][3][4]. The company unveiled Alpamayo, an open-source autonomous driving platform featuring a 10-billion parameter vision language action model designed to help self-driving cars reason through complex scenarios[2][3][4]. "The ChatGPT moment for physical AI is here, when machines begin to understand, reason and act in the real world," Huang said during his presentation[3][5].

Later Monday evening, AMD CEO Lisa Su took the stage at 6:30 p.m. PT to present her company's roadmap for delivering AI solutions "from cloud to enterprise, edge and devices"[6][7][8]. The keynote, held at the Palazzo Ballroom at the Venetian, highlighted AMD's position in the competitive AI chip market as the company works to challenge Nvidia's dominance[9][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MeB1pmYM--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2026-01/2026-01-05T220947Z_1_LYNXMPEM0416L_RTROPTP_4_TECH-CES-NVIDIA.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
