<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:38:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Global AI spending to surge 44% in 2026, Gartner forecasts</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/global-ai-spending-to-reach-3-frT4ZQ.GQfirWRig5gUmwA</link>
      <description>The artificial intelligence industry is on track for a historic year, with global spending projected to surge 44% to $2.53 trillion in 2026 before climbing to $3.33 trillion by 2027, according to new forecasts from Gartner released this week. The boom is simultaneously propelling semiconductor revenues past $1 trillion for the first time in the industry's history.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://g.foolcdn.com/image/?url=https%253A%252F%252Fg.foolcdn.com%252Feditorial%252Fimages%252F838892%252Fnvidia-voyager-headquarters.jpg&amp;w=1200&amp;op=resize" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's acting president proposes oil reforms to lure US investment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-s-rodriguez-seeks-oi-3qsHYGXxQsaYGSeljzr_pg</link>
      <description>Acting Venezuelan President Delcy Rodríguez has submitted a proposal to reform her country's hydrocarbon law, seeking to open doors to greater US investment in the oil-rich nation less than two weeks after US special forces captured former President Nicolás Maduro in a surprise military operation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rodríguez announced on Thursday that she was proposing the reforms to Venezuela's National Assembly, a move that addresses a key demand from major American oil companies who have described the country as "uninvestable" under current regulations. At her first press conference since Maduro's ouster, Rodríguez also declared Venezuela was entering a "new political era" marked by greater tolerance toward political rivals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768511210/getty_uploads/2256293841_zaopbf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil's Bolsonaro ordered transferred to maximum-security prison</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/bolsonaro-ordered-transferred-80_sKSCLQ8KzhBuFTw.TaQ</link>
      <description>Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered the transfer of former President Jair Bolsonaro to the Papuda Penitentiary Complex in Brasilia on Thursday, according to court documents released January 15, 2026. The move represents a stark shift in the conditions under which the 70-year-old far-right politician will serve his 27-year sentence for plotting a coup following his 2022 election defeat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bolsonaro has been detained at the Federal Police Superintendency since his arrest in late November 2025, housed in a 12-square-meter room equipped with a bed, private bathroom, air conditioning, television, and desk. Under the new order, he will be relocated to a building within the Papuda complex, Brazil's largest maximum-security penitentiary facility in the capital.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768512622/getty_uploads/2234877459_xx5kxq.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet's sunward jets baffle scientists</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/interstellar-comet-3iatlas-baf-UeUKFUMHQbqqRwRroBUJOw</link>
      <description>The third known interstellar object to visit our solar system continues to puzzle astronomers as it exits toward Jupiter, displaying sunward jets that defy conventional comet physics while yielding no detectable alien signals to radio telescopes scanning for signs of extraterrestrial technology.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Comet 3I/ATLAS, first spotted on July 1, 2025, by the NASA-funded ATLAS survey in Chile, has been the subject of intense scientific scrutiny since its discovery. With the Breakthrough Listen project confirming no technosignatures were detected during five hours of observation using the Green Bank Telescope on December 18, 2025, researchers have largely settled the question of whether this cosmic wanderer might be artificial.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We all would have been thrilled to find technosignatures coming from 3I/ATLAS, but they're just not there," Benjamin Jacobson-Bell from the University of California, Berkeley, told Space.com. "Finding no signals was the result we expected, due to the significant evidence for 3I/ATLAS being a comet with only natural features."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d1rldr9jdodfaa.cloudfront.net/images/01KCBFR8ZZ5921Q9SH2DFHJJ2Q/a68a0c35-9588-4296-ad79-ef131d82467e_1765617181.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMF awaits shareholder backing before aiding Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/imf-awaits-shareholder-recogni-uTgzyWRhTe6gSTIgonLiwg</link>
      <description>The International Monetary Fund stands ready to support Venezuela, but must first receive backing from its major shareholders to recognize the country's post-Maduro leadership before any assistance can flow, Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva said Thursday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If there is an opportunity to support the people of Venezuela, you can be sure the Fund will be there," Georgieva told Reuters during a visit to Ukraine. The remarks came nearly two weeks after U.S. forces removed former President Nicolás Maduro in a January 3 military operation, leaving acting President Delcy Rodríguez to navigate the country's economic turmoil.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://preview.thenewsmarket.com/Previews/IMFO/VideoAssets/1920x1080/IMFO_54923_693582_v3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists map hidden landscape beneath Antarctica's ice</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-unveil-detailed-map-D0.jRWgyR6umyQUa4pQbgQ</link>
      <description>A team of international scientists has produced the most comprehensive map yet of Antarctica's concealed terrain, revealing thousands of previously unknown hills, ridges, and river channels buried beneath miles of ice. The breakthrough, published Thursday in the journal Science, could transform researchers' ability to predict how the frozen continent will respond to climate change and contribute to rising sea levels.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The map uncovers geological features spanning 2 to 30 kilometers beneath the ice sheet, which covers more than 5.4 million square miles. Among the discoveries are deep alpine valleys, extensive channels carved by ancient flowing water that stretch for hundreds of kilometers, and sharp transitions between highland and lowland terrain that may indicate tectonic boundaries.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zrdwMQv5GKotVK6JHozwGi-1600-80.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese universities claim 8 of top 10 spots in global research rankings</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-universities-overtake-kfXdUHTRRRuMGXqeL5o6vA</link>
      <description>Zhejiang University has claimed the top spot in the Leiden Rankings, a global measure of research productivity, pushing Harvard to third place and marking a shift in academic power that reflects both China's strategic investments in science and the mounting financial pressures facing American higher education.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The rankings, produced by the Centre for Science and Technology Studies at Leiden University in the Netherlands, now feature eight Chinese institutions in the top 10. Twenty years ago, only one Chinese school would have made the top 25.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://img2.chinadaily.com.cn/images/202510/24/68fb2feaa310f735017f66cc.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump announces 'Board of Peace' to oversee Gaza governance</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-formation-of-g-V7.67.UuRC6JC7MIynN5LQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump announced Thursday that the "Board of Peace" for Gaza has been officially formed, moving forward with the second phase of his 20-point plan to end the conflict in the Palestinian territory. The announcement came via his Truth Social platform, one day after his special envoy Steve Witkoff declared the launch of the plan's next stage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It is my Great Honor to announce that THE BOARD OF PEACE has been formed," Trump wrote, adding that the body's members would be revealed "shortly." He called it "the Greatest and Most Prestigious Board ever assembled at any time, any place."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/72RIUXQYOVPGJNQPHYJYWBGBOE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Einstein's wormholes may be time bridges, not space tunnels</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/new-research-reinterprets-worm-VkwZuU9hTYKcJNvizcHPsg</link>
      <description>Wormholes, long imagined as cosmic tunnels for interstellar travel and time machines, may not exist as shortcuts through space at all. Instead, new research suggests that Einstein-Rosen bridges—the mathematical structures behind the wormhole concept—represent something more fundamental: connections between two opposing directions of time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A paper published this week in the journal Classical and Quantum Gravity by astrophysicist Enrique Gaztañaga and colleagues presents a reinterpretation of the original 1935 work by Albert Einstein and Nathan Rosen. The researchers argue that the popular conception of wormholes arose from a misunderstanding of what the physicists intended.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/en/the_conversation_464/564d1607573689b91047c8cbfe4ca4de" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli startup nT-Tao fires first plasma in compact fusion reactor</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nt-tao-c3-fusion-prototype-ach-rEZJrCgGSF.AwkUb0qKZWw</link>
      <description>Israeli compact fusion energy company nT-Tao announced on January 15, 2026 that its C3 prototype has successfully fired its first plasma pulses, reaching operational status just over two months after assembly began. The milestone represents a concrete advancement in the company's pursuit of a container-sized fusion reactor capable of generating 10-20 MW of clean power.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Hod Hasharon-based startup's C3 system builds directly upon the successful experimental campaign of its predecessor, the C2-A, which achieved plasma temperatures of approximately one million degrees Celsius—roughly 100 electron volts—at the intended high-density regime. The new prototype incorporates design refinements across magnets, pulsed power systems, diagnostics, and overall integration, with experimental goals focused on reaching higher temperatures and extended confinement durations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/lo/mysterio/api/2FBF7BD88CB836199EDF5DAE3192554FA1DB3B7DBB52986A09D43AB194B6BC5B/subgraphmysterio/resizefit_w1200%3Bquality_90%3Bformat_webp/https:%252F%252Fs.yimg.com%252Fos%252Fen%252Finteresting_engineering_646%252F9d4294ed9233832bf20f2048915eea74" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's acting president calls for oil reforms, US thaw</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-s-new-leader-seeks-o-cg7.sL0HT8iHnxo_bgHGrQ</link>
      <description>Less than two weeks after the United States military captured Nicolás Maduro, Venezuela's acting president used her first major address to lawmakers to call for sweeping reforms to the country's oil industry and a diplomatic thaw with Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a 44-minute state of the union speech on Thursday, Delcy Rodríguez urged Venezuela's National Assembly to approve changes to the nation's hydrocarbon law that would open doors to greater foreign investment in the state-controlled oil sector. The address marked a striking departure from the anti-American rhetoric that defined her predecessor's rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4HV2AFG5QVKOTLUHQAUKOLQRSI.jpg?auth=9cb8a23b74e72ea1f9eddd8becb2464c255bdd3a9ff113663f4d0b0d79ca182f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT team cools trapped ions 10 times below standard limit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-uncover-new-quantum-JDj0suPnTSKZI6Vk69Wafw</link>
      <description>Two separate research efforts published this week are advancing the frontiers of quantum computing by solving distinct challenges: achieving efficient cooling for chip-based systems and discovering unexpected quantum states in exotic materials.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers at MIT and MIT Lincoln Laboratory announced Wednesday a technique for cooling trapped ions using integrated photonics that reaches temperatures about 10 times below the standard laser cooling limit, known as the Doppler limit. The method achieves this in approximately 100 microseconds, several times faster than existing approaches.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Meanwhile, scientists at TU Wien in Vienna and Rice University revealed Tuesday in Nature Physics that they observed an "emergent topological semimetal" — a quantum state previously considered impossible because it combines two phenomena thought to be incompatible.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://qci.dlr.de/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2025-10-01-Keyvisual-840-Toccata.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN High Seas Treaty to take effect, protecting two-thirds of ocean</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-high-seas-treaty-takes-effe-qCgiZpOuSLS_2oeZL0.h5A</link>
      <description>The United Nations High Seas Treaty, formally known as the Biodiversity Beyond National Jurisdiction (BBNJ) Agreement, will officially enter into force on January 17, 2026, establishing the first legally binding international framework to protect marine biodiversity in nearly two-thirds of the world's ocean.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The treaty becomes international law after Morocco became the 60th nation to ratify it on September 19, 2025, triggering a 120-day countdown to implementation. Currently, 82 countries have officially joined the agreement, and 145 of the UN's 193 member states have signed it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://marine-conservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/ocean-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver coating makes solid-state batteries 5 times crack-resistant</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/stanford-strengthens-solid-ele-KF6SdoQ5Q9Kjos7fECqPUg</link>
      <description>A team of Stanford researchers has discovered that applying an ultrathin coating of silver to solid electrolytes makes them nearly five times more resistant to cracking, addressing one of the most persistent obstacles to commercializing next-generation lithium metal batteries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published January 16 in Nature Materials, could accelerate development of batteries that are safer, store more energy, and charge faster than today's lithium-ion technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://fordauthority.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/SK-On-Oxide-Based-Solid-Electrolyte-Solid-State-Battery-002.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan shares surge to record after US finalizes trade deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-markets-mixed-as-taiwan-B7AVd0YdSfm2TgDNofF_AQ</link>
      <description>Asian markets finished Friday with divergent outcomes as Taiwan led regional gains, surging nearly 2 percent to a record close after the United States and Taiwan finalized a semiconductor-focused trade agreement the day before.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Taiwan Weighted Index climbed 1.94 percent to close at a record 31,408.7, making it the best-performing Asian market on Friday. The rally came after Washington and Taipei announced a deal on Thursday that will reduce tariffs on Taiwanese goods from 20 percent to 15 percent while securing commitments from Taiwanese chip and technology companies to invest at least $250 billion in U.S. production capacity.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/5D573OOWGJIT7HXTZ5JI6JFCI4.jpg?auth=a105645deb11d15375a741a1501ce152c1a9a90dc2b5a048a4b33b2d75bd48b0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers discover massive iron bar hiding inside Ring Nebula</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-find-massive-iron-Li1iU6IdRXidQMH83bX.9Q</link>
      <description>A European team has discovered a hidden bar of iron stretching across the interior of the Ring Nebula, one of the most iconic objects in the night sky. The structure, described for the first time this week in Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, contains a mass of iron atoms comparable to Mars and had gone completely unnoticed despite decades of observations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discovery raises a puzzle that astronomers cannot yet solve: how did such a large concentration of iron end up in such a distinct shape inside a nebula formed from a dying star?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/230804122801-james-webb-space-telescope-ring-nebula.jpg?c=original" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's giant telescope captures first clear evidence of fast radio burst origins</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-telescope-reveals-cause-GCUr10_oS_uexolz3_zOrA</link>
      <description>Using the world's largest single-dish radio telescope, an international team of researchers has captured the first clear evidence linking mysterious cosmic radio signals to a dense plasma cloud, providing strong support for the theory that some fast radio bursts originate from binary star systems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published Friday in the journal Science, are based on nearly 20 months of observations by China's Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope, known as FAST, of a repeating fast radio burst designated FRB 20220529, located approximately 2.9 billion light-years from Earth.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.globaltimes.cn/Portals/0/attachment/2022/2022-08-01/5e357d6b-91fc-4306-aba0-d5d7fd55f097.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS spins every 7 hours, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-interstellar-object-ro-xOgCoCYuS.2wVj2cJkHhGQ</link>
      <description>The interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS completes a full rotation approximately every 7.1 hours, according to new research by Harvard astrophysicist Abraham Loeb and Italian astronomer Toni Scarmato. The findings arrive just days before a rare celestial alignment on January 22 that could provide unprecedented data about this cosmic traveler from beyond our solar system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, which analyzed Hubble Space Telescope images from late 2025, used two independent methods to determine the rotation period: tracking the wobble of the comet's jet-like features and measuring brightness variations over time. The jet position angle analysis yielded a period of 7.20 ± 0.05 hours, while photometric measurements produced 7.136 ± 0.001 hours.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://sm.mashable.com/mashable_me/seo/default/untitled-2026-01-16t122549001_dqw2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS makes final pass before leaving solar system</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/comet-3iatlas-makes-final-pass-bx8rCRtnT4eVGTGXPtYuNg</link>
      <description>The interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS, only the third object from beyond our solar system ever detected passing through our cosmic neighborhood, is making its final observable appearance before vanishing into the void. The Virtual Telescope Project is hosting a farewell livestream today at 21:00 UTC to mark humanity's last opportunity to view the celestial visitor.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zT58SVFsEFhx8fytDdVCPd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada and China strike trade deal on EVs, canola amid US tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canada-and-china-forge-new-str-PUW0WR_iR3GMkdJuV08EWA</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney and Chinese President Xi Jinping announced a landmark trade agreement on Friday in Beijing, with Canada agreeing to slash tariffs on Chinese electric vehicles in exchange for China reducing duties on Canadian agricultural products, marking a dramatic shift in Ottawa's trade policy away from the United States.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Under the deal, Canada will allow up to 49,000 Chinese EVs into the country at a 6.1% tariff rate, replacing the 100% duty imposed by former Prime Minister Justin Trudeau in 2024. The quota will increase to 70,000 vehicles over five years. In return, China will lower tariffs on Canadian canola seed from approximately 84% to 15% by March 1, according to statements from both governments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/reuters_6969e91c-1768548636.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
