<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 04:10:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>At least 39 killed in Spain's deadliest train crash in over a decade</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spain-train-crash-kills-at-lea-D8RrlAypT_GUzH1i0XHY7g</link>
      <description>At least 39 people were killed and more than 150 injured after two high-speed trains collided Sunday evening in southern Spain, in the country's deadliest rail disaster in more than a decade. Authorities warned on Monday that the death toll could rise as cranes began lifting mangled carriages from the wreckage near the town of Adamuz.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crash occurred around 7:45 PM local time when the rear carriages of an Iryo train traveling from Málaga to Madrid derailed and crossed onto an adjacent track, slamming into an oncoming Renfe Alvia service headed from Madrid to Huelva. The Renfe train's first two carriages tumbled down a four-meter embankment, sustaining the most severe damage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/3S4UV53UDJNOTLPWEPFMIB7VXQ.jpg?auth=c94786562326648302295905bc24637482feff568078da348ef827763a5a0a86&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU weighs first use of 'trade bazooka' against Trump tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-prepares-retaliatory-measur-DBKYMqleTqmKtQrOAeAPow</link>
      <description>European Union leaders are mobilizing an unprecedented response to President Donald Trump's threat of escalating tariffs on nations opposing his campaign to acquire Greenland, with officials considering activating the bloc's most powerful trade weapon for the first time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;EU ambassadors from all 27 member states convened an emergency meeting in Brussels on Sunday, where the European Commission presented multiple countermeasures, including reactivating a €93 billion retaliatory tariff package and deploying the Anti-Coercion Instrument, a mechanism adopted in 2023 but never triggered.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108253936-1768812919028-gettyimages-2256239146-berg-greenlan260117_npf6x.jpeg?v=1768812948&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin invited to join Trump's 'Board of Peace' as 60 nations weigh membership</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-invites-putin-and-60-nat-UmcTaQqhT2KgG_YPcduJaw</link>
      <description>The Kremlin announced Monday that Russian President Vladimir Putin has received an invitation to join U.S. President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace," with Moscow saying it is studying the proposal and hopes for further contacts with Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The invitation to Putin comes as Trump has dispatched letters to approximately 60 world leaders asking them to become founding members of the new international body, which he will chair for life. Initially conceived to oversee governance and reconstruction in post-war Gaza, the board's draft charter indicates aspirations for a broader mandate addressing global conflicts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2025/08/putin-peace-talks.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers breach Iran state TV to air exiled prince's protest call</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-state-television-hacked-t-_5CrKF10T4K_MELDK6dAdg</link>
      <description>Hackers breached Iran's state television network on Sunday, hijacking broadcasts for approximately 10 minutes to air anti-regime messages and an address from exiled Crown Prince Reza Pahlavi calling on Iranians to continue their protests against the Islamic Republic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The cyberattack targeted Iran's Badr satellite, which transmits several state-run provincial channels nationwide, allowing opposition footage to reach millions of homes across the country during prime evening viewing hours. According to Israel's public broadcaster KAN News, the hacked broadcast aired around 9:30 p.m. local time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/en/thewrap.com/f69dce9a84a4cf1dd0fa1c41d8192252" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz urges restraint as France pushes for EU trade retaliation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/merz-seeks-to-restrain-macron-xqhk3rUTTdKsdNkMLtlD6g</link>
      <description>Chancellor Friedrich Merz signaled on Sunday that Germany prefers a measured response to President Donald Trump's threat of escalating tariffs over Greenland, putting Berlin on a different track than Paris as Europe's two largest economies grapple with how to handle the unprecedented American demands.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Merz said Germany and its European partners have agreed "that we want to avoid any escalation in this dispute if at all possible," according to his remarks in Berlin on Monday. While French President Emmanuel Macron has formally requested activation of the European Union's most powerful trade weapon—the anti-coercion instrument, often called the EU's "trade bazooka"—Merz indicated Germany would support such measures only "if necessary."</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768840961/getty_uploads/2257055960_sbjaqa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia posts record budget deficit as oil revenues collapse</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/russia-posts-record-budget-def-FWK7EpnZQz6FBki.KzUETw</link>
      <description>Russia recorded a federal budget deficit of 5.645 trillion rubles ($72.3 billion) in 2025, the largest since at least 1996, according to data released by the Finance Ministry on Sunday. The shortfall more than doubled from 3.47 trillion rubles the previous year, exposing the mounting fiscal strain of nearly three years of war in Ukraine.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The record gap came despite aggressive spending cuts in December, when expenditures fell 19% from a year earlier as the government moved to keep the deficit within its revised target of 2.6% of GDP. Finance Minister Anton Siluanov confirmed the target was met in an interview with Interfax last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/DBIWNL6RGRJH7O4TZG5RCJFJQU.jpg?auth=da630f786f36686c179fee256f9fab418cbe97e14997e8e5c9098aad465c9955&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hotel explosion in Kabul kills at least 7, injures Chinese nationals</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/deadly-blast-in-kabul-hotel-ki-2JwcEFUlRHS_m7MuSIVvjQ</link>
      <description>A powerful explosion tore through a hotel in central Kabul on Monday, killing at least seven people and injuring 13 others, according to officials and a hospital that treated casualties. The blast struck the heavily guarded Shahr-e-Naw district, considered one of the safest neighborhoods in the Afghan capital.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Italian NGO EMERGENCY, which operates a surgical center in Kabul, confirmed receiving at least 20 patients from the incident, including women and children. The organization reported seven deaths from the explosion that occurred at a hotel on Gulfaroshi Street in the capital's fourth district.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://harici.com.tr/en/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/llllllllllllllll.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan's PM Takaichi calls snap election for February 8</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/japan-pm-takaichi-calls-snap-e-Hi9DoPMIRoif8xuhCxeEZg</link>
      <description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi announced Monday that she will dissolve parliament on Friday and hold a snap general election on February 8, just three months after becoming the country's first female leader. The move sets the stage for a high-stakes campaign as Takaichi seeks a stronger mandate to advance her fiscal policies and hardline security stance amid escalating tensions with China.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I want the public to decide whether Sanae Takaichi is suitable as prime minister," she told reporters at a press conference in Tokyo. Official campaigning will begin on January 27, with only 16 days between the dissolution and voting day, the shortest such period since the end of World War II.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/19/multimedia/19int-japan-election-01-jmzh/19int-japan-election-01-jmzh-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prince Harry's privacy trial against Daily Mail begins in London</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/prince-harry-daily-mail-privac-nEgOHnatSnWO4RfA5rukDw</link>
      <description>Prince Harry arrived at London's High Court on Monday, waving to reporters and saying "good morning" as he entered via a side entrance for the start of what his legal team calls the "final chapter" of his crusade against British tabloid media. The Duke of Sussex, 41, sat in the back row of the courtroom alongside actresses Elizabeth Hurley and Sadie Frost as his barrister, David Sherborne, alleged the Daily Mail and Mail on Sunday engaged in "clear, systematic and sustained use of unlawful information gathering" spanning two decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The civil trial, expected to last nine weeks, sees Harry and six other high-profile claimants accusing Associated Newspapers Limited of illegal practices including phone hacking, hiring private investigators to plant listening devices in homes and cars, and obtaining medical and financial records through deception—a practice known as "blagging". The publisher has "vigorously denied" all allegations, calling them "preposterous smears" and part of a "coordinated effort" against the media.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://variety.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/prince-harry.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=667&amp;crop=1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France rejects Trump's Gaza Board of Peace, citing UN concerns</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/france-declines-trump-s-gaza-b-iRgGG6qzQ1qUmYh57Gw1iA</link>
      <description>France will not accept an invitation to join President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace" initiative aimed at overseeing Gaza's governance, according to a source close to President Emmanuel Macron. The announcement comes as the French government simultaneously pursues its own path of engagement in the region, dispatching nearly 400 tons of humanitarian aid to the war-ravaged territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.elysee.fr/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto%252Cquality=100%252Cwidth=800%252Cheight=420%252Ctrim=274%253B0%253B29%253B0%252Cfit=cover/images/default/0001/18/a1520042f300e92a96f1c37cd6aee79403d2c528.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italian PM Meloni offers to mediate US-Europe standoff over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/meloni-offers-to-mediate-betwe-mwPEa6hlQ52SmAK.UFbp5w</link>
      <description>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni positioned herself as a potential bridge between Washington and European capitals on Sunday, calling President Donald Trump's tariff threats over Greenland "a mistake" while suggesting the crisis stemmed from a "communication breakdown" rather than fundamental disagreement among allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking during a visit to Seoul on January 18, Meloni disclosed that she had spoken directly with Trump "a few hours ago" and conveyed her concerns about the escalating tensions. "There has been a problem of understanding and communication," she told reporters, arguing that European military deployments to Greenland were misinterpreted as anti-American when they were actually intended to deter "other actors" — a reference to Russia and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iZEM9UMjuRDk/v1/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German Chancellor Merz seeks Trump meeting at Davos over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/german-chancellor-merz-seeks-t-sgyePYIlQsOYSN5ZTvt5NA</link>
      <description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz announced Monday he will attempt to meet with President Donald Trump at the World Economic Forum in Davos this week to defuse escalating tensions over Greenland, as Europe prepares potential countermeasures against threatened U.S. tariffs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking at a press conference in Berlin, Merz said European nations that expressed solidarity with Denmark want to prevent the dispute from spiraling further. "We will have the opportunity this week in Davos to discuss this in various meetings. I will try to meet with President Trump on Wednesday," Merz said. Trump is scheduled to deliver a special address at the forum on January 21.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.bgnes.com/static/images/news/2026/01/19/16440/1280X720-15147.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump to meet with global CEOs after Davos keynote address</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-to-meet-global-ceos-at-2-2xsn8SLCQveGVXZS5BWE8A</link>
      <description>Business executives attending this week's World Economic Forum received an unexpected invitation on Monday: President Donald Trump wants to meet with them after his Wednesday keynote address in Davos, Switzerland.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The U.S. president plans to convene a group of corporate executives following his speech at the forum, according to Reuters and Semafor, though the agenda remains unclear. The invitations, which originated from the White House, sent corporate staffers scrambling to rework schedules that had been months in the making.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/OWWQ7U7VOFLQBJPNGSMAINWUC4.jpg?auth=4afe85d964f8d233f56aee32fd27df27581023b728034f58145d353a9bb1cb9b&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark deploys combat troops to Greenland amid Trump threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/denmark-deploys-substantial-tr-ZO5hBrBhRSa5ec9F.ongLg</link>
      <description>Denmark is deploying a substantial contingent of combat soldiers to Greenland on Monday evening, with Army Chief Major General Peter Boysen accompanying the forces as Copenhagen reinforces its Arctic presence in the face of escalating pressure from U.S. President Donald Trump to acquire the self-governing territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Danish Armed Forces confirmed to broadcaster TV 2 that the additional troops are scheduled to arrive in Kangerlussuaq, describing the deployment as "a substantial contribution." Around 100 Danish soldiers had already arrived in Nuuk, Greenland's capital, with a similar number stationed in Kangerlussuaq before the latest reinforcement.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768856395/getty_uploads/2256362000_wfiahq.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark, Greenland propose NATO Arctic surveillance mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/denmark-and-greenland-propose-4hC1fdczRViHoVye5aIMJA</link>
      <description>Denmark and Greenland have formally proposed establishing a NATO surveillance mission in the Arctic, Danish Defence Minister Troels Lund Poulsen announced Monday after meeting with NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte in Brussels. The proposal marks an attempt to address escalating transatlantic tensions sparked by U.S. President Donald Trump's push to acquire the strategically located island.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We have proposed it, the secretary general has taken note of that, and I think we can now—we hope—define a framework on how that can be concretised," Poulsen told Danish television following the meeting, which also included Greenlandic Foreign Minister Vivian Motzfeldt.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768851337/getty_uploads/2256362066_m21ttx.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland dispute could suck oxygen from Davos talks, Stubb says</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/greenland-dispute-could-suck-o-00XWuVBRQuqYCPauvdIhFQ</link>
      <description>Finnish President Alexander Stubb voiced concerns on Monday that escalating tensions over Greenland will "suck out all the oxygen" at this week's World Economic Forum in Davos, potentially sidelining critical discussions about ending Russia's war in Ukraine and securing the country's reconstruction.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We are doing everything we can to avoid that," Stubb told reporters in Davos on Monday, adding that "for Ukraine, the best that can come out of Davos is some kind of an agreement on an economic plan or reconstruction".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The warning comes as the 56th World Economic Forum opened January 19 under the theme "A Spirit of Dialogue," with nearly 3,000 participants from more than 130 countries, including approximately 65 heads of state and six G7 leaders. Yet the gathering has been upended by President Donald Trump's threat to impose escalating tariffs on European allies unless they acquiesce to American acquisition of Greenland.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://elyria-media.mynews360.com/image/418622/2/0/10/0/95" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump, China's He Lifeng court CEOs at Davos amid trade tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-and-chinese-officials-co-UDMnQSGhQyqiKeUGjhPMDQ</link>
      <description>As more than 850 chief executives gather in the Swiss Alps for the World Economic Forum, both the United States and China are competing for their attention, with President Donald Trump and Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng scheduling separate meetings with global business leaders amid renewed trade talks and escalating geopolitical tensions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump plans to convene a group of corporate executives Wednesday evening following his anticipated speech at the forum, according to Semafor and Reuters. The invitations, sent from the White House, caught some executives off guard Monday, forcing corporate staffers to scramble to rework schedules that had been months in the making.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PPMGAS5XHVJ7DIIDKU4ILXHI4E.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists predict 2026 will extend streak of record global heat</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/2025-and-2026-among-hottest-ye-K0YnV2vVRe.USbOap1zkSg</link>
      <description>The World Meteorological Organization confirmed this week that 2025 was among the three warmest years on record, while Canadian and European climate scientists predict 2026 will extend an unprecedented streak of extreme global heat that shows no signs of abating.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The global average surface temperature in 2025 reached 1.44°C above pre-industrial levels, according to the WMO's consolidated analysis of eight international datasets, placing it effectively tied with 2023 and trailing only 2024, which remains the hottest year on record at 1.55°C above the 1850-1900 baseline.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 23:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/D1vLX7WIjGRap6L7Q1O8VQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04NDU-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/cp_finance_889/c924d1f1f8ba9656a2bba9a99dd8d9e7" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1,500 ISIS prisoners escape Syrian facility as ceasefire collapses</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/1500-isis-prisoners-escape-syr-c7RVF2viQ3eSl160q8RtAA</link>
      <description>Approximately 1,500 Islamic State members escaped from Shaddadi prison in northeastern Syria on Monday, according to the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces, as a ceasefire deal between Kurdish fighters and the Damascus government appeared to collapse just one day after it was announced.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;SDF spokesperson Farhad Shami told the Kurdish website Rudaw that the mass prison break occurred after "Damascus factions" launched repeated attacks on the facility, which held thousands of ISIS detainees. The Syrian army denied attacking the prison and instead accused the SDF of deliberately releasing the militants. By Monday evening, Syrian officials said they had regained control of both the city and the prison, and imposed a curfew while troops searched for escapees.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/afp_696e6fa76174-1768845223.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experts warn Iran's nuclear stockpile at risk amid unrest</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/analysts-warn-iran-crisis-rais-0LAn3Z9FTgeAD.rzYES9jA</link>
      <description>As the United States and Iran trade escalating threats amid Tehran's bloody crackdown on protesters, nuclear experts are sounding alarms about the potential for Iran's nuclear materials to fall into the wrong hands during a period of internal chaos.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The warning, detailed in a report by the Associated Press, comes as the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) has acknowledged losing visibility over Iran's stockpile of highly enriched uranium following U.S. and Israeli airstrikes on nuclear facilities last June.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://ynet-pic1.yit.co.il/picserver5/wcm_upload/2024/04/18/S1aA75AlR/ap2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
