<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:41:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Two trains collide in Spain, killing at least 21</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spain-train-crash-kills-21-in-QLAfyx4OTze_otHnVJEOZA</link>
      <description>At least 21 people were killed and up to 100 injured when two high-speed trains collided in southern Spain on Sunday evening after one derailed and crossed into the path of an oncoming service, prompting authorities to suspend all rail traffic between Madrid and the Andalusia region.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crash occurred at approximately 6:40 p.m. local time near the town of Adamuz in Córdoba province when an Iryo train traveling from Málaga to Madrid derailed and struck a Renfe train heading from Madrid to Huelva, according to Spanish rail network operator Adif. Both trains were carrying hundreds of passengers—roughly 300 on the Iryo service and around 100 to 200 on the Renfe train.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spain's Transport Minister Óscar Puente confirmed the death toll after midnight, stating that all survivors had been rescued from the wreckage. Among those killed was the driver of the Renfe train, according to state broadcaster Televisión Española. Officials said 25 of the injured sustained serious wounds, with 73 passengers transported to six different hospitals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamereactor.eu/media/61/_4786153b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU holds off on trade 'bazooka' as Trump tariffs loom</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-prepares-response-to-trump-6arEsVIZRmO_MBwHFDFkow</link>
      <description>The European Union is weighing tariffs on up to €93 billion ($108 billion) worth of American goods and considering unprecedented trade countermeasures after President Donald Trump threatened to impose a 10% levy on eight European countries unless Washington is allowed to purchase Greenland.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;EU ambassadors from all 27 member states convened for an emergency meeting in Brussels on Sunday following Trump's announcement on Saturday that tariffs would take effect February 1 on Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, and Finland. The president warned the rate would rise to 25% by June 1 unless a deal is reached for the "Complete and Total purchase of Greenland."</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/5743x3230%2B0%2B31/resize/1400/quality/85/format/jpeg/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fb9%252F2e%252F542206b94db6865f90820f05eac2%252Fap25353099211791.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excitons outperform light for engineering quantum materials</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/excitons-enable-efficient-quan-8J676c_6QuKownQbJR_FMA</link>
      <description>A breakthrough in Floquet engineering demonstrates that excitons—quasiparticles formed within semiconductors—can modify material properties far more efficiently than light alone, potentially opening a new path to creating quantum materials on demand.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers from the Okinawa Institute of Science and Technology (OIST) and Stanford University have shown that exciton-driven Floquet effects in monolayer semiconductors are two orders of magnitude stronger and last longer than effects achieved with conventional light-based methods, according to findings published in Nature Physics on January 18, 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/IE-photo-ratio-19201080-21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMF raises growth forecasts for India and Nigeria in 2026 outlook</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/imf-and-world-bank-raise-growt-Tzgp9yTfRveq_Jv6Xr.nCQ</link>
      <description>The International Monetary Fund on Monday upgraded economic growth forecasts for both India and Nigeria, positioning them among the strongest performers in their respective regions as global growth remains steady despite lingering trade tensions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In its January 2026 World Economic Outlook update, the IMF raised India's FY26 growth estimate by 0.7 percentage points to 7.3%, citing a "better-than-expected outturn in the third quarter" and strong momentum heading into the final months of the fiscal year. The Fund expects growth to moderate to 6.4% in both 2026 and 2027 "as cyclical and temporary factors wane".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nigeria's 2026 growth outlook was raised to 4.4% from 4.2% projected in October, with the IMF citing improved macroeconomic stability and the government's ongoing reform efforts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/E6THMUTMG5JWXA74EY2LSSO3NA.jpg?auth=8120968d2cb163c5f9af2d9bf7e333ac6e602f34b708c6de1fdee774372ba159&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens tariffs on eight nations over bid to buy Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-tariffs-over-g-wWYYt3fcT7eDbP_3bsAm5Q</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's threat to impose escalating tariffs on eight European nations until the U.S. is allowed to buy Greenland has roiled global markets, sent gold and silver to record highs, and prompted European leaders to consider unprecedented countermeasures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump announced Saturday that he would levy a 10% tariff on goods from Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the Netherlands, Finland, and the United Kingdom starting February 1, rising to 25% by June 1 unless an agreement is reached for the "complete and total purchase of Greenland."</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AP26017638904066-1-1768808767.jpg?resize=770%252C513&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump cites Nobel snub to justify Greenland demand in letter</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-links-greenland-push-to-aCDzPtDTTRyayqNHPx858w</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has told Norwegian Prime Minister Jonas Gahr Støre that he "no longer feels an obligation to think purely of peace" after being denied the Nobel Peace Prize, using the perceived slight to justify his demand for American control over Greenland in a letter that has sent shockwaves through transatlantic relations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The letter, first reported by PBS journalist Nick Schifrin on Sunday and confirmed by multiple outlets including Bloomberg and Reuters, was shared by Trump's National Security Council with several European ambassadors in Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/KCDOH4LXLFOHNPFKV7ZFIP3GZE.jpg?auth=0958fed0e0e78c83c0372640dee4565c4a803ed719b177391166bcf04ed7506f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's birth rate hits record low as population shrinks again</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-s-birth-rate-plunges-to-PsVu0M.CRGWoPMxWVzRg5g</link>
      <description>China recorded its lowest birth rate since the founding of the People's Republic in 1949, with just 7.92 million babies born in 2025, according to official data released Monday by the National Bureau of Statistics. The figure represents a 17% decline from the 9.54 million births recorded in 2024, dashing hopes that a modest uptick last year signaled a reversal of the country's deepening demographic crisis.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The birth rate fell to 5.63 births per 1,000 people, marking the lowest level in more than seven decades of record-keeping. Meanwhile, deaths climbed to 11.31 million, the highest mortality rate since 1968, resulting in a net population decline of 3.39 million. China's total population now stands at 1.405 billion, shrinking for the fourth consecutive year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108253907-1768797042153-gettyimages-2254332899-vcg111612870235.jpeg?v=1768797238&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian researchers build motor powered by liquid metal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/unsw-researchers-unveil-first-jWrIqoeWS4e774kWnTEfVg</link>
      <description>Researchers at the University of New South Wales have developed a motor that operates using a droplet of liquid metal instead of traditional rigid components—a breakthrough that could reshape the future of soft robotics, flexible electronics, and medical devices.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The tiny device, called a liquid metal droplet rotary paddle motor, generates motion through swirling flows inside a liquid metal droplet embedded in a salt solution and exposed to an electric field. A small copper paddle placed within the swirling metal is carried along by these internal flows, creating rotation at speeds of up to 320 revolutions per minute.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"This is a completely new way to create motion," said Dr Priyank Kumar, a UNSW Senior Lecturer who supervised the project and served as the corresponding author on a paper published in npj Flexible Electronics. "We're harnessing the flow of liquid metal itself to produce rotation, without any traditional moving parts. It's simple, compact, and inherently flexible".</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.uow.edu.au/assets/media-centre/Xiaolin-Wang.pdj.05.08.15.002-1920x1080.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI says revenue hit $20 billion in 2025, up 233% from prior year</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-revenue-reaches-20-bill-feuwH2T6SnSa2hEf.hgAZQ</link>
      <description>OpenAI's annualized revenue surpassed $20 billion in 2025, marking a 233% increase from the previous year, the company announced Sunday. The milestone underscores explosive demand for AI services even as the company confronts mounting competitive pressure from Anthropic and Google.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"This is growth on a scale never seen before," Chief Financial Officer Sarah Friar wrote in a blog post detailing the figures. The company's revenue climbed from $2 billion in 2023 to $6 billion in 2024 before reaching the $20 billion mark—roughly a tenfold increase in just two years.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108074841-1733965530853-gettyimages-2188251582-mc_16795_qpk84voo.jpeg?v=1768570902&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At least 39 killed in Spain's deadliest train crash in over a decade</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spain-train-crash-kills-at-lea-D8RrlAypT_GUzH1i0XHY7g</link>
      <description>At least 39 people were killed and more than 150 injured after two high-speed trains collided Sunday evening in southern Spain, in the country's deadliest rail disaster in more than a decade. Authorities warned on Monday that the death toll could rise as cranes began lifting mangled carriages from the wreckage near the town of Adamuz.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crash occurred around 7:45 PM local time when the rear carriages of an Iryo train traveling from Málaga to Madrid derailed and crossed onto an adjacent track, slamming into an oncoming Renfe Alvia service headed from Madrid to Huelva. The Renfe train's first two carriages tumbled down a four-meter embankment, sustaining the most severe damage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/3S4UV53UDJNOTLPWEPFMIB7VXQ.jpg?auth=c94786562326648302295905bc24637482feff568078da348ef827763a5a0a86&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU weighs first use of 'trade bazooka' against Trump tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-prepares-retaliatory-measur-DBKYMqleTqmKtQrOAeAPow</link>
      <description>European Union leaders are mobilizing an unprecedented response to President Donald Trump's threat of escalating tariffs on nations opposing his campaign to acquire Greenland, with officials considering activating the bloc's most powerful trade weapon for the first time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;EU ambassadors from all 27 member states convened an emergency meeting in Brussels on Sunday, where the European Commission presented multiple countermeasures, including reactivating a €93 billion retaliatory tariff package and deploying the Anti-Coercion Instrument, a mechanism adopted in 2023 but never triggered.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108253936-1768812919028-gettyimages-2256239146-berg-greenlan260117_npf6x.jpeg?v=1768812948&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin invited to join Trump's 'Board of Peace' as 60 nations weigh membership</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-invites-putin-and-60-nat-UmcTaQqhT2KgG_YPcduJaw</link>
      <description>The Kremlin announced Monday that Russian President Vladimir Putin has received an invitation to join U.S. President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace," with Moscow saying it is studying the proposal and hopes for further contacts with Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The invitation to Putin comes as Trump has dispatched letters to approximately 60 world leaders asking them to become founding members of the new international body, which he will chair for life. Initially conceived to oversee governance and reconstruction in post-war Gaza, the board's draft charter indicates aspirations for a broader mandate addressing global conflicts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2025/08/putin-peace-talks.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers breach Iran state TV to air exiled prince's protest call</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-state-television-hacked-t-_5CrKF10T4K_MELDK6dAdg</link>
      <description>Hackers breached Iran's state television network on Sunday, hijacking broadcasts for approximately 10 minutes to air anti-regime messages and an address from exiled Crown Prince Reza Pahlavi calling on Iranians to continue their protests against the Islamic Republic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The cyberattack targeted Iran's Badr satellite, which transmits several state-run provincial channels nationwide, allowing opposition footage to reach millions of homes across the country during prime evening viewing hours. According to Israel's public broadcaster KAN News, the hacked broadcast aired around 9:30 p.m. local time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/en/thewrap.com/f69dce9a84a4cf1dd0fa1c41d8192252" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz urges restraint as France pushes for EU trade retaliation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/merz-seeks-to-restrain-macron-xqhk3rUTTdKsdNkMLtlD6g</link>
      <description>Chancellor Friedrich Merz signaled on Sunday that Germany prefers a measured response to President Donald Trump's threat of escalating tariffs over Greenland, putting Berlin on a different track than Paris as Europe's two largest economies grapple with how to handle the unprecedented American demands.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Merz said Germany and its European partners have agreed "that we want to avoid any escalation in this dispute if at all possible," according to his remarks in Berlin on Monday. While French President Emmanuel Macron has formally requested activation of the European Union's most powerful trade weapon—the anti-coercion instrument, often called the EU's "trade bazooka"—Merz indicated Germany would support such measures only "if necessary."</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768840961/getty_uploads/2257055960_sbjaqa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia posts record budget deficit as oil revenues collapse</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/russia-posts-record-budget-def-FWK7EpnZQz6FBki.KzUETw</link>
      <description>Russia recorded a federal budget deficit of 5.645 trillion rubles ($72.3 billion) in 2025, the largest since at least 1996, according to data released by the Finance Ministry on Sunday. The shortfall more than doubled from 3.47 trillion rubles the previous year, exposing the mounting fiscal strain of nearly three years of war in Ukraine.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The record gap came despite aggressive spending cuts in December, when expenditures fell 19% from a year earlier as the government moved to keep the deficit within its revised target of 2.6% of GDP. Finance Minister Anton Siluanov confirmed the target was met in an interview with Interfax last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/DBIWNL6RGRJH7O4TZG5RCJFJQU.jpg?auth=da630f786f36686c179fee256f9fab418cbe97e14997e8e5c9098aad465c9955&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hotel explosion in Kabul kills at least 7, injures Chinese nationals</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/deadly-blast-in-kabul-hotel-ki-2JwcEFUlRHS_m7MuSIVvjQ</link>
      <description>A powerful explosion tore through a hotel in central Kabul on Monday, killing at least seven people and injuring 13 others, according to officials and a hospital that treated casualties. The blast struck the heavily guarded Shahr-e-Naw district, considered one of the safest neighborhoods in the Afghan capital.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Italian NGO EMERGENCY, which operates a surgical center in Kabul, confirmed receiving at least 20 patients from the incident, including women and children. The organization reported seven deaths from the explosion that occurred at a hotel on Gulfaroshi Street in the capital's fourth district.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://harici.com.tr/en/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/llllllllllllllll.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan's PM Takaichi calls snap election for February 8</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/japan-pm-takaichi-calls-snap-e-Hi9DoPMIRoif8xuhCxeEZg</link>
      <description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi announced Monday that she will dissolve parliament on Friday and hold a snap general election on February 8, just three months after becoming the country's first female leader. The move sets the stage for a high-stakes campaign as Takaichi seeks a stronger mandate to advance her fiscal policies and hardline security stance amid escalating tensions with China.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I want the public to decide whether Sanae Takaichi is suitable as prime minister," she told reporters at a press conference in Tokyo. Official campaigning will begin on January 27, with only 16 days between the dissolution and voting day, the shortest such period since the end of World War II.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/19/multimedia/19int-japan-election-01-jmzh/19int-japan-election-01-jmzh-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prince Harry's privacy trial against Daily Mail begins in London</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/prince-harry-daily-mail-privac-nEgOHnatSnWO4RfA5rukDw</link>
      <description>Prince Harry arrived at London's High Court on Monday, waving to reporters and saying "good morning" as he entered via a side entrance for the start of what his legal team calls the "final chapter" of his crusade against British tabloid media. The Duke of Sussex, 41, sat in the back row of the courtroom alongside actresses Elizabeth Hurley and Sadie Frost as his barrister, David Sherborne, alleged the Daily Mail and Mail on Sunday engaged in "clear, systematic and sustained use of unlawful information gathering" spanning two decades.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The civil trial, expected to last nine weeks, sees Harry and six other high-profile claimants accusing Associated Newspapers Limited of illegal practices including phone hacking, hiring private investigators to plant listening devices in homes and cars, and obtaining medical and financial records through deception—a practice known as "blagging". The publisher has "vigorously denied" all allegations, calling them "preposterous smears" and part of a "coordinated effort" against the media.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://variety.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/prince-harry.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=667&amp;crop=1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France rejects Trump's Gaza Board of Peace, citing UN concerns</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/france-declines-trump-s-gaza-b-iRgGG6qzQ1qUmYh57Gw1iA</link>
      <description>France will not accept an invitation to join President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace" initiative aimed at overseeing Gaza's governance, according to a source close to President Emmanuel Macron. The announcement comes as the French government simultaneously pursues its own path of engagement in the region, dispatching nearly 400 tons of humanitarian aid to the war-ravaged territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.elysee.fr/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto%252Cquality=100%252Cwidth=800%252Cheight=420%252Ctrim=274%253B0%253B29%253B0%252Cfit=cover/images/default/0001/18/a1520042f300e92a96f1c37cd6aee79403d2c528.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italian PM Meloni offers to mediate US-Europe standoff over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/meloni-offers-to-mediate-betwe-mwPEa6hlQ52SmAK.UFbp5w</link>
      <description>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni positioned herself as a potential bridge between Washington and European capitals on Sunday, calling President Donald Trump's tariff threats over Greenland "a mistake" while suggesting the crisis stemmed from a "communication breakdown" rather than fundamental disagreement among allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking during a visit to Seoul on January 18, Meloni disclosed that she had spoken directly with Trump "a few hours ago" and conveyed her concerns about the escalating tensions. "There has been a problem of understanding and communication," she told reporters, arguing that European military deployments to Greenland were misinterpreted as anti-American when they were actually intended to deter "other actors" — a reference to Russia and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iZEM9UMjuRDk/v1/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
