<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 23:27:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli startup nT-Tao fires first plasma in compact fusion reactor</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nt-tao-c3-fusion-prototype-ach-rEZJrCgGSF.AwkUb0qKZWw</link>
      <description>Israeli compact fusion energy company nT-Tao announced on January 15, 2026 that its C3 prototype has successfully fired its first plasma pulses, reaching operational status just over two months after assembly began. The milestone represents a concrete advancement in the company's pursuit of a container-sized fusion reactor capable of generating 10-20 MW of clean power.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Hod Hasharon-based startup's C3 system builds directly upon the successful experimental campaign of its predecessor, the C2-A, which achieved plasma temperatures of approximately one million degrees Celsius—roughly 100 electron volts—at the intended high-density regime. The new prototype incorporates design refinements across magnets, pulsed power systems, diagnostics, and overall integration, with experimental goals focused on reaching higher temperatures and extended confinement durations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/lo/mysterio/api/2FBF7BD88CB836199EDF5DAE3192554FA1DB3B7DBB52986A09D43AB194B6BC5B/subgraphmysterio/resizefit_w1200%3Bquality_90%3Bformat_webp/https:%252F%252Fs.yimg.com%252Fos%252Fen%252Finteresting_engineering_646%252F9d4294ed9233832bf20f2048915eea74" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's acting president calls for oil reforms, US thaw</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-s-new-leader-seeks-o-cg7.sL0HT8iHnxo_bgHGrQ</link>
      <description>Less than two weeks after the United States military captured Nicolás Maduro, Venezuela's acting president used her first major address to lawmakers to call for sweeping reforms to the country's oil industry and a diplomatic thaw with Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a 44-minute state of the union speech on Thursday, Delcy Rodríguez urged Venezuela's National Assembly to approve changes to the nation's hydrocarbon law that would open doors to greater foreign investment in the state-controlled oil sector. The address marked a striking departure from the anti-American rhetoric that defined her predecessor's rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4HV2AFG5QVKOTLUHQAUKOLQRSI.jpg?auth=9cb8a23b74e72ea1f9eddd8becb2464c255bdd3a9ff113663f4d0b0d79ca182f&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT team cools trapped ions 10 times below standard limit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-uncover-new-quantum-JDj0suPnTSKZI6Vk69Wafw</link>
      <description>Two separate research efforts published this week are advancing the frontiers of quantum computing by solving distinct challenges: achieving efficient cooling for chip-based systems and discovering unexpected quantum states in exotic materials.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers at MIT and MIT Lincoln Laboratory announced Wednesday a technique for cooling trapped ions using integrated photonics that reaches temperatures about 10 times below the standard laser cooling limit, known as the Doppler limit. The method achieves this in approximately 100 microseconds, several times faster than existing approaches.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Meanwhile, scientists at TU Wien in Vienna and Rice University revealed Tuesday in Nature Physics that they observed an "emergent topological semimetal" — a quantum state previously considered impossible because it combines two phenomena thought to be incompatible.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://qci.dlr.de/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2025-10-01-Keyvisual-840-Toccata.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN High Seas Treaty to take effect, protecting two-thirds of ocean</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-high-seas-treaty-takes-effe-qCgiZpOuSLS_2oeZL0.h5A</link>
      <description>The United Nations High Seas Treaty, formally known as the Biodiversity Beyond National Jurisdiction (BBNJ) Agreement, will officially enter into force on January 17, 2026, establishing the first legally binding international framework to protect marine biodiversity in nearly two-thirds of the world's ocean.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The treaty becomes international law after Morocco became the 60th nation to ratify it on September 19, 2025, triggering a 120-day countdown to implementation. Currently, 82 countries have officially joined the agreement, and 145 of the UN's 193 member states have signed it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://marine-conservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/ocean-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver coating makes solid-state batteries 5 times crack-resistant</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/stanford-strengthens-solid-ele-KF6SdoQ5Q9Kjos7fECqPUg</link>
      <description>A team of Stanford researchers has discovered that applying an ultrathin coating of silver to solid electrolytes makes them nearly five times more resistant to cracking, addressing one of the most persistent obstacles to commercializing next-generation lithium metal batteries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published January 16 in Nature Materials, could accelerate development of batteries that are safer, store more energy, and charge faster than today's lithium-ion technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://fordauthority.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/SK-On-Oxide-Based-Solid-Electrolyte-Solid-State-Battery-002.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan shares surge to record after US finalizes trade deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-markets-mixed-as-taiwan-B7AVd0YdSfm2TgDNofF_AQ</link>
      <description>Asian markets finished Friday with divergent outcomes as Taiwan led regional gains, surging nearly 2 percent to a record close after the United States and Taiwan finalized a semiconductor-focused trade agreement the day before.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Taiwan Weighted Index climbed 1.94 percent to close at a record 31,408.7, making it the best-performing Asian market on Friday. The rally came after Washington and Taipei announced a deal on Thursday that will reduce tariffs on Taiwanese goods from 20 percent to 15 percent while securing commitments from Taiwanese chip and technology companies to invest at least $250 billion in U.S. production capacity.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/5D573OOWGJIT7HXTZ5JI6JFCI4.jpg?auth=a105645deb11d15375a741a1501ce152c1a9a90dc2b5a048a4b33b2d75bd48b0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers discover massive iron bar hiding inside Ring Nebula</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-find-massive-iron-Li1iU6IdRXidQMH83bX.9Q</link>
      <description>A European team has discovered a hidden bar of iron stretching across the interior of the Ring Nebula, one of the most iconic objects in the night sky. The structure, described for the first time this week in Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, contains a mass of iron atoms comparable to Mars and had gone completely unnoticed despite decades of observations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discovery raises a puzzle that astronomers cannot yet solve: how did such a large concentration of iron end up in such a distinct shape inside a nebula formed from a dying star?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/230804122801-james-webb-space-telescope-ring-nebula.jpg?c=original" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's giant telescope captures first clear evidence of fast radio burst origins</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-telescope-reveals-cause-GCUr10_oS_uexolz3_zOrA</link>
      <description>Using the world's largest single-dish radio telescope, an international team of researchers has captured the first clear evidence linking mysterious cosmic radio signals to a dense plasma cloud, providing strong support for the theory that some fast radio bursts originate from binary star systems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published Friday in the journal Science, are based on nearly 20 months of observations by China's Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical radio Telescope, known as FAST, of a repeating fast radio burst designated FRB 20220529, located approximately 2.9 billion light-years from Earth.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.globaltimes.cn/Portals/0/attachment/2022/2022-08-01/5e357d6b-91fc-4306-aba0-d5d7fd55f097.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS spins every 7 hours, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-interstellar-object-ro-xOgCoCYuS.2wVj2cJkHhGQ</link>
      <description>The interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS completes a full rotation approximately every 7.1 hours, according to new research by Harvard astrophysicist Abraham Loeb and Italian astronomer Toni Scarmato. The findings arrive just days before a rare celestial alignment on January 22 that could provide unprecedented data about this cosmic traveler from beyond our solar system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, which analyzed Hubble Space Telescope images from late 2025, used two independent methods to determine the rotation period: tracking the wobble of the comet's jet-like features and measuring brightness variations over time. The jet position angle analysis yielded a period of 7.20 ± 0.05 hours, while photometric measurements produced 7.136 ± 0.001 hours.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://sm.mashable.com/mashable_me/seo/default/untitled-2026-01-16t122549001_dqw2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS makes final pass before leaving solar system</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/comet-3iatlas-makes-final-pass-bx8rCRtnT4eVGTGXPtYuNg</link>
      <description>The interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS, only the third object from beyond our solar system ever detected passing through our cosmic neighborhood, is making its final observable appearance before vanishing into the void. The Virtual Telescope Project is hosting a farewell livestream today at 21:00 UTC to mark humanity's last opportunity to view the celestial visitor.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zT58SVFsEFhx8fytDdVCPd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada and China strike trade deal on EVs, canola amid US tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canada-and-china-forge-new-str-PUW0WR_iR3GMkdJuV08EWA</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney and Chinese President Xi Jinping announced a landmark trade agreement on Friday in Beijing, with Canada agreeing to slash tariffs on Chinese electric vehicles in exchange for China reducing duties on Canadian agricultural products, marking a dramatic shift in Ottawa's trade policy away from the United States.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Under the deal, Canada will allow up to 49,000 Chinese EVs into the country at a 6.1% tariff rate, replacing the 100% duty imposed by former Prime Minister Justin Trudeau in 2024. The quota will increase to 70,000 vehicles over five years. In return, China will lower tariffs on Canadian canola seed from approximately 84% to 15% by March 1, according to statements from both governments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/reuters_6969e91c-1768548636.jpg?resize=1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former South Korean president sentenced to 5 years in prison</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/former-south-korean-president-gElRg9xMRT6ddMINJYv9cQ</link>
      <description>Former South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol was sentenced to five years in prison on Friday by the Seoul Central District Court, marking the first verdict in a series of criminal trials stemming from his brief declaration of martial law in December 2024.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The court found Yoon guilty of obstructing authorities from executing an arrest warrant, falsifying official documents, and failing to follow proper legal procedures for declaring martial law, according to a live broadcast of the verdict. The ruling comes half the 10-year sentence prosecutors had requested, setting the stage for a more consequential insurrection verdict expected next month.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://bostonglobe-prod.cdn.arcpublishing.com/resizer/v2/ZC4NJADG47UCPXX3QTLVEMV6WU.jpg?auth=08bbd4b3a5567d94674841a7c2a238a6ad047b6ab7b4c16a210264041514c04d&amp;width=1200&amp;height=672" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens tariffs on nations opposing his Greenland bid</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-tariffs-over-g-ulearT0aRQqvMyMY65iJwQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump warned Friday that he may impose tariffs on countries that do not support his efforts to acquire Greenland, escalating his campaign to take control of the strategically vital Arctic territory despite growing international opposition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I may put a tariff on countries if they don't go along with Greenland, because we need Greenland for national security," Trump said during a roundtable event at the White House. The threat came as European nations deployed military personnel to the semiautonomous Danish territory for joint exercises, and a bipartisan delegation of U.S. lawmakers arrived in Copenhagen to demonstrate solidarity with Denmark.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.arctictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/2026-01-14T162111Z_2038492178_RC221JA20R53_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP-GREENLAND-DENMARK-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US and Taiwan reach trade deal cutting tariffs, securing chip investment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-and-taiwan-reach-landmark-t-bLbbji7oS9qvz.nDk2QwOA</link>
      <description>The United States and Taiwan have reached a trade agreement that will reduce tariffs on Taiwanese goods from 20 percent to 15 percent and secure hundreds of billions of dollars in semiconductor investment commitments, according to officials familiar with the matter. The deal, which the White House was set to announce Thursday, places Taiwan on equal footing with Japan and South Korea, which secured similar arrangements last year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Under the agreement, Taiwanese semiconductor companies will commit to a $500 billion increase in financing for American operations, with Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. pledging to build at least five additional fabrication plants in Arizona, effectively doubling its manufacturing presence in the state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/03/multimedia/03biz-tsmc-sub-vzgl-wpzq/03biz-tsmc-sub-vzgl-wpzq-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky rejects Trump's claim that Ukraine is blocking peace</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/zelensky-rejects-trump-s-claim-.CTTFbCiQTi__bLXeDKZ_g</link>
      <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy firmly rejected U.S. President Donald Trump's assertion that Ukraine is obstructing peace negotiations, declaring that his country "has never been and will never be an obstacle to peace" while pointing to ongoing Russian attacks on civilian infrastructure as evidence of Moscow's true intentions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dispute erupted after Trump told Reuters on January 15 that Russian President Vladimir Putin is "ready to make a deal" while characterizing Ukraine as "less ready." When asked why U.S.-led negotiations had failed to end the nearly four-year-old conflict, Trump responded with a single word: "Zelenskyy."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thehill.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/12/mr-zelensky-trump_122925ap.jpg?w=1280" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet's alien dust unlike anything in our solar system</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/3iatlas-interstellar-comet-she-1jTNJpmQTJWkaIBJYmBPmw</link>
      <description>The interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS continues to defy expectations, maintaining active outgassing and shedding material with a chemical composition unlike anything found in our solar system—even as it recedes toward the outer reaches of space.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A ground-based telescope in Hawaii captured the object on January 14, 2026, revealing a compact nucleus surrounded by a structured coma and the early formation of a tail, despite the comet being approximately 300 million kilometers from Earth. At such distances, most small bodies would fade into obscurity, yet 3I/ATLAS remains visible and active.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/48/2025/11/3i-atlas-11-november-2025.jpg?w=1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA to roll out SLS rocket for first crewed Moon mission in 50 years</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-rolls-out-sls-rocket-for-qBSxvzgaQMqP2BUABb5iHw</link>
      <description>NASA is set to begin rolling out its towering Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft for the Artemis II mission as early as Saturday morning, marking the final preparatory steps before the first crewed voyage to the Moon in more than half a century.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The rollout from the Vehicle Assembly Building to Launch Pad 39B at Kennedy Space Center in Florida is targeted to begin no earlier than 7 a.m. EST on January 17, according to NASA. The 322-foot rocket will travel approximately 6.4 kilometers over the course of up to 12 hours aboard the agency's crawler-transporter-2.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/48/2026/01/artemis-i-rollout.jpg?w=1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI to test ads in ChatGPT for the first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-begins-testing-ads-in-c-iftvcU5LSGyw9AKiVGW_wg</link>
      <description>OpenAI announced this week it will begin testing advertisements in ChatGPT for the first time, marking a pivotal shift for the artificial intelligence company as it seeks new revenue streams amid mounting financial pressures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to OpenAI's official statement, the company will start testing ads in the U.S. in the coming weeks, limited to users of the free tier and the newer $8-a-month ChatGPT Go plan. Ads will appear at the bottom of responses when a sponsored product or service is relevant to the conversation, and will be clearly labeled as such. Users of premium tiers including Plus, Pro, Business, and Enterprise will not see advertisements.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.wsj.net/im-43992188?width=1280&amp;size=1.501" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI to begin testing ads in ChatGPT's free tier</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/openai-to-begin-testing-ads-in-2EXornIkQamQywz7OEDx4Q</link>
      <description>OpenAI announced Friday it will begin testing advertisements in ChatGPT, a major shift for the artificial intelligence company as it seeks to diversify revenue beyond subscriptions amid mounting operational costs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The ads will roll out to users of the free version of the chatbot as well as those subscribing to ChatGPT Go, the company's newly launched budget-tier subscription that is becoming available globally at around $8 per month, according to The Wall Street Journal and Bloomberg. The move comes as OpenAI faces pressure to monetize its massive user base, with only about 5% of ChatGPT's 800 million weekly active users paying for subscriptions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/zxiQh.BqtI1GzO19tk4Oqg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTI0MDA7aD0xNjAw/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_independent_635/9ee224bdd15987a4e510c71e0f72884f" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists open world's first ice core sanctuary in Antarctica</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-map-antarctica-and-TlthFNS0QMi8Nbn1WUnioQ</link>
      <description>In a week of advances for polar science, researchers have unveiled the most detailed map ever created of Antarctica's hidden bedrock while a separate team inaugurated the world's first ice core sanctuary on the frozen continent, both efforts aimed at understanding and preserving climate data before it disappears.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/6a7ac34a-d717-4857-b5dc-dbe52078c268/wirestory_25c45a3a1e6375a1f241c825e5e63e5c_16x9.jpg?w=1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
