<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Canada models guerrilla warfare response to US invasion</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canadian-military-simulates-us-_WgxXgVURueKc1oAvoC4JA</link>
      <description>The Canadian Armed Forces have modeled a hypothetical U.S. military invasion of Canada and potential responses employing unconventional warfare tactics, The Globe and Mail reported on Tuesday, marking the first time in approximately 100 years that such scenarios have been war-gamed by Canada's military.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to two senior government officials who spoke to The Globe and Mail, military planners are simulating a U.S. invasion from the south, anticipating American forces could overwhelm Canada's strategic defenses on land and at sea within as little as two days. The officials emphasized, however, that a U.S. invasion remains highly improbable.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.the-independent.com/2026/01/20/21/06/GettyImages-2206320029.jpeg?trim=1%252C0%252C1%252C0&amp;width=1200&amp;height=800&amp;crop=1200%253A800" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX prepares Ship 39 for Starship Flight 12 debut</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-targets-mars-and-advanc-fAr4MKzYQJqKG_Pym8mN3w</link>
      <description>SpaceX is accelerating preparations for an ambitious year that could include the company's first uncrewed mission to Mars, while simultaneously advancing Starship development and maintaining a rapid pace of satellite launches.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company is targeting a Starship launch to Mars during the November-December 2026 planetary alignment window, which would represent the first private company mission to another planet. CEO Elon Musk has estimated a 50% chance of meeting the 2026 deadline, with plans to send Tesla Optimus humanoid robots on the initial missions to "prepare the way for humans."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.teslarati.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Starship-update-2022-SpaceX-Raptor-V1-vs-V2-1-crop-c.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela receives $300M from US-controlled oil sales</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-receives-300-million-iILx8irUQPek9CtKJnmGkg</link>
      <description>Venezuela's acting president Delcy Rodríguez announced on Tuesday that the country has received $300 million from the sale of Venezuelan crude oil facilitated by Washington, funds she intends to use to stabilize the country's battered currency and protect workers from inflation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We must inform you that we have received funds from the sale of oil, and of the first $500 million, we received 300 million," Reuters quoted Rodríguez as saying during a visit to a commune base in Caracas. The interim leader stated the revenues would be used "to stabilize" the foreign exchange market "to protect the income and purchasing power of our workers".</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768970804/getty_uploads/2256492636_qo2xr6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump demands NATO allies spend 5 percent of GDP, doubts their support</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-demands-nato-allies-spen-vRmqmMgoTLi5DAq9QgjilQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump used the one-year anniversary of his second term to renew calls for NATO allies to meet the alliance's 5% GDP defense spending commitment, while casting doubt on whether European partners would fulfill their mutual defense obligations. His remarks come amid escalating tensions over his campaign to acquire Greenland from Denmark.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I have done more for NATO than anyone else," Trump said during a White House briefing Tuesday. "The big fear I have with NATO is we spend tremendous amounts of money with NATO, and I know we'll come to their rescue, but I really do question whether or not they'll come to ours."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/17/multimedia/17dc-tariffs-greenland-topart-ctfl/17dc-tariffs-greenland-topart-ctfl-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds ChatGPT systematically favors wealthy Western nations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/study-finds-chatgpt-biased-tow-BC3lrUoASXOZwJ.6CEBJLg</link>
      <description>When prompted with subjective questions comparing places around the world, OpenAI's ChatGPT systematically favors wealthier, Western regions while ranking much of the Global South at the bottom, according to new research published Tuesday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The study, titled "The Silicon Gaze: A typology of biases and inequality in LLMs through the lens of place," analyzed more than 20 million queries submitted to ChatGPT's 4o-mini model. Researchers from the Oxford Internet Institute at the University of Oxford and the University of Kentucky found that the chatbot repeatedly ranked high-income countries, including the United States, Western Europe, and parts of East Asia, as "better," "smarter," "happier," and "more innovative" than poorer regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.euronews.com/articles/stories/09/61/97/17/1536x864_cmsv2_d37a6a81-89e7-555c-b86f-3795f66a6051-9619717.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weather disaster deaths decline despite climate change, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/climate-change-drives-disaster-xx0yqdJFTnSMP7O1kV2q3Q</link>
      <description>As climate change intensifies extreme weather events around the world, a paradox has emerged: overall mortality from weather-related disasters has declined in recent decades, even as storms, floods, and heatwaves grow more frequent and severe.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;An analysis by AFP of data from EM-DAT, a global disaster database run by the Belgium-based Centre for Research on the Epidemiology of Disasters (CRED), found that more than 2.3 million people died from weather-related events between 1970 and 2025. The death toll from 2015 to 2025 reached 305,156, a notable decline from 354,428 in the previous decade.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It's not because the events haven't become more dangerous. It's because we have become a lot better at coping with them," Dr. Marina Romanello, executive director of the Lancet Countdown, told AFP.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/3000x1688%2B0%2B156/resize/1400/quality/85/format/jpeg/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Feb%252F74%252Fe939da694982a4ec60c6d8718688%252Fgettyimages-1242172582.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Orbiter captures high-detail view of solar flare's trigger</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/solar-orbiter-reveals-magnetic-cXbdwKfUSry1PlSJ1bgKxQ</link>
      <description>The European Space Agency's Solar Orbiter spacecraft has captured the most detailed view ever of how solar flares ignite, revealing they are triggered by cascading magnetic avalanches rather than single coherent eruptions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published Wednesday in Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, could improve predictions of solar storms that pose radiation hazards to satellites, astronauts, and Earth-based technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6NhQakd7cZ9X3ZJ5kqJjbC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treasury chief calls Denmark 'irrelevant' amid Greenland tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-treasury-secretary-dismisse-NiACPZWYQtuFh3XbHTHfNQ</link>
      <description>U.S. Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent on Wednesday brushed aside concerns about potential European divestment from American government debt, making dismissive remarks about Denmark amid escalating tensions over President Donald Trump's push to acquire Greenland.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking to reporters at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, Bessent characterized Danish investments in U.S. Treasury bonds as insignificant. "Denmark's investment in U.S. Treasury bonds, like Denmark itself, is irrelevant," the Treasury secretary said. He added that he had "no worries at all" about any sell-off, pointing to "record foreign investment" in Treasury auctions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768989543/getty_uploads/2256680653_mxr1zy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Far-red light triggers protein that disarms antibiotic-resistant bacteria</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/far-red-light-reduces-virulenc-rEkRekYNSYWMpqcP44XtuA</link>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Chicago have uncovered a light-sensitive signaling pathway that suppresses biofilm formation and virulence in Pseudomonas aeruginosa, an antibiotic-resistant bacterium responsible for dangerous hospital-acquired infections. The discovery, published in Nature Communications, identifies a small protein called DimA as the master activator of the bacteria's response to far-red light, opening potential new avenues for infection control that do not rely on antibiotics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://biologicalsciences.uchicago.edu/sites/biologicalsciences/files/styles/social/public/2026-01/p-aeruginosa.jpg?h=c74750f6&amp;itok=BPq-Hyol" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JPMorgan CEO Dimon says AI will cut jobs at the bank</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jpmorgan-ceo-dimon-predicts-ai-ENxUsT2NTOiy7pxqzGzHMA</link>
      <description>Speaking at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, this week, JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon warned that artificial intelligence will transform the banking industry and reduce employment at the nation's largest financial institution over the next five years. Dimon estimated the bank will have fewer employees than its current workforce of more than 317,000, even as the company continues to grow globally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I do think it may go too fast for society," Dimon said during a panel discussion on Monday. "And if it goes too fast for society, that's where government and business and the collaborative ways to step in together and come up with a way to retrain people or move it over time."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EIV4HXAFVNNWNKBWJBKHMBHXDQ.jpg?auth=535d1002f0611a26955e5f60f54c72c9210bca170f65fab9d841fdd74c7b6a1d&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump demands Greenland talks at Davos, rules out force</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-demands-greenland-talks-q9_uynS8Q0Cbr3GXWFSfKw</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump delivered a combative speech at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, on Wednesday, using the global gathering to press his case for acquiring Greenland while criticizing European allies and calling Denmark "ungrateful" for refusing to cede the territory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"No nation or coalition of nations is in any position to be able to secure Greenland other than the United States," Trump told the assembled business leaders and diplomats. "We're a great power, much greater than people even understand."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The speech came amid unprecedented tensions between the United States and its European allies, with Trump threatening tariffs on eight NATO countries unless they support his bid to purchase the semi-autonomous Danish territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://bostonglobe-prod.cdn.arcpublishing.com/resizer/v2/N5YCGKHLLLWTYEORTY2YYNXKFQ.jpg?auth=aa15e42fa15fc74ca3bc7809b8738ca737048337ba96a1fadabd5edb33bd64a9&amp;width=1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canadian PM Carney says US-led global order is over</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canadian-pm-carney-says-us-led-nvwdU2OxQFqSyCNl2nOPQQ</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney declared the end of the American-led rules-based international order on Tuesday, urging "middle powers" like Canada to band together against coercion from larger nations in an address at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland that delivered a direct rebuke to U.S. President Donald Trump's territorial ambitions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking in both French and English to the assembled global elite, Carney described a "rupture" in global affairs where "the powerful act as they wish, while the vulnerable endure what they must." The speech came just hours after Trump posted AI-generated images on Truth Social depicting American flags overlaid on Canada, Greenland, Cuba, and Venezuela.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.barrons.com/asset/external-media/afp/AFP2802786153032761998333060348832159029096---1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU leaders to hold emergency summit over Greenland tensions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/von-der-leyen-warns-eu-at-cros-zub1C8GlSWmvAQImXH9sZA</link>
      <description>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen declared Wednesday that the European Union stands "at a crossroads" as tensions with the United States over Greenland escalate, warning that President Donald Trump's tariff threats risk triggering a "dangerous downward spiral" between allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Europe prefers dialogue and solutions – but we are fully prepared to act, if necessary, with unity, urgency and determination," von der Leyen told the European Parliament in Strasbourg, signaling a more forceful approach to Trump's persistent pressure campaign to acquire the Arctic territory from Denmark.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769007182/getty_uploads/2256658226_rh6pia.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsealed emails show Microsoft pushed OpenAI toward rapid monetization</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/documents-reveal-microsoft-s-r-dg_QZTKZQKWHcdBGdkdQ0Q</link>
      <description>Newly unsealed internal communications from Elon Musk's lawsuit against OpenAI and Microsoft show how Microsoft executives actively shaped the AI startup's rapid pivot from a cautious nonprofit into one of the most valuable companies in technology. The documents, made public through legal discovery, offer a rare glimpse into the corporate maneuvering that transformed OpenAI from an obscure research lab into a company now valued at $500 billion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;GeekWire journalist Todd Bishop examined the cache of emails, memos, and text messages, revealing that Microsoft's leadership, including CEO Satya Nadella, pushed aggressively for monetization at critical junctures in OpenAI's development.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/107329641-1699296366156-IMG_3589.jpg?v=1738098239&amp;w=1600&amp;h=900" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump rules out force for Greenland, demands negotiations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-addresses-davos-amid-gre-waIO7giWR3Gi39.B2BKXcQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump delivered a defiant 72-minute speech at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland on Wednesday, ruling out military force to acquire Greenland while demanding "immediate negotiations" with Denmark over the Arctic territory and criticizing European allies as heading in the "wrong direction."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The address, widely anticipated as a pivotal moment in escalating transatlantic tensions, saw Trump claim Greenland as American territory while simultaneously attempting to reassure nervous European partners. "We probably won't get anything unless I decide to use excessive strength and force, where we would be, frankly, unstoppable. But I won't do that," Trump told the audience of billionaires, government officials, and diplomats.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/85cf57fb-4999-4b26-988b-a1e13cd88a05/trump-davos-2-gty-jef-260121_1769003727272_hpMain_16x9.jpg?w=1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesian cave hand stencil becomes oldest dated rock art</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/67800-year-old-hand-stencil-fo-t01qbIWDSg6c6GBj6ydOjg</link>
      <description>A faded hand stencil found in a cave on Indonesia's Muna Island has been dated to at least 67,800 years ago, making it the oldest reliably dated rock art ever discovered. The finding, published Wednesday in the journal Nature, surpasses the previous record holder — hand stencils attributed to Neanderthals in Spain — by more than a millennium and offers new insights into early human migration toward Australia.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/20110140/SEI_281501994.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pew report finds Catholicism declining sharply across Latin America</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/pew-reports-decline-in-christi-uP_bO.uMQtG5IJW1JlC6fw</link>
      <description>A new report from the Pew Research Center released Wednesday reveals that Catholicism continues to decline across Latin America, with the Catholic share of the population falling by at least 9 percentage points in each of six major countries surveyed over the past decade. The findings mirror broader trends of Christian disaffiliation documented by Pew across Europe, where millions have left the faith since childhood.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The report, titled "Catholicism Has Declined in Latin America Over the Past Decade," is based on surveys of more than 6,200 adults conducted in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico, and Peru between January and April 2024. These six nations collectively represent about 75% of Latin America's population.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Our analysis found that the Catholic share of the population in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico and Peru has significantly declined since 2013-14, while a growing share of adults in the region are religiously unaffiliated," said Kirsten Lesage, a Pew research associate and the report's lead author.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://zenit.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/alguna-vez-fue-una-figura-muy-popular-en-america-latina-ahora-esta-viendo-una-disminucion-en-su-favorabilidad-01.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mountain regions warming faster than lowlands, threatening water for billions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/climate-change-drives-extreme-Jz2dFQ5ST2WH6uLYJ4PZpQ</link>
      <description>The past 11 years have been the warmest in modern history, the World Meteorological Organization confirmed last week, as scientists warn that global warming is intensifying heatwaves, floods, and storms while threatening water supplies for more than a billion people.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The WMO reported that 2025 ranked among the three warmest years on record, with global average surface temperatures reaching 1.44°C above pre-industrial levels. Six of eight international climate datasets ranked 2025 as the third-warmest year, while two ranked it second-warmest in the 176-year temperature record. The findings came despite the cooling influence of La Niña conditions at the start and end of the year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The year 2025 started and ended with a cooling La Niña and yet it was still one of the warmest years on record globally because of the accumulation of heat-trapping greenhouse gases in our atmosphere," said WMO Secretary-General Celeste Saulo.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.sciencenews.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/052919_CG_himalaya_feat.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar object 3I/ATLAS to reach optimal viewing alignment</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/avi-loeb-flags-18-anomalies-in-zw1aQsUeRtaR8CXezoOJrg</link>
      <description>Harvard astrophysicist Avi Loeb has published an essay cataloguing 18 unusual characteristics of interstellar object 3I/ATLAS, raising questions about whether the cosmic visitor could be artificial rather than a natural comet. The provocative analysis, titled "What if 3I/ATLAS Is AI/ATLAS?" arrives as the object approaches a rare near-opposition alignment on January 22, 2026, offering astronomers an unprecedented observational window.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Loeb, the former chair of Harvard's astronomy department, states that 3I/ATLAS is "most likely natural" but argues the anomalies warrant investigation. He ranks the object at 4 on his self-devised 10-point "Loeb Scale" for interstellar significance.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/48/2025/09/3i-atlas-gemini-south-social.jpg?w=1200&amp;webp=1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's Board of Peace gains members ahead of Davos signing</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-forms-board-of-peace-ami-WU3GSPSER46iKg4G07N06g</link>
      <description>US President Donald Trump's newly created "Board of Peace" is gaining members while exposing rifts among Western nations, as the initiative designed to oversee Gaza's reconstruction expands into a broader conflict-resolution body that some fear could challenge the United Nations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On Wednesday, divisions sharpened as Israel, Egypt, Bahrain, Azerbaijan, and Kosovo announced they would join the board, while Norway and Sweden followed France in declining the invitation. A White House official said about 30 countries are expected to sign on, with 50 having received invitations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump is scheduled to hold a formal signing ceremony Thursday at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, where the charter will be officially established.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769002948/getty_uploads/2256790569_w70blj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
