<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:12:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists detail plans to study asteroid's potential moon strike</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-prepare-for-potenti-cgj7dpFHSqi4hx9FUweWpA</link>
      <description>A 60-meter-wide asteroid discovered just over a year ago carries a small but notable chance of striking the moon in late 2032, and researchers worldwide are preparing for what could be the most energetic lunar impact ever recorded in human history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Asteroid 2024 YR4, which was first detected on December 27, 2024, at the Asteroid Terrestrial-impact Last Alert System telescope in Chile, has approximately a 4% probability of colliding with the moon on December 22, 2032. While that means there is a 96% chance the asteroid will miss, scientists are treating the possibility as both a potential hazard and a rare scientific opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://orbitaltoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Asteroid-2024-YR4-Moon.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold surges past $5,500 to record high on safe-haven demand</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-surges-past-5400-dollars-m7Q8mjTQScqu3KzzUYdQ1Q</link>
      <description>Gold prices vaulted past $5,400 per ounce on Wednesday, extending an explosive rally that has seen the precious metal gain more than 25% since the start of the year, as investors sought refuge from mounting geopolitical risks and a weakening dollar ahead of the Federal Reserve's decision to hold interest rates steady.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The yellow metal climbed as much as 4% during the session, with spot gold reaching $5,393.19 an ounce and U.S. gold futures for February settling 4.3% higher at $5,303.60, according to Reuters. By early Thursday trading in Asia, gold had pushed above $5,500 per ounce, marking gains of more than $500 over four sessions since first breaking the $5,000 barrier on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/INGIB4VICZKTZJ7OYOZBJJO6VE.jpg?auth=1275bd6aff3189a1763e176ed9782287daeb0ee17e0ea358a6eddfebac72b434&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio says Donetsk territory is last major hurdle in Ukraine talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-brokered-peace-talks-contin-kmmZ8RdIRnGszHY1V5yhaQ</link>
      <description>Negotiations to end the nearly four-year war between Russia and Ukraine have narrowed to a single, pivotal issue: control over Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region. U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio told the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on Wednesday that resolving the territorial dispute remains "very difficult," even as both sides prepare for another round of talks in Abu Dhabi scheduled for February 1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"It's still a gap, but at least we've been able to narrow down the issue set to one central one," Rubio said during testimony. He indicated there may be American participation in the upcoming discussions, though President Donald Trump's key envoys—Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner—will not attend.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769653387/getty_uploads/2258665596_bxi8ur.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starmer and Xi meet in Beijing to reset UK-China relations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/starmer-meets-xi-jinping-to-re-DTvi7QzFSzCnHKf5iIJGgg</link>
      <description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer met with Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing on Thursday, marking the first visit by a UK leader to China in eight years as the two nations seek to repair relations strained by years of tension over security concerns and human rights issues.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At the Great Hall of the People, Xi acknowledged that the UK-China relationship had "gone through some twists and turns that did not serve the interests of our countries," while declaring China "ready to develop with the UK a long-term and consistent strategic partnership." Starmer responded by calling for a "more sophisticated relationship" with Beijing, emphasizing that "China is a vital player on the global stage."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/BCHMTAR5Z5JZLKAVOKWHYE2GKY.jpg?auth=4792e921f44370f0ae7af73d0978883caac4a30f9d7aff22b07f197d005823e5&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change made southern Africa flooding 40% worse, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/climate-change-intensifies-ext-DIEPJthNRNugGfjDrMN96A</link>
      <description>A rapid new scientific assessment has linked deadly flooding across southern Africa to human-caused warming and shifting climate patterns, as large parts of the continent lurch between extremes—deluges in the south and intensifying dryness across the Horn of Africa.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a report released Thursday, the World Weather Attribution (WWA) initiative said the kind of extreme multi-day rainfall that fuelled recent floods in Mozambique, South Africa, Zimbabwe and Eswatini has become about 40% more intense since pre-industrial times, based on observational datasets. The study also found that the current weak La Niña made such extreme rainfall spells around five times more likely and boosted their intensity by about 22%—a compounding effect layered on top of long-term warming.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.dw.com/image/75575128_605.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK-Korean team begins first drilling into main Thwaites Glacier</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/antarctic-expeditions-reveal-n-5i3IGb1OQMOfrSdu7bNBPg</link>
      <description>International research teams are conducting multiple expeditions across Antarctica this month, collecting unprecedented data about ice sheet stability, ancient climate patterns, and the forces driving glacier melt in a warming world.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In one of the largest coordinated scientific pushes to the frozen continent in recent years, researchers from Australia, the UK, Korea, the US, and several European nations are racing against time and extreme conditions to gather information that could reshape understanding of future sea-level rise.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://thwaitesglacier.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/The%2520hot%2520water%2520drill%2520rig%2520and%2520Icefin_David%2520Vaughan.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP authorizes $10B buyback as cloud revenue hits record</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sap-q4-2025-results-cloud-reve-P9goJjwTRhmB2zHyatgFng</link>
      <description>SAP reported fourth-quarter and full-year 2025 results showing continued momentum in its cloud business, with cloud revenue rising to €5.61 billion in Q4 and total cloud backlog reaching a record €77 billion. Alongside the earnings, the company authorized a new two-year share repurchase program of up to €10 billion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Total revenue for the quarter was €9.7 billion, matching a company-compiled consensus, as demand for cloud software and related services held up amid a softer macro backdrop.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.techmonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/29/2025/01/shutterstock_2423167951.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicist proposes time emerges from information, not entropy</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/physicists-question-whether-ti-KmFzvPmPTsKznw5NtcFpew</link>
      <description>Time feels like the most basic feature of everyday life—clocks tick, causes precede effects, and memories seem to pile up in one direction. But a new strand of physics research is reviving an old, unsettling possibility: **time may not be fundamental at all**, and what humans experience as “flow” could instead be a byproduct of how the universe stores and spreads information.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In an essay published January 28, physicist Florian Neukart of Leiden University argued that modern physics still lacks a unified account of time, in part because its two pillars treat it differently: **Einstein’s relativity** folds time into spacetime, while **quantum mechanics** typically assumes time as an external parameter. Attempts to combine the two, he wrote, can even yield equations in which time “disappears,” a long-running difficulty known as the “problem of time”.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/713591/original/file-20260121-56-ahajey.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;rect=0%252C348%252C4176%252C2088&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam, EU upgrade ties to strategic partnership amid U.S. tariff pressure</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/vietnam-and-eu-elevate-ties-am-ea0IQ3tDRniqiYlYnfLUNQ</link>
      <description>Vietnam and the European Union announced Thursday that they have upgraded their relationship to a comprehensive strategic partnership, a top-tier diplomatic status in Vietnam’s system, as both sides seek to broaden international partnerships amid disruptions linked to higher U.S. tariffs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decision was unveiled during a visit to Hanoi by European Council President Antonio Costa, and was framed by Vietnamese leaders as a political milestone rather than a deal with binding commitments. Vietnam’s President Luong Cuong called the upgrade “a historic milestone,” according to Reuters.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.barrons.com/asset/external-media/afp/AFP9424869023870230802764282382811411976092---1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese researchers report perovskite solar efficiency record</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-scientists-boost-solar-aGdyZdHyTz2Y7zsd_CVmAg</link>
      <description>A cluster of Chinese-led research results published and announced in January points to rapid progress on two long-running solar challenges: pushing conversion efficiency higher while keeping cells and panels stable under heat, humidity and uneven real-world conditions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In one of the latest headline-grabbers, trade outlets reported that Shenzhen-based perovskite developer SolaEon said it reached 27.87% power-conversion efficiency on a single-junction perovskite cell, with the measurement certified by China’s National Photovoltaic Industry Metrology and Testing Center (NPVM). The reports described the result as a laboratory-scale device, underscoring that the road from record cells to mass-produced modules still runs through durability testing and manufacturing scale-up.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/CVTEjYL7w_2v66ng1XgeOg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_cool_down_737/0c2dd0b8e8ae69a0dff9e8ae72d6ac81" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Webb confirms most distant galaxy ever observed</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/james-webb-telescope-maps-dark-wl.4RV2iSGGzE6_AsX8acw</link>
      <description>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope has delivered two landmark discoveries this week, producing the most detailed map of dark matter ever created and confirming the most distant galaxy ever observed, offering new windows into the universe's invisible architecture and earliest moments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dark matter map, published January 26 in the journal Nature Astronomy, captures nearly 800,000 galaxies in the constellation Sextans and reveals the universe's hidden scaffolding with twice the resolution of any previous map. Just two days later, astronomers announced the confirmation of galaxy MoM-z14, which existed just 280 million years after the Big Bang—making it the most distant known object in the universe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/VKw2siavwce_5UrGje.JbQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD01MDA-/https://d29szjachogqwa.cloudfront.net/images/user-uploaded/Webb_Telescope_MoM-z14.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds water can survive near Earth's core in superionic state</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/superionic-state-enables-long-4HyRAmdWTZ.pRBFR49vX2g</link>
      <description>New research published January 28 in Science Advances reveals that water can survive the extreme conditions of Earth's deep lower mantle by entering a superionic state, challenging the long-held assumption that most hydrous minerals release their water at high temperatures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Scientists from the Institute of Geochemistry of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (IGCAS) used molecular dynamics simulations combining ab initio and deep-learning potential methods to study how water behaves near Earth's core-mantle boundary. The findings suggest that ancient water from Earth's early stages may have been preserved over geological timescales, accumulating as a long-term reservoir near the base of the mantle.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.thebrighterside.news/uploads/2026/01/water-3.webp?format=auto&amp;optimize=high&amp;width=1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford, Osaka teams advance light-based quantum computing</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/researchers-advance-light-base-BOUmB9KbRrStVyzSAuYRgw</link>
      <description>Two research teams are using light to tackle one of quantum computing’s core hurdles: how to scale fragile atomic systems from laboratory demonstrations into machines with enough qubits to do useful work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In results published over the past week, Stanford researchers reported an optical-cavity “readout” platform designed to pull information quickly from many atom-based qubits at once, while a University of Osaka group detailed a nanophotonic routing scheme aimed at delivering multiple laser colors across trapped-ion chips without a tangle of free-space optics.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/new-light-based-platfo-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China unveils plans for space tourism and orbital AI data centers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-plans-space-tourism-and-4LbkB1KkQTiaJh.5VQ2dfA</link>
      <description>China unveiled ambitious plans this week to develop space tourism and launch orbiting artificial intelligence data centers within five years, escalating competition with the United States in what both nations see as the next frontier for commercial and strategic dominance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;State media reported on Thursday that China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC), the country's primary space contractor, has committed to establishing gigawatt-class "space digital intelligence infrastructure" as part of its 15th Five-Year Plan spanning 2026-2030. The initiative aims to process Earth-generated data in orbit by combining computing power, storage capabilities, and transmission bandwidth, according to CCTV.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_%21RWlT%21%2Cw_1200%2Ch_675%2Cc_fill%2Cf_jpg%2Cq_auto:good%2Cfl_progressive:steep%2Cg_auto/https%253A%252F%252Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fpublic%252Fimages%252F7e49472c-3117-4edf-8029-3ad11db7d91a_3746x2082.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP shares tumble after cloud backlog growth misses expectations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sap-shares-plunge-11-percent-a-_9in.bjsStqUWHZBrKMJ9w</link>
      <description>SAP SE, Europe's largest software company, suffered its steepest single-day drop since October 2020 on Thursday after reporting cloud contract backlog growth that fell short of investor expectations, extending a selloff that has erased approximately $150 billion from its market capitalization since its 2025 peak.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shares of the German enterprise software giant fell as much as 14% in early European trading before settling around an 11% decline, hitting their lowest level since June 2024. The selloff came despite strong full-year operating profit and record free cash flow, underscoring how closely investors are scrutinizing cloud metrics amid growing concerns about AI disruption in the software sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iAjAj3jDg9p0/v0/-1x-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper hits record high as speculation and weak dollar drive rally</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/copper-prices-hit-record-highs-DGOKFQesRTWBoT7iHnyeHQ</link>
      <description>Copper surged past $14,000 per metric ton on Thursday, posting its largest single-day gain in over 16 years as a wave of speculative trading in China and a persistently weak U.S. dollar fueled a broader rally across global metals markets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Futures on the London Metal Exchange rose as much as 7.9% to reach a record $14,125 per ton before pulling back slightly in early European trading. The most-active contract on the Shanghai Futures Exchange jumped 6.35% to 108,740 yuan ($15,652) per metric ton, also setting an all-time high.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/qHMzUBfWaiu5XWhoBuyGfg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/5ab527b5ba79f84b09e3aaeaff194d6a" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyundai Q4 profit drops 40% as US tariffs cost $2.87B</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hyundai-q4-profit-drops-40-per-lfpf5guuTTioXQp6S96F7g</link>
      <description>Hyundai Motor reported a worse-than-expected 40 percent fall in fourth-quarter operating profit on Thursday, as U.S. tariffs cost the South Korean automaker an estimated 4.1 trillion won ($2.87 billion) last year. The company warned of continued challenges in 2026 but forecast improved sales and profit margins despite looming threats of higher levies from Washington.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The October-December results mark the third consecutive quarterly profit decline for the world's third-largest automaking group by sales. Hyundai booked operating profit of 1.7 trillion won ($1.19 billion) for the quarter, down from 2.8 trillion won in the same period a year earlier, missing the 2.7 trillion won consensus estimate from analysts surveyed by LSEG.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4DZJ5FHR6ZIGXNUGXACCKTXK24.jpg?auth=a1f67ef66144ea8890982ba5dc72152122baf4a849a061ad5eeffc0049faab9c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canal Plus shares surge after projecting synergies from MultiChoice deal</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/canal-plus-targets-over-400-mi-L36v1aZwQ7WqMjaleaM23w</link>
      <description>Canal+ on Thursday announced it expects to deliver over 400 million euros in annual cost synergies and over 300 million euros in free cash flow synergies from 2030 following its $3 billion acquisition of South African broadcaster MultiChoice Group, sending shares to a record high.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Paris-based media company's stock rose approximately 14% after executives outlined synergy targets that analysts described as exceeding expectations. Bank of America raised its price target to 450 pence from 400 pence, calling the projected savings "meaningfully above expectations" of 100 million to 200 million euros.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/76G2TQJCHZO7DDFNOIDQWOM5FY.jpg?auth=4441cde2003e4c28e8a9162af2cfee1f4fe65ec34ea66820a78f66f24b765f56&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold snap threatens to delay NASA's Artemis II moon mission</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/artemis-ii-faces-possible-laun-CHtr_vsFQFCNgyUV1nFJKQ</link>
      <description>NASA is watching an unusual Florida cold snap that could complicate final preparations for Artemis II, the agency’s first crewed mission around the Moon since Apollo. Forecasts calling for overnight lows near freezing along the Space Coast have raised the risk that temperature constraints could interrupt a key prelaunch fueling test—and potentially push back a launch planned no earlier than early February.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Artemis II Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft, now on the pad at Kennedy Space Center, must complete a “wet dress rehearsal” before NASA sets an official liftoff date. The test involves loading the rocket with cryogenic propellants and running a full countdown without actually launching.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/QnXhKmI0No05ggLPdtkGQA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/usa_today_news_641/f0a8e3a565f6fbe758afbac4d396454c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian researchers report advances in solar panel cooling, perovskite efficiency</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/hydrogel-coating-and-perovskit-icvPRfSgQC6BMUMswfPPsw</link>
      <description>Two research teams in Asia have reported advances aimed at squeezing more electricity from solar hardware in the real world: one by cooling conventional silicon panels at their hottest failure-prone points, the other by pushing perovskite technology closer to scalable, high-efficiency modules.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In Hong Kong, researchers at The Hong Kong Polytechnic University said a hydrogel-based layer can reduce “hot spot” temperatures on panels while raising output, a result they argue could be especially relevant for dense cities with rooftop and building-integrated solar. In South Korea, a team led by Gwangju Institute of Science and Technology (GIST) reported a perovskite mini-module with 22.56% efficiency, addressing a key hurdle in making perovskites perform reliably as device area increases.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.polyu.edu.hk/-/media/department/home/media-release/2026/0120/photo-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
