<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:34:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese researchers train AI to 'mumble' to itself</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/oist-researchers-boost-ai-lear-_wz6vOvHQ9GElUm_tWRKwg</link>
      <description>New research from Japan suggests artificial intelligence systems may benefit from a surprisingly human trait: talking to themselves. Scientists at the Okinawa Institute of Science and Technology (OIST) have demonstrated that AI models learn more efficiently, adapt to new situations more easily, and handle multiple tasks better when trained to use internal "mumbling" alongside short-term memory systems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published in Neural Computation on January 28, reveal that combining self-directed inner speech with working memory architecture allows AI to generalize across different tasks more effectively while requiring far less training data than conventional approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://images.ctfassets.net/mrbo2ykgx5lt/24235/091980aca978f37a0fc40e1a1f0028ce/neuroscience-brain-simulation-algorithm-exascale.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesian stocks plunge after MSCI freezes index additions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-shares-mixed-as-s-p-500-ZuEcx3gSTGGvtsVQlBJ5mg</link>
      <description>Asian markets diverged sharply on Wednesday as investors weighed a fresh record on Wall Street and record-high gold prices against significant regional headwinds, including a plunge in Indonesian stocks and a weakening U.S. dollar ahead of the Federal Reserve's interest rate decision.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The S&amp;P 500 closed at a record high on Tuesday, climbing 0.41% to 6,978.60 — its fourth record close of 2026 and fifth consecutive day of gains. The tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite also advanced, rising 0.91%. The Dow Jones Industrial Average, however, fell amid pressure on health insurer stocks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://english.news.cn/20250409/ef4f3ccc7405447c9508cb7760dd5f2a/20250409ef4f3ccc7405447c9508cb7760dd5f2a_ChkhgeE007009_20250409_CBMFN0A001.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU to elevate Vietnam ties to highest level during Costa visit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-and-vietnam-to-boost-cooper-6nLPhi0CTJKgMYtNegEnnA</link>
      <description>The European Union and Vietnam are set to deepen cooperation on critical minerals, semiconductors, and "trusted" 5G communications infrastructure during European Council President António Costa's visit to Hanoi this week, according to a draft joint statement reviewed by Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The eight-page document, scheduled to be adopted on Thursday when Costa meets Vietnamese leaders, will elevate diplomatic ties to Vietnam's highest level—placing the EU on the same tier as the United States, China, and Russia.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://bcp.cdnchinhphu.vn/zoom/670_420/344443456812359680/2025/6/10/hoidongchauau-1749520381261285754800-27-0-513-777-crop-1749520383980225500531.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope may have found birthplaces of massive black holes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/jwst-discovers-potential-birth-.pYtekHLTsyIBFbvvHIHNA</link>
      <description>A growing body of research suggests that mysterious objects called "Little Red Dots," discovered by the James Webb Space Telescope, may represent the first observational evidence of direct-collapse black holes forming in the early universe—potentially solving one of astronomy's most vexing puzzles.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These compact, red objects, identified through deep extragalactic surveys conducted by the JWST since it began operations in 2022, existed when the universe was less than a billion years old. Scientists now believe they could be witnessing the birth of the most massive black holes in the cosmos.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.princeton.edu/sites/default/files/styles/scale_1440/public/images/2023/11/Abell2744_JWST_3000x1688.jpg?itok=agEjSC5H" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold hits record high above $5,300 as dollar tumbles</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-surges-past-5280-to-new-r-lOP2AxoRTMqSJhHKi9.fyg</link>
      <description>Gold prices breached the $5,300 mark for the first time on Wednesday, hitting an all-time high of $5,311.31 per ounce as the U.S. dollar plunged to a near four-year low ahead of the Federal Reserve's first interest rate decision of 2026.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The precious metal climbed as much as 2.3% during the session, extending a blistering rally that has seen prices surge more than 20% since the start of the year. The gains followed a 3.4% jump on Tuesday, the largest single-day increase since April.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/DHcxLHaRtai2VS4W5Ch4VQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2026-01/8e3d91e0-fc23-11f0-bdfd-60445a49298c" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 50 million in West Africa face acute hunger by summer, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/officials-warn-of-climate-chan-rSvJV2OLQlurCizevGCgYQ</link>
      <description>A worsening pattern of climate-driven displacement and hunger is taking shape across the globe, as rising sea levels threaten coastal communities from Liberia to Hawaii while crop losses deepen food insecurity affecting tens of millions in Africa.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The United Nations World Food Programme warned in January that 318 million people now face crisis levels of hunger or worse globally—more than double the figure recorded in 2019. In West Africa and the Sahel alone, the Food and Agriculture Organization reported this week that 41.8 million people are currently experiencing acute food insecurity, a number projected to climb to 52.8 million during the June-August lean season without urgent intervention.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2024/in-niger-people-were-f.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European stocks slip as investors await Fed rate decision</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/european-stocks-fall-as-invest-82BEr14uSduQJNdeQDD8Eg</link>
      <description>European stock markets traded lower on Wednesday as investors exercised caution ahead of the Federal Reserve's first interest rate decision of 2026, while contrasting corporate earnings results created a mixed sector backdrop.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The CAC 40 in Paris dropped about 0.9% to around 8,080 points at midday, weighed down heavily by disappointing results from luxury giant LVMH. The FTSE 100 in London fell 0.4% to 10,165.25, while the DAX in Frankfurt slipped 0.2%. The pan-European Stoxx Europe 600 index declined 0.4%.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/V2JHKABKQNLP7LQKMJFYTPEHPI.jpg?auth=9b6f7321ed9fa2c17ff8e4a2eaad27cfe9a0a93ebecf2953d9bcb0c9cded2a7e&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dollar recovers from four-year low as traders await Fed decision</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/dollar-recovers-after-four-yea-1VOr.hIPS6.Ey_F_7ZFeGQ</link>
      <description>The U.S. dollar clawed back some ground on Wednesday after tumbling to a four-year low, as markets turned their attention to the Federal Reserve's first policy decision of 2026.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;President Donald Trump's casual dismissal of the currency's recent slide triggered the sharpest single-day drop in the greenback since the tariff upheaval in April. When asked Tuesday whether the dollar had declined too much, Trump told reporters in Iowa, "No, I think it's great," adding that it should "just seek its own level." Traders interpreted the remarks as a green light to sell the U.S. currency aggressively.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/bIlqmosaIcVBn.eM_sETWw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/dea2377cf8df0f44d5113ea36ea41485" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musk eyes June planetary alignment for record SpaceX IPO</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/musk-plans-spacex-ipo-for-june-uzxPRo4MRgColT0nhVCnag</link>
      <description>Elon Musk has proposed timing SpaceX's potential initial public offering to coincide with a rare planetary alignment in mid-June, according to the Financial Times. The rocket maker is targeting a $1.5 trillion valuation and aims to raise up to $50 billion, which would make it the largest IPO in history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company is eyeing mid-June when Jupiter and Venus will appear very close together in the sky for the first time in more than three years, five people familiar with the matter told the Financial Times. On June 8 and 9, the two planets will be positioned within roughly 1.6 degrees of each other, about the width of a thumb held at arm's length, according to the nonprofit Planetary Society. Musk's 55th birthday on June 28 was also a factor in the timing decision, sources said.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/SIEU4L73zv8kGmqB7tTi7A--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bloomberg_holding_pen_162/3c213431a99fd4793326b8619d0a899e" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China's solar and wind capacity surpasses coal for first time</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-solar-and-wind-capacity-EHntyMxJR.yccrBWoBxeSw</link>
      <description>China installed a record 315 gigawatts of new solar capacity in 2025 alongside 119 gigawatts of wind power, pushing combined wind and solar capacity past coal-based thermal generation for the first time in the nation's history, according to official data released by the National Energy Administration on January 28.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The figures mark a structural shift in the energy mix of the world's largest greenhouse gas emitter. By the end of December, China's cumulative wind and solar capacity reached 1.84 terawatts, exceeding thermal power by 300 million kilowatts and accounting for 47.3 percent of the country's total installed power generation capacity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://photos.watchmedier.dk/Images/17829631/mznwe6/ALTERNATES/schema-16_9/24353468342510-3600x2027ma-jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump warns Iran 'time is running out' as US naval fleet approaches</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-warns-iran-time-running-rkEJZHQeRcuuhVG7KmsENQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump issued an urgent ultimatum to Iran on Wednesday, warning that "time is running out" to negotiate a nuclear agreement as a massive US naval fleet approaches the region. The warning escalates tensions weeks after deadly protests rocked Iran and following last year's US strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Hopefully Iran will quickly 'come to the table' and negotiate a fair and equitable deal — NO NUCLEAR WEAPONS — one that is good for all parties," Trump wrote in a social media post, according to Reuters. "Time is running out, it is truly of the essence!"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump explicitly referenced the previous US military strikes on Iran, warning that "the next attack will be far worse" if Tehran does not comply. The president also noted that a "huge armada is making its way to Iran with great speed and power" and would "fulfill its mission with speed and violence if necessary".</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://e3.365dm.com/26/01/1600x900/skynews-uss-abraham-lincoln_7144024.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaked draft shows Trump's Gaza board would grant him sweeping power</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-s-board-of-peace-grants-co8bUHTHSCSdCDc.iMtBTw</link>
      <description>A leaked document has revealed that President Donald Trump's newly established Board of Peace would grant him extraordinary authority over Gaza's governance, reconstruction, and legal framework, drawing sharp criticism from humanitarian leaders and sparking divisions among U.S. allies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The unsigned draft resolution, dated January 22 and obtained by Drop Site News from three independent sources, shows that Trump would serve as chairman with power to sign all resolutions into force, approve military commanders, and appoint key officials throughout the governing apparatus. The document states the Board would hold "all transitional legislative and executive authority, emergency powers, and the administration of justice" over Gaza.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/22300319-clean-orentrumpboardofp-00-00-22-28-still002.jpg?c=16x9&amp;q=w_1280%2Cc_fill" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bank of Canada holds rates steady, warns Fed independence threats add to global instability</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/fed-and-bank-of-canada-hold-in-x4UkpM.9S7.r8KHrocdcEg</link>
      <description>The Bank of Canada on Wednesday maintained its benchmark interest rate at 2.25 percent, while the U.S. Federal Reserve is widely expected to keep its policy rate unchanged in the 3.5-3.75 percent range when it announces its decision later today. Both central banks are navigating elevated uncertainty, with Governor Tiff Macklem warning that threats to the Fed's independence add to global economic instability.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/TZ5P3SS5IZL5HE6KA4CIMMIHLU.jpg?auth=be1acfad6715cf76f31dadcee85218502e911057ec907cf2a47fba402b72c599&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast-growing trees threaten forest diversity worldwide, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/fast-growing-trees-threaten-fo-68x8sfWkT3S4p3f_KysSyA</link>
      <description>The world's forests are undergoing a transformation that may weaken their ecological integrity for decades to come. A comprehensive international study published January 27 in Nature Plants warns that fast-growing tree species are increasingly dominating forest ecosystems worldwide, displacing slower-growing native trees and reducing both biodiversity and long-term carbon storage capacity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research team analyzed more than 31,000 tree species globally and found that forests are becoming homogenized as fast-growing varieties such as acacia, eucalyptus, poplar, and pine outcompete specialized native species. Nearly 41 percent of naturalized tree species—those that have established wild populations outside their native ranges—possess traits like rapid growth and small leaves that make them well-suited to disturbed environments but unable to fulfill the ecological roles of the species they replace.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://sustainability.stanford.edu/sites/sustainability/files/styles/card_1900x950/public/media/earth_news/Forest-trees-Michigan-by_dennis_buchner-via_unsplash.jpg?h=8a6d63f3&amp;itok=OwxfcZSd" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Reserve holds interest rates steady amid Trump pressure</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/federal-reserve-holds-interest-Eko25I5dTnyfr6XEJ7KBYQ</link>
      <description>The Federal Reserve on Wednesday announced it will leave its benchmark interest rate unchanged at 3.5%-3.75%, marking a pause after three consecutive quarter-point cuts late last year. The widely anticipated decision comes as Chair Jerome Powell navigates unprecedented political pressure from President Donald Trump and a Justice Department investigation that Powell has called a "pretext" for influencing monetary policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108251474-1768259127895-gettyimages-2251234549-_s018465_4pcnj0j0.jpeg?v=1769531538&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>East Africa faces drought and faster tectonic rifting as south floods</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/east-africa-faces-faster-rift-ZBcy1FyLQVabTUnFTBkwog</link>
      <description>East Africa is contending with a dual climate crisis: new scientific research shows that millennia of drying conditions are accelerating the continent's tectonic split, while the region confronts a severe drought in the north and catastrophic flooding in the south.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static.temblor.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/kenya-rift-split-8m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexico suspends oil shipments to Cuba amid US pressure</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mexico-halts-oil-shipments-to-n5z8EzJcTH6tbCuudh9KKw</link>
      <description>Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum confirmed Tuesday that her government has at least temporarily suspended oil shipments to Cuba, a move that comes as the Trump administration intensifies efforts to economically isolate the Caribbean island nation. While Sheinbaum insisted the decision was "sovereign" and not made under pressure from the United States, the timing follows weeks of escalating American rhetoric demanding an end to Cuba's energy lifelines.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;State oil company Petróleos Mexicanos (Pemex) was scheduled to send a crude shipment aboard the vessel Swift Galaxy in mid-January but removed the cargo from its schedule without explanation, according to documents reviewed by Bloomberg. The cancellation leaves Cuba facing deepening fuel shortages and extended blackouts, with the island already producing only half the electricity it needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/en/united_press_international_articles_356/191d427ab799669d5dd1fd7597f627c9" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German chancellor warns weak dollar burdens exporters</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/merz-urges-us-to-honor-eu-trad-BgtODoxoTe66Wd97a.XzhQ</link>
      <description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz warned Wednesday that the weakening dollar has become a "considerable additional burden" for Germany's export-oriented economy, while calling on Washington to uphold trade commitments made with the European Union last year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"We will have to assert ourselves globally against a weak dollar and a strong euro," Merz told reporters in Berlin. "We simply have to become more competitive and stronger, especially given the currency exchange rates."</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.bundesregierung.de/resource/image/2354572/16x9/1023/575/4528c2d871f6b24f2395d3113136291d/C13A948D0B756B605745975DCC650140/oport-friedrich-merz.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta to report Q4 earnings amid AI spending surge, layoffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/meta-prepares-q4-2025-earnings-H6xu6Va9Q3mOqtQwxpmLtg</link>
      <description>Meta Platforms, Inc. will announce its fourth-quarter 2025 earnings after market close Wednesday as Wall Street scrutinizes the social media giant's aggressive artificial intelligence spending and recent workforce cuts in its virtual reality division.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Analysts surveyed by Bloomberg expect the company to report revenue of approximately $58.4 billion, a 21% year-over-year increase, with earnings per share of around $8.16 to $8.21. Bank of America analysts project the company could beat consensus estimates, forecasting revenue of $59.2 billion and EPS of $8.27.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/10/29/multimedia/META-EARNINGS-1-jkvf/META-EARNINGS-1-jkvf-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft shares fall despite beating cloud revenue expectations</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/microsoft-cloud-revenue-grows-.FDTth66SOushhaza8y_Qw</link>
      <description>Microsoft reported stronger-than-expected quarterly results on Wednesday, but its shares fell more than 7% in extended trading as investors questioned whether the tech giant's cloud growth justifies the scale of its artificial intelligence investments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company posted fiscal second-quarter revenue of $81.3 billion, up 17% year-over-year and slightly above the $80.3 billion analysts had expected. Earnings per share of $5.16 also beat Wall Street estimates of $3.92. Azure, the cloud computing division closely watched by investors, grew 39%—narrowly edging past the 38.8% consensus estimate.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/zRXQazeHHQdEuu9K7cow0Q--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02ODU-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-07/8ee90540-cac7-11ea-b8ba-1c6dec32d9d2" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
