<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Arctic sees surge in unprecedented extreme weather events</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/arctic-records-hottest-year-an-kWOng5ujQgiquRM2n01mQg</link>
      <description>The Arctic recorded its hottest year since measurements began 125 years ago, while a new study reveals the region has entered an unprecedented era of extreme weather events that threaten ecosystems and communities across the polar north.

Temperatures from October 2024 through September 2025 were the warmest in the Arctic since 1900, according to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's annual Arctic Report Card released in December[1][2][3]. The past decade represents the 10 warmest years on record for the region[1][2][3]. In March 2025, Arctic winter sea ice reached its lowest annual maximum extent in the 47-year satellite record[1][4][5].

Research published this week in the journal Science Advances documents a sharp increase in extreme weather events across the Arctic over the past 30 years[6][7][8]. The study, led by the Finnish Meteorological Institute with an international team including the University of Sheffield, found that approximately one-third of the Arctic land area has recently begun experiencing extreme weather events that had not occurred there previously[6][7][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--08OKc3Uw--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/E08fPsSeFwAFE8PjPHzobQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_cool_down_737/429ca205e01bc31ad03b5c9beec61698" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shell shares drop on weak trading, chemicals losses</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/shell-shares-fall-after-weak-q-zO.pyuJ0Rs.UFCqWVEXRHQ</link>
      <description>Shell shares dropped as much as 2.6% Thursday after the energy giant warned of weaker fourth-quarter trading results and losses in its chemicals division, raising doubts about whether the company can maintain its $3.5 billion quarterly share buyback program[1][2][3][4].

The London-based company said trading results for the fourth quarter of 2025 would be "significantly lower" than the previous three months, with its chemicals and products segment expected to swing to an adjusted loss[1][5][3][6]. Oil trading represents a major portion of Shell's trading operations, alongside refined products such as diesel and gasoline[1][3][7].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--dZ9jpUYj--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108094052-1738158569863-gettyimages-2151322364-01-bb1_2324-_a8y3vjph.jpeg%3Fv%3D1750866394%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French, Greek farmers blockade cities ahead of EU-Mercosur vote</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/french-and-greek-farmers-prote-n_.WwgBKS8W.Dm98ZKcrTQ</link>
      <description>Farmers in France and Greece launched major tractor protests on Thursday, blocking highways and storming central Paris to oppose the European Union's looming free trade agreement with South American nations, escalating a months-long battle over agricultural policy just ahead of a critical vote on Friday[1][2][3].

Around 100 tractors forced their way into the French capital, bypassing police barriers to reach landmarks including the Eiffel Tower and the Arc de Triomphe[1][4]. In Greece, farmers initiated a 48-hour blockade of major highways and toll stations, shutting down key routes including the main highway connecting Athens to Thessaloniki[3][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--h-lwjimz--/t_thumbnail/https://s.abcnews.com/images/International/wirestory_a1b0b7caff7ed163ddbbd43b3bf0306d_16x9_992.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antarctic iceberg and Thwaites Glacier show instability</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/antarctica-s-doomsday-glacier-vaK6yeTWQxC_GB_Rh03KCA</link>
      <description>Satellite observations and seismic monitoring have revealed alarming developments at two of Antarctica's most closely watched ice formations, raising fresh concerns about the stability of the continent's ice sheet and its potential contribution to sea level rise.

NASA's Terra satellite captured images on December 26, 2025, showing iceberg A-23A covered in extensive pools of blue meltwater, indicating the massive berg could disintegrate within days or weeks[1]. Separately, a study published in Geophysical Research Letters detected more than 360 glacial earthquakes near Antarctica's Thwaites Glacier between 2010 and 2023, with 245 concentrated at the marine end of the glacier known as the "Doomsday Glacier"[2][3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--yl2VYo80--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/3600x2025%2B0%2B198/resize/1400/quality/100/format/jpeg/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fde%252Fe7%252Fb0b6d0aa4bc2ba2153f034834c82%252Fgettyimages-2195644962.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tree bark microbes remove millions of tons of greenhouse gases yearly</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tree-bark-microbes-remove-gree-3HGn3k.LQ2e5lYd8tf73nA</link>
      <description>Australian researchers have discovered that trillions of microorganisms living in tree bark are silently removing greenhouse gases from the atmosphere, potentially amplifying the climate benefits of forests beyond their well-known carbon dioxide absorption.

A study published in Science reveals that bark-dwelling microbes consume methane, hydrogen, and carbon monoxide—all gases that contribute to global warming or enhance its effects[1][2]. The research, conducted over five years by teams from Monash University and Southern Cross University, examined eight common tree species across eastern Australia, including wetland, coastal, and upland forests[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--uE3DfEjQ--/t_thumbnail/https://images.theconversation.com/files/703281/original/file-20251119-56-j7k6xd.jpg%3Fixlib%3Drb-4.1.0%26q%3D45%26auto%3Dformat%26w%3D1000%26fit%3Dclip" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio to meet with Danish, Greenland officials on Trump acquisition push</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-revives-push-to-buy-gree-ZTkT8Js3RaKQRjFUMxUBbQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's renewed push to acquire Greenland intensified this week as U.S. officials discussed offering direct payments to residents and Secretary of State Marco Rubio announced plans to meet with Danish officials next week. The White House confirmed Wednesday that Trump and his national security team are "actively discussing" what a potential purchase would look like[1][2], despite firm rejections from both Denmark and Greenland.

According to four sources familiar with White House deliberations, U.S. officials have discussed sending lump-sum payments ranging from $10,000 to $100,000 per person to Greenland's 57,000 residents to encourage them to secede from Denmark and potentially join the United States[3][2]. At the upper end, such payments would total nearly $6 billion. The administration is also exploring a Compact of Free Association, similar to agreements with Pacific island nations, which would require Greenland to first become independent from Denmark[3][2].

Trump has justified his interest by citing national security concerns and the island's strategic Arctic location. "We need Greenland from the standpoint of national security, and Denmark isn't going to be able to do it," Trump told reporters Sunday[4][2]. The administration has not ruled out military intervention, though officials say they prefer diplomatic or economic means[1][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MPx8tgbw--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108249430-17678037262026-01-07t163452z_843971512_rc2gwiart3yv_rtrmadp_0_usa-venezuela-congress.jpeg%3Fv%3D1767803756%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protest death toll hits 45 as internet blackout imposed</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-protests-death-toll-climb-LHeuOupaQnODBIz4QdqEYQ</link>
      <description>At least 45 protesters, including eight minors, have been killed during 12 days of nationwide demonstrations in Iran, with Wednesday marking the deadliest single day of unrest as security forces killed 13 people, according to Norway-based Iran Human Rights[1]. The protests, which began in Tehran's Grand Bazaar on December 28 over economic grievances, have now spread to all 31 of Iran's provinces and evolved into broader calls for regime change[2][1].

Internet monitoring group NetBlocks reported a nationwide internet blackout on Thursday as authorities intensified efforts to suppress the demonstrations[3][4]. "The evidence shows that the scope of crackdown is becoming more violent and more extensive every day," said Iran Human Rights director Mahmood Amiry-Moghaddam, adding that hundreds more have been wounded and over 2,000 arrested[1].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--5K8qBVEE--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/07/multimedia/07int-iran-protests-zghc/07int-iran-protests-zghc-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese study finds urban air contains millions of microplastic particles per cubic meter</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-find-microplastics-8wtfXcjNSKO6RMHJfJwuwg</link>
      <description>Researchers in China have identified urban atmospheres as primary reservoirs for microplastic and nanoplastic pollution, finding concentrations up to a million times higher than previously detected using traditional methods.

A study published in Science Advances on January 7 by scientists from the Institute of Earth Environment of the Chinese Academy of Sciences revealed that microplastics and nanoplastics accumulate in city air at levels ranging from 140,000 to 180,000 particles per cubic meter in the two Chinese megacities of Guangzhou and Xi'an[1][2][3]. The research marks the first detection of nanoplastics as small as 200 nanometers in complex environmental samples[4][1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Rv6Ojerm--/t_thumbnail/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_independent_635/0c9cdd11020c9e1300e0f33e9a641433" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN says US must pay dues despite Trump order to quit 66 groups</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-urges-us-to-fund-agencies-a-KZ8P45JBSLKF1HPy0q5MvQ</link>
      <description>The United Nations said Thursday the United States has a legal obligation to continue funding U.N. agencies, one day after President Donald Trump signed an order withdrawing from 66 international organizations, including 31 affiliated with the world body[1][2][3].

Secretary-General Antonio Guterres expressed regret over the decision and stressed that assessed contributions to the U.N. regular budget and peacekeeping operations "are a legal obligation under the UN Charter for all Member States, including the United States," according to spokesman Stephane Dujarric[1][4][5]. The statement came as U.N. officials said they learned of the withdrawal through news reports and White House social media posts Wednesday, with no formal notification from the Trump administration[1][2].

The executive order, which followed a yearlong review, targets organizations the White House says promote "radical climate policies, global governance, and ideological programs that conflict with U.S. sovereignty and economic strength"[6][7][8]. Among the 31 U.N. entities are the U.N. Population Fund, which provides reproductive health services in more than 150 countries, and UN Women, which promotes gender equality[1][2][9]. The order also directs withdrawal from the U.N. Framework Convention on Climate Change, the 1992 treaty that underpins the Paris climate agreement[6][1][2].

Secretary of State Marco Rubio defended the move in a statement, saying the Trump administration determined the organizations were "redundant, mismanaged, unnecessary, wasteful, poorly run" or advancing agendas inconsistent with U.S. interests[10][11][12]. The White House said the withdrawals would end American taxpayer funding for entities "that advance globalist agendas over U.S. priorities"[6][13][9].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Q7R0RGyr--/t_thumbnail/https://static.dw.com/image/75427171_605.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese scientists extract 98% of gold from e-waste in 20 minutes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chinese-scientists-unveil-fast-0d0Nbo7LSDSQHPdnDL78Xw</link>
      <description>Researchers from China have developed a rapid and environmentally-friendly technique to extract more than 98 percent of gold from electronic waste in under 20 minutes, offering a potentially lucrative solution to the global e-waste crisis as gold prices hover near record highs.

The breakthrough method, developed by scientists at the Guangzhou Institute of Energy Conversion, part of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and South China University of Technology, uses a simple chemical solution that operates at room temperature without the need for toxic substances like cyanide[1][2][3]. The findings were published in the journal Angewandte Chemie International Edition[1][4][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Gk-Zf4ie--/t_thumbnail/https://sustainability-news.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Breakthrough-composite-material-boosts-gold-recovery-from-e-waste-by-10x-1536x1024.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump warns Iran over protester deaths as internet blackout spreads</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-warns-iran-of-severe-con-Trv4bXE3S4qNA7aXNXZ.Uw</link>
      <description>US President Donald Trump issued stark warnings to Iran on Thursday that Washington would respond with force if authorities continue killing peaceful protesters, as the Islamic Republic plunged into a nationwide internet blackout amid the largest demonstrations in more than three years.

Speaking with conservative radio host Hugh Hewitt on January 8, Trump declared that Iranian authorities would "have to pay hell" if they persist in lethal violence against demonstrators[1][2][3]. "I have let them know that if they start killing people, which they tend to do during their riots—they have lots of riots—if they do it, we are going to hit them very hard," Trump stated[2]. The warning came as human rights groups reported at least 39 to 45 protesters have been killed since demonstrations erupted in late December, including eight minors[4][5][6][7].

The protests, which began December 28 at Tehran's Grand Bazaar over economic grievances, have spread to all 31 provinces[4][8]. Violence intensified on Thursday evening after exiled Crown Prince Reza Pahlavi called for coordinated demonstrations at 8 p.m. local time[9][5]. Witnesses reported crowds chanting "Death to the dictator" and "Pahlavi will return" across Tehran and other major cities[9][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767906303/getty_uploads/2254941676_vfvj84.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kim pledges unconditional, permanent support for Putin</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/kim-jong-un-pledges-permanent-wuJxyv_qTgeEmg9b6caraw</link>
      <description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has promised Russian President Vladimir Putin unconditional and permanent support for all his policies, according to a letter reported by state media KCNA on Friday[1][2][3][4][5].

"I will unconditionally respect and unconditionally support all your policies and decisions and I have a willingness to be always with you for the sake of you and your Russia," Kim wrote to Putin[1][2][5]. "This choice will be constant and permanent."

The letter, which KCNA said was a response to an earlier message from Putin, marks the latest expression of deepening ties between the two nations as North Korea provides critical military support to Russia's war in Ukraine[1][2][3][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s---1C47fCp--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/2025-09-03T230731Z_1960464257_RC2LKGAQQ32P_RTRMADP_3_WW2-ANNIVERSARY-CHINA-NORTHKOREA-KCNA-1757034664.jpg%3Fresize%3D1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia pushes back on Thai claims over border scam centers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/cambodia-and-thailand-agree-to-8MjrV9KDQqCyQKw5AdnI7A</link>
      <description>Cambodia's Deputy Prime Minister Sun Chanthol said on Wednesday his country wants to "lower the temperature" with Thailand and pushed back against Bangkok's claims that recent border clashes were focused on combating scam centers, as both nations work to maintain a fragile 11-day-old ceasefire[1].

The comments come after Thailand and Cambodia signed a renewed ceasefire agreement on December 27, ending three weeks of fighting that killed at least 101 people and displaced more than half a million on both sides of the border[2][3]. Thailand released 18 Cambodian soldiers on December 31 who had been held as prisoners of war for 155 days, a move described by Thailand's Ministry of Foreign Affairs as "a gesture of goodwill and trust-building"[2].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767914494/url_uploads/-1x-1_akr6nt.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian missiles kill one, wound 24 in Zelenskyy's hometown</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/russian-missile-strikes-on-kry-xGeB2vTmScq2761GYBWj9A</link>
      <description>Two Russian Iskander ballistic missiles struck residential apartment buildings in Kryvyi Rih on Thursday evening, killing at least one person and wounding 24 others, including six children, in President Volodymyr Zelenskyy's hometown. The attack came as Russia continued its systematic targeting of Ukraine's energy infrastructure, leaving hundreds of thousands without power, water, and heating amid freezing temperatures[1][2][3][4].

The missiles hit the city around 5 p.m. local time, damaging approximately 15 apartment buildings and nearby vehicles[5][6][7]. Among the casualties was a 77-year-old woman who died in the strike, while the wounded included children aged 7 and 16[8][9]. One man who lost a leg in the explosion remained in critical condition and underwent surgery[5][8].</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1767915299/url_uploads/-1x-1_q66tjx.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS puzzles scientists with three symmetrical jets</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/interstellar-comet-3iatlas-dis-4Et_MP8GQD2DJHV0Qe0oRA</link>
      <description>As the rare interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS speeds through our solar system on its way toward Jupiter, astronomers have detected an unusual feature that has moved the scientific conversation from curiosity to genuine puzzle: the ancient comet is producing three perfectly symmetrical jets of material, separated by a strikingly consistent 120 degrees.

The phenomenon, confirmed through observations by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope and the Gemini North telescope in Hawaii between late November and late December 2025, defies standard models of how comets behave[1][2]. While most comets vent gas and dust in irregular, flickering plumes as they are heated by the sun, 3I/ATLAS has maintained this geometric precision for weeks, with each jet displaying comparable brightness and curvature[1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--EO4QO_1I--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zT58SVFsEFhx8fytDdVCPd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient humans may have met at Indonesian cave 40,000 years ago</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/sulawesi-cave-dig-reveals-anci-qTUPoZqXRr.pHu4ubLJ8zg</link>
      <description>A deep excavation in Indonesia has uncovered evidence that modern humans and an extinct hominin species may have overlapped at the same cave site more than 40,000 years ago, according to research published Wednesday by an international archaeological team led by Griffith University.

The findings from Leang Bulu Bettue, a limestone cave in southern Sulawesi, reveal a dramatic shift in the archaeological record around 40,000 years ago that researchers believe marks the arrival of Homo sapiens and the possible replacement of archaic hominins who had occupied the island for over a million years[1][2][3][4].

"The depth and continuity of the cultural sequence at Leang Bulu Bettue now positions this cave as a flagship site for investigating whether these two human lineages overlapped in time," said Basran Burhan, a Griffith PhD candidate who led the study published in PLOS ONE[2][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 03:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--8iIKflWm--/t_thumbnail/https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/1540573/2147483647/strip/true/crop/6000x3150%2B0%2B425/resize/1200x630%21/quality/90/%3Furl%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252F1b%252F44%252Ff81515ee4790971f804215a05053%252Fcave.jpeg%26na.image_optimisation%3D0" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oil prices climb on Venezuela, Iran supply concerns</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/oil-prices-rise-on-venezuela-a-vkELzgtcQsyI8gVqy1LlzQ</link>
      <description>Oil prices climbed for a second consecutive day Friday as traders weighed potential supply disruptions from Venezuela and escalating unrest in Iran, pushing Brent crude to $62.43 per barrel and West Texas Intermediate to $58.15[1][2][3].

The gains followed a sharp rally Thursday when both benchmarks surged more than 3%—the largest single-day increase since October—after two days of declines[1][2][4]. Brent is on track to climb 2.7% for the week, while WTI has gained 1.4%[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--e0svcPka--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108234888-1764640978236-gettyimages-1291793738-366223737.jpeg%3Fv%3D1767843943%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oceans set heat record in 2025 for ninth straight year</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/oceans-absorbed-record-heat-in-47VXWjTkTQaAGSz8NhyJ6A</link>
      <description>Earth's oceans absorbed a record-breaking amount of heat in 2025, marking the ninth consecutive year of unprecedented warming and intensifying concerns about extreme weather, rising seas, and collapsing marine ecosystems, according to research published Friday by an international team of scientists.

The upper 2,000 meters of the world's oceans absorbed 23 zettajoules more energy than in 2024—an amount equivalent to roughly 37 years of global energy consumption—according to the study in Advances in Atmospheric Sciences[1][2][3][4][5]. The research involved more than 50 scientists from 31 institutions across three continents[3][4].

"Every year, we are witnessing an increase in global temperatures—setting new records has become a recurring theme," said Prof. John Abraham from the University of St. Thomas, who co-authored the study[2]. "Global warming equates to ocean warming. To understand how much the Earth has warmed or how quickly we may warm in the future, we must look to the oceans"[2].</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--16UIXWLT--/t_thumbnail/https://www.geomar.de/fileadmin/_processed_/e/4/csm__GEO0151_2025-11-05_Petersenpreis_Gruppenfoto-select-Karina-von-Schuckmann_Sarah-Uphoff_d2a1eea917.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers discover hottest early galaxy cluster, starless dark matter cloud</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-discover-unusual-e-U7M73nkqTvmDOqH.FJ7jSw</link>
      <description>Two extraordinary discoveries presented this week at the American Astronomical Society meeting in Phoenix are challenging fundamental assumptions about galaxy formation and the nature of dark matter, offering astronomers rare glimpses into the universe's earliest epochs.

Researchers announced the identification of the earliest and hottest galaxy cluster ever observed, alongside the first confirmed detection of a starless dark matter cloud—a "failed galaxy" that has existed unchanged for billions of years[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--e7BUA9yb--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/13/multimedia/08HS-sci-cloud-9-clph/08HS-sci-cloud-9-clph-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemify says chemistry stuck in 'dark ages,' needs AI</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/chemify-advances-digital-chemp-w6nRbmj3TpOl3R9KUI1VRA</link>
      <description>A Glasgow-based chemistry startup is pioneering a digital revolution in molecular synthesis, arguing that chemistry remains trapped in manual methods while other sciences have embraced automation and artificial intelligence.

In an article published Wednesday, Chemify founder and CEO Lee Cronin declared that "chemistry is stuck in the dark ages" and needs a programmable language to bring it into the digital era[1][2][3]. The University of Glasgow professor argues that while AI can design thousands of hypothetical drug molecules overnight, each still requires human chemists to manually synthesize them—creating a bottleneck that prevents chemistry from matching the speed of computational design[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--xbaZ_-g0--/t_thumbnail/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_conversation_464/5ee0299a18accfed54967c915220d0cf" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
