<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:42:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Gold, silver, palladium retreat sharply as investors take profits</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-and-palladium-prices-plun-4Br4rpDrST2aGEybNaE1sw</link>
      <description>Gold, palladium, and silver retreated sharply on Thursday as investors locked in profits following a historic rally that pushed precious metals to record highs. The selloff came a day after the Federal Reserve held interest rates steady and as traders reassessed positions after weeks of gains.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spot gold fell as much as 4% during Thursday's trading to around $5,150 per ounce, pulling back from record highs above $5,500 reached earlier in the week. Palladium tumbled 5% to approximately $1,969 per ounce, while silver dropped more than 5% to around $110 per ounce after briefly touching $120 earlier in the session.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/NTC6CLJUJVINBIZVPODMLDGVAU.jpg?auth=b9b4d5481988eda4144420b19965daf3d15bd9357bcb89947ed78cfd26388828&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump orders Venezuelan airspace reopened for commercial travel</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-announces-reopening-of-v-TtOLAWJ5R7arsuyMQGlfUA</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump said Thursday he has instructed U.S. officials to reopen Venezuelan airspace for commercial travel, a move that could ease flight planning across northern South America and, he suggested, clear the way for Americans to visit Venezuela again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump said he relayed the decision to Venezuela’s acting leader, Delcy Rodríguez, and directed Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy and U.S. military leaders to open “all commercial airspace over Venezuela” by the end of the day. “American citizens will be very shortly able to go to Venezuela, and they’ll be safe there,” Trump said, according to an Associated Press account carried by multiple outlets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.tribuneindia.com/sortd-service/imaginary/v22-01/jpg/large/high?url=dGhldHJpYnVuZS1zb3J0ZC1wcm8tcHJvZC1zb3J0ZC9tZWRpYTM1NDE3ZDgwLWNkNDQtMTFmMC1hNWYzLWU1NWZlMzk3YzBhZi5qcGc=" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU approves new Iran sanctions, moves to designate IRGC as terrorist group</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eu-approves-new-iran-sanctions-BgHOlLpESsmCAfpowS2X9w</link>
      <description>European Union foreign ministers on Jan. 29 approved a new round of sanctions against Iran over a lethal crackdown on nationwide protests and moved toward listing the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) as a terrorist organisation—an escalation EU officials said would put the force in the same category as groups such as al-Qaeda and ISIS.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The measures come amid mounting international pressure on Tehran, as activists and rights groups report thousands killed since demonstrations erupted in late December, while Iranian authorities cite a far lower death toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2026/01/AFP__20260129__94DQ3MC__v1__HighRes__BelgiumEuCouncilPoliticsDiplomacy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran refuses talks with US while Trump issues military threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-rejects-us-negotiations-u-.HcREmk0RI.q5f6esf2fyA</link>
      <description>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi declared on Wednesday that Tehran will not negotiate with the United States while Washington continues to issue military threats, as President Donald Trump announced a "massive armada" heading toward the Islamic Republic. The diplomatic standoff comes amid a significant US military buildup in the Middle East and heightened regional fears of a wider conflict.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"There can be no negotiations in an atmosphere of threats," Araghchi said in remarks carried by Iran's state news agency IRNA. "Conducting diplomacy through military pressure is neither effective nor useful. If they want negotiations, they must abandon threats, excessive demands, and illogical issues."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.ncr-iran.org/en/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/iran-abbas-araghchi-regime-proposed-foreign-minister.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump officials met with Alberta separatists, Financial Times reports</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-officials-meet-alberta-s-19gOxhXDRTWmu3FtGByJsw</link>
      <description>The Trump administration has held at least three meetings with a fringe separatist group advocating for Alberta to break away from Canada, a report in the Financial Times said, adding a volatile new element to already strained U.S.-Canada relations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Leaders tied to the Alberta Prosperity Project (APP) met U.S. State Department officials in Washington three times since April 2025, according to people familiar with the discussions. The group is seeking another meeting in February with State and U.S. Treasury officials to pitch a proposed $500 billion credit facility that it says would help finance an independent Alberta if a referendum succeeds.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/1ZzJd49p2d0icrx0ITrynA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD05MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/national_post_articles_198/d9cef49a28baf2736d03fd6402a2e1a0" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX and xAI in merger talks ahead of potential IPO, Reuters reports</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-and-xai-plan-merger-ahe-fnAdyFbWSP2EKNYm5y8QGw</link>
      <description>Elon Musk’s SpaceX and his artificial-intelligence company xAI are in talks to merge ahead of a planned public offering, a move that would combine rockets, satellites, social media and AI products inside one corporate structure, according to a Reuters report citing a person briefed on the matter and corporate filings.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discussions, first reported by Reuters, would bring SpaceX’s launch business and Starlink satellite network together with xAI’s Grok chatbot and the X social-media platform, which xAI controls. Under the proposed structure, xAI shares would be exchanged for SpaceX shares, the source said, with some xAI executives potentially offered cash instead of SpaceX stock. No final agreement has been signed, and the timing and structure remain fluid, Reuters reported.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.zonebourse.com/static/resize/0/0/images/reuters/2026-01/2026-01-12T073019Z_1_LYNXMPEM0B098_RTROPTP_4_SPACE-EXPLORATION-SPACEX.JPG" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold hits record high, oil surges as Trump threatens Iran strike</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-hits-record-oil-surges-on-hd28SZjpSUKjtpz9RiQhyw</link>
      <description>Gold surged past $5,500 per ounce for the first time Thursday, while oil prices climbed to multi-month highs as President Donald Trump escalated military threats against Iran over its nuclear program. The precious metal touched an intraday record of $5,608 before pulling back sharply amid volatile trading, while Brent crude topped $70 a barrel for the first time since late summer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The commodity rallies came as Trump warned Iran that "time is running out" to negotiate a nuclear deal, posting on Truth Social that a "massive armada" was heading toward the region "with speed and violence, if necessary."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://qz.com/cdn-cgi/image/width=1200%2Cquality=85%2Cformat=auto/https://assets.qz.com/media/Gold%2520bars%2520bullion.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio says Donetsk is final obstacle in Ukraine peace talks</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/us-leads-peace-talks-as-donets-CqCLI0K3SCyZFkKavycoSQ</link>
      <description>Territorial disputes over Donetsk have emerged as the final barrier to ending the nearly four-year war in Ukraine, US Secretary of State Marco Rubio said Wednesday, as trilateral negotiations between Washington, Kyiv, and Moscow prepare to resume this weekend amid concerns about the preparedness of American negotiators.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The one remaining item … is the territorial claim on Donetsk. There is active work going to try to see if both sides' views on this can be reconciled," Rubio told a US Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing on January 28. "It's still a bridge we haven't crossed. It's still a gap, but at least we've been able to narrow down the issue set to one central one, and it will probably be a very difficult one."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Russia currently occupies roughly 70 percent of Donetsk and demands Ukraine cede the remaining territory it controls. Kyiv has refused to surrender land that Russian forces have not captured on the battlefield, with polls showing little Ukrainian public support for territorial concessions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/B4XZJZRLGBOYJBOFEMUYXK4F2E.jpg?auth=dcf0ee9f8992ddd461b90ee842aa93c9f12dd4616bfae11b96ede2e46960e0e0&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX and xAI in merger talks ahead of potential record IPO</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-and-xai-in-merger-talks-nIiFhNf4Qh2WWuT9UW9ddA</link>
      <description>Elon Musk's SpaceX and xAI are in negotiations regarding a potential merger ahead of what could become the largest initial public offering in history, according to exclusive reporting by Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The merger would unite Musk's aerospace empire with his artificial intelligence venture, consolidating the Starlink satellite network, the X social media platform, and the Grok AI chatbot under a single corporate structure. Reuters reported that two Nevada entities were established on January 21 to facilitate the transaction, with SpaceX Chief Financial Officer Bret Johnsen listed as a managing member in corporate filings.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769714274/url_uploads/GettyImages-2246892016_ki7bsw.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba's oil reserves down to 15-20 days as U.S. pressure mounts</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/cuba-faces-critical-oil-shorta-RmS89jOkQDWR7wQjCfBiUg</link>
      <description>Cuba's oil reserves have dwindled to a level that will sustain the island for only 15 to 20 days, according to data from energy analytics firm Kpler, as U.S. pressure on traditional suppliers threatens to push the nation toward economic collapse.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crisis has deepened rapidly following the Trump administration's January 3 military operation that captured Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro, effectively severing Cuba's primary oil lifeline. Venezuela, which supplied roughly a third of Cuba's oil at approximately 26,500 barrels per day in 2025, has not shipped any crude or fuel to the Caribbean island since early January.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/PLNAJVZ4I5P4VIQ7F6CMDIJWN4.jpg?auth=c991b9e0c150e19da297dcb1b6aa800ebadf7c3aeb66f0268d8477bfe3b82b9d&amp;width=1080&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia, Microsoft and Amazon in talks to invest $60B in OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/tech-giants-in-talks-to-invest-5daBeu84Q9mqlyhbqHDyww</link>
      <description>Nvidia, Microsoft and Amazon are in discussions to invest up to $60 billion in OpenAI, according to a report by The Information published Wednesday. The talks, if they lead to a deal, would be one of the largest private financings ever for an AI company and would further entangle the world’s biggest technology suppliers in the scramble for computing power and market share in generative AI.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The negotiations are ongoing and terms could change, and Reuters said it could not immediately verify The Information’s reporting. Still, the report fits a widening fundraising push around OpenAI that has drawn in major strategic backers and deep pools of global capital.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108202500-17585857512025-02-07t115613z_865237367_rc2npcauossb_rtrmadp_0_openai-germany.jpeg?v=1758585772&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple posts record quarter as iPhone sales surge 23%</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/apple-reports-record-breaking-6t1kE_ZZQ9.GX6x_7JaKew</link>
      <description>Apple delivered what CEO Tim Cook called a "remarkable, record-breaking quarter" on Thursday, posting fiscal first-quarter results that far exceeded Wall Street expectations as iPhone sales surged 23% year-over-year to drive the company's best holiday period ever.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The tech giant reported revenue of $143.8 billion for the quarter ending December 27, up 16% from the prior year and well ahead of analyst estimates of $138.4 billion. Earnings per share reached $2.84, a 19% increase that set a new all-time record and topped the $2.67 consensus forecast.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://variety.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Tim-Cook.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=563&amp;crop=1" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon in talks to invest up to $50 billion in OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/amazon-in-talks-to-invest-up-t-trh4tniASmCl2_pjpcffdw</link>
      <description>Amazon.com, Inc. is negotiating a potential investment of up to $50 billion in OpenAI, according to a report from The Wall Street Journal on Thursday, a deal that would represent one of the largest bets yet on artificial intelligence and deepen ties between the world's largest cloud-computing provider and the maker of ChatGPT.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Amazon CEO Andy Jassy is personally leading the discussions with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, sources familiar with the matter told The Wall Street Journal and CNBC. The final structure of any potential deal remains fluid, though a term sheet could be finalized in the coming weeks, according to CNBC.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108254537-1768938695162-CNBC_Stage_01_021.jpg?v=1768939511&amp;w=1920&amp;h=1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold surges to record high near $5,600 for ninth straight session</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/global-stocks-rise-on-earnings-epF0k88rQQKvwDWVBT8xow</link>
      <description>World stocks gained on Thursday as investors maintained their appetite for equities ahead of Apple results, while gold climbed to a record high for the ninth consecutive session. The rally in precious metals, coupled with strong corporate guidance from Meta, provided support across global markets despite concerns over tech sector capital expenditure.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://resource.tradingkey.com/cms_uploads/img/20230925/da287e094158a505a285240c546dcf15.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela approves law ending 20 years of state oil control</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-approves-historic-oi-LPgBSK6XSHufeNdUmJwfkg</link>
      <description>Venezuela's National Assembly on Thursday approved a sweeping reform to the country's hydrocarbons law, ending more than two decades of state control over the nation's oil sector and opening the door to private investment in the world's largest proven crude reserves.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The vote marks a dramatic departure from the socialist economic model that has governed Venezuela since former President Hugo Chávez nationalized the industry in the mid-2000s. The legislation comes less than a month after the U.S. military captured then-President Nicolás Maduro in Caracas on January 3.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 01:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769736124/getty_uploads/1171553517_yssqzq.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says he plans to talk to Iran amid naval buildup</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-plans-talks-with-iran-am-TWVP2QJfSBuO0d299yRWvg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump confirmed on Thursday that he is planning to hold direct talks with Iran as tensions between Washington and Tehran escalate, pairing diplomatic signals with warnings about the naval forces now positioned near the Islamic Republic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I have had and I am planning on it," Trump told reporters at the Kennedy Center when asked about potential discussions with Iran. He simultaneously emphasized the military pressure, stating, "We have a lot of very big, very powerful ships sailing to Iran right now, and it would be great if we didn't have to use them".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking to CBS News on Thursday, Trump revealed he has communicated two key demands to Iran in recent conversations: "No. 1, no nuclear. And No. 2, stop killing protesters".</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/SRLH7PCHXZPHXFBOO6F42HSP7A.jpg?auth=777ef14382f07f1c5dc30d30a254e48c12e4400a71df9bff0e06637525a55f0e&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA simulations reveal magnetic chaos before neutron stars collide</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-simulates-merging-neutron-X9OC4z3AT8SGpg5AJfUkyw</link>
      <description>NASA researchers have unveiled supercomputer simulations that provide an unprecedented view into the chaotic magnetic interactions between neutron stars in the final moments before they collide, identifying potential electromagnetic signals that future observatories could detect.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The new findings, announced by NASA on January 29, offer scientists their most detailed look yet at how the magnetospheres—highly magnetized, plasma-filled regions surrounding neutron stars—behave as the city-sized stellar remnants spiral toward a cataclysmic merger. The research, led by Dimitrios Skiathas, a graduate student at the University of Patras in Greece conducting work at NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center, was published in The Astrophysical Journal.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/vis/a010000/a014800/a014884/Lines_Inclined_Still.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harvard scientist proposes global network to detect interstellar objects</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-study-interstellar-3GUDcwLNSs2Ng6Hjg9V8.Q</link>
      <description>The interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS, which has been traversing our solar system since its discovery in July 2025, continues to reveal unusual features that have prompted scientists to propose a global early warning network for detecting future visitors from beyond our cosmic neighborhood.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A new scientific proposal led by Harvard astrophysicist Avi Loeb and co-authored with graduate researcher Oem Trivedi outlines what they describe as the Comprehensive Interstellar Objects Network, or CISON. The framework argues that humanity is currently underprepared to detect and respond to fast-moving objects arriving from interstellar space.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://d1rldr9jdodfaa.cloudfront.net/images/01KC3B20YR7CSVZY8ZYEAY81TP/20251210_051702_1616035191.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA begins critical Artemis II fueling test ahead of moon launch</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-prepares-artemis-ii-moon-yzf1RScCSnmaUu84i.Cqfw</link>
      <description>Two days after families gathered at Kennedy Space Center to mark the 40th anniversary of the Challenger disaster, NASA is pressing forward with final preparations for Artemis II, which will send astronauts around the Moon for the first time since 1972.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The space agency began wet dress rehearsal operations on Thursday evening at Launch Pad 39B, a critical fueling test that will determine whether the mission can proceed toward its targeted launch date of February 6. The test involves loading more than 700,000 gallons of cryogenic propellants into the Space Launch System rocket and running a simulated countdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/75tEx5XMobTa55Kk8vEgGA-1920-80.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UBS lifts gold forecast to $6,200 as prices hit record highs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ubs-raises-gold-price-target-t-qmnkTG_.QMecros31L16qQ</link>
      <description>UBS has increased its gold price target to $6,200 per ounce for March, June, and September 2026, up from its previous forecast of $5,000, citing stronger-than-expected demand stemming from increased investment flows and central bank buying.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The upgrade came as spot gold surged to an all-time high of $5,594.82 on Thursday, extending a remarkable rally that has seen the precious metal climb more than 27% since the beginning of the year. The safe-haven metal has now achieved record highs for nine consecutive sessions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/INGIB4VICZKTZJ7OYOZBJJO6VE.jpg?auth=1275bd6aff3189a1763e176ed9782287daeb0ee17e0ea358a6eddfebac72b434&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
