<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:33:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>NASA begins critical Artemis II fueling test ahead of moon launch</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-prepares-artemis-ii-moon-yzf1RScCSnmaUu84i.Cqfw</link>
      <description>Two days after families gathered at Kennedy Space Center to mark the 40th anniversary of the Challenger disaster, NASA is pressing forward with final preparations for Artemis II, which will send astronauts around the Moon for the first time since 1972.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The space agency began wet dress rehearsal operations on Thursday evening at Launch Pad 39B, a critical fueling test that will determine whether the mission can proceed toward its targeted launch date of February 6. The test involves loading more than 700,000 gallons of cryogenic propellants into the Space Launch System rocket and running a simulated countdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/75tEx5XMobTa55Kk8vEgGA-1920-80.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UBS lifts gold forecast to $6,200 as prices hit record highs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ubs-raises-gold-price-target-t-qmnkTG_.QMecros31L16qQ</link>
      <description>UBS has increased its gold price target to $6,200 per ounce for March, June, and September 2026, up from its previous forecast of $5,000, citing stronger-than-expected demand stemming from increased investment flows and central bank buying.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The upgrade came as spot gold surged to an all-time high of $5,594.82 on Thursday, extending a remarkable rally that has seen the precious metal climb more than 27% since the beginning of the year. The safe-haven metal has now achieved record highs for nine consecutive sessions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/INGIB4VICZKTZJ7OYOZBJJO6VE.jpg?auth=1275bd6aff3189a1763e176ed9782287daeb0ee17e0ea358a6eddfebac72b434&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT engineers build silicon chips that compute with waste heat</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mit-develops-heat-powered-sili-6jTjj8FqQM.x5v6Kp807dA</link>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology have engineered microscopic silicon structures capable of performing mathematical calculations using waste heat rather than electricity, achieving more than 99 percent accuracy in matrix multiplication operations fundamental to machine learning.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The findings, published January 29 in Physical Review Applied, represent a proof of concept for "thermal analog computing" that could enable more energy-efficient electronics by transforming a liability into a computational asset.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2026/mit-engineers-design-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Airbus defense chief warns EU red tape threatens space ambitions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/airbus-leonardo-thales-form-eu-JYHB_x6bT_qr_nMN8toMaA</link>
      <description>Europe's three aerospace giants—Airbus, Leonardo, and Thales—are moving toward creating a unified European space company as the continent races to compete with American rivals and close what industry leaders describe as a widening capability gap.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The companies signed a Memorandum of Understanding in October 2025 to merge their space operations into a single entity that would employ approximately 25,000 people and generate about €6.5 billion in annual revenue. The venture, expected to become operational in 2027 pending regulatory approvals, would see Airbus hold a 35% stake while Leonardo and Thales each take 32.5%.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.airbus.com/sites/g/files/jlcbta136/files/styles/w1200h675/public/2025-10/Michael-Schoellhorn_portrait.jpg?h=2aaaa9f2&amp;itok=laz-nC_G" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX launches free satellite collision-tracking system</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-unveils-stargaze-system-FYW49n1TQiyztWoMLOcf6A</link>
      <description>SpaceX announced Thursday night the launch of Stargaze, a new Space Situational Awareness system designed to help satellite operators avoid collisions in Earth's increasingly congested orbit. The company said it will make the collision-tracking data available to all satellite operators free of charge via its space-traffic management platform in the coming weeks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"SpaceX is now providing precise positional awareness of objects in Earth orbit to all satellite operators for free," CEO Elon Musk wrote on X. "This will greatly reduce the probability of collisions that create orbital debris (space junk) hazards."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/EQUCZ77D3RITJDJ3Y6MLK2R6RA.jpg?auth=4f98ffdd6873aa12834fc70921cea5e07c76a3374242858ed1465f69455fd75c&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA finds ammonia on Europa, boosting hopes for habitability</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-finds-ammonia-on-europa-s-vlOBofS5TT68kQJkZhTqsw</link>
      <description>Scientists have discovered ammonia-bearing compounds on the surface of Jupiter's moon Europa for the first time, NASA announced Thursday, a finding that has prompted renewed optimism about the icy world's potential to harbor life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discovery emerged from re-analysis of decades-old data collected by NASA's Galileo spacecraft, which studied the Jupiter system between 1995 and 2003. Researcher Al Emran of NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California detected faint signals of ammonia near fractures on Europa's frozen surface by examining data from the mission's Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer instrument captured during Galileo's 11th orbit of Jupiter in 1997.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.science.nasa.gov/dynamicimage/assets/science/psd/solar/2023/09/2/204_PIA19048.jpg?w=2300&amp;h=1700&amp;fit=clip&amp;crop=faces%252Cfocalpoint" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA delays Artemis II test as arctic cold grips Florida</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/artemis-ii-to-launch-next-week-0d8_JDb8TbOvI5Uw7Jb.0A</link>
      <description>NASA has rescheduled the Artemis II mission's final pre-launch test due to an unusual arctic outbreak affecting Florida, pushing the earliest possible launch date to Sunday, February 8. The mission will mark humanity's first crewed voyage toward the Moon in 54 years, with Canadian astronaut Jeremy Hansen becoming the first non-American to journey to lunar space.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/8c7a227/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1280x853%2B0%2B0/resize/880x586%21/quality/90/?url=http%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252F5d%252F48%252Fd628a1624d92ae9008d1e4c482d6%252Fafrc2026-0017-09-medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurozone posts best year since 2022 as Q4 growth beats forecasts</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/europe-grows-03-percent-as-str-yh6oAlemTJOr2oHSIfg1jA</link>
      <description>The eurozone economy closed out 2025 with a better-than-expected quarterly expansion, but economists warn that the surging euro poses fresh challenges for the bloc's export-dependent industries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to preliminary data released Thursday by Eurostat, the European Union's statistics agency, gross domestic product in the 21 countries using the euro grew 0.3% in the fourth quarter of 2025, matching the prior quarter's pace and exceeding market expectations of 0.2%. For the full year, the eurozone expanded 1.5%, its strongest performance since 2022 and well above the European Commission's 1.3% projection.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/LDGXEY6SFJJE5C4IKK6RZJ7PMY.jpg?auth=b34553dbd57181a213d3a86211b8b6bd11e3efdf7e5ba23f9005a6b73d5e2166&amp;height=1005&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80&amp;smart=true" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IAEA holds emergency session on Ukraine nuclear safety threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-nuclear-watchdog-warns-of-u-CXkpchdeSlmyI.f4xAfxmw</link>
      <description>The International Atomic Energy Agency held a special session Friday to address growing nuclear safety concerns in Ukraine, with IAEA Director General Rafael Grossi declaring that the conflict there "remains the greatest threat to nuclear safety globally."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The urgent four-hour meeting of the IAEA's Board of Governors was convened in Vienna at the request of the Netherlands with support from 11 other countries—Belgium, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Portugal, Romania, and the United Kingdom. The gathering came in response to weeks of Russian attacks on Ukrainian energy infrastructure that have left millions of citizens without power during winter while threatening nuclear facilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.barrons.com/asset/external-media/afp/AFP7883850354648577293113164614069463780690---1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New map reveals Milky Way's magnetic field far more complex than expected</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/scientists-unveil-most-detaile-IehehHXgRZeN6adV9VlFrQ</link>
      <description>An international team of astronomers has produced the clearest picture yet of the Milky Way's magnetic field, revealing a landscape of hidden complexity that challenges previous assumptions about our galaxy's invisible architecture.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The new map, created using data from the Dominion Radio Astrophysical Observatory near Penticton, British Columbia, shows that more than half of the northern sky contains intricate magnetic structures rather than the simple, uniform fields scientists once expected. The research, led by the University of British Columbia Okanagan, was published this week in The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G23rcfYWjdwdmaJopud6aT.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation finds Liberia's largest gold miner leaked toxins</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/liberia-gold-miner-linked-to-t-_knsOxk5TgycEfrMi3QV8g</link>
      <description>A joint investigation by The Associated Press and The Gecko Project has revealed that Bea Mountain Mining Corporation, Liberia's largest gold mining company, repeatedly leaked cyanide, arsenic, and copper from its facilities into local waterways at levels exceeding legal limits, contaminating rivers that nearby communities depend on for drinking water and fishing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The investigation, based on reports retrieved from Liberia's Environmental Protection Agency after they were removed from its website, documents four confirmed spills between 2016 and 2023 at the company's New Liberty mine in Grand Cape Mount County. Residents of Jikandor village, located downstream from the mine, said they have been forced to reckon with an impossible choice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If we don't move, we will die," village chief Mustapha Pabai told reporters.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/UYrG_2EjjfR.UQRpIEMKwg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/ap.org/3be861ba86f65fe363676c9fd035b21a" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine sends youngest recruits to front lines as troop shortage deepens</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ukraine-sends-youngest-recruit-pHrsO_8nT16KhNE9e6ihsw</link>
      <description>As Ukraine enters the fourth year of its war with Russia, the country is grappling with a deepening manpower crisis that has forced young recruits barely out of their teens onto the deadliest parts of the front line, while units across the battlefield operate at a fraction of their intended strength.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scale of the crisis was laid bare this month when newly appointed Defense Minister Mykhailo Fedorov told parliament that two million Ukrainians are wanted for evading military service, while 200,000 soldiers have gone absent without leave. The 34-year-old Fedorov, who took over the ministry with what he described as a 300 billion hryvnia ($6.9 billion) budget deficit, called for urgent reforms to address problems "that have accumulated over the years".</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/cae2a4dc-9b95-4d18-bffc-5a92d4b1be00/Ukraine-soldiers-3-gty-jm-240731_1722442986484_hpEmbed_3x2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns of 'imminent financial collapse' by July</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/un-faces-imminent-collapse-aft-e4rZDKFpT_yTyMYYOnSwHQ</link>
      <description>The United Nations is on the brink of "imminent financial collapse" and could run out of cash by July, Secretary-General António Guterres warned in a letter to ambassadors dated January 28, marking the most severe funding crisis in the organization's 80-year history.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"The crisis is deepening, threatening programme delivery and risking financial collapse. And the situation will deteriorate further in the near future," Guterres wrote in the correspondence, obtained by Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The alarm comes weeks after President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on January 7 directing the withdrawal of the United States from 66 international organizations, including 31 UN entities, deeming them "contrary to the interests of the United States".</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CFSJJ7WOTZJ5BB3FKZ3LJ37ZCE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic stuns Sinner in five sets to reach Australian Open final</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/djokovic-defeats-sinner-in-epi-uff7gEbFRGarUi0YfJexCw</link>
      <description>Novak Djokovic turned back the clock in the early hours of Saturday morning in Melbourne, outlasting two-time defending champion Jannik Sinner in a grueling five-set semifinal to reach his 11th Australian Open final. The 38-year-old Serbian prevailed 3-6, 6-3, 4-6, 6-4, 6-4 in four hours and nine minutes, finishing at 1:32 a.m. local time, to become the oldest man in the Open Era to reach the championship match at Melbourne Park.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The victory snapped Djokovic's five-match losing streak against Sinner, his first win over the Italian since November 2023, and propelled him one match away from a record-extending 25th Grand Slam title that would surpass Margaret Court's all-time mark of 24 major singles championships.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://live-production.wcms.abc-cdn.net.au/352f20784daee52a365324e2c0eb63f3?impolicy=wcms_crop_resize&amp;cropH=2002&amp;cropW=3559&amp;xPos=0&amp;yPos=82&amp;width=862&amp;height=485" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump says he's in talks with Iran as US warships mass in Gulf</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-deploys-massive-armada-t-8J_2wo3DS4S65pWp2r7bFg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has confirmed he is in talks with Iranian leaders while deploying a major naval fleet to the Persian Gulf, escalating pressure on Tehran to accept U.S. demands on its nuclear program or face military action he warns will be "far worse" than last year's strikes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I have had, and I am planning on it," Trump said Friday when asked about recent conversations with Iran, adding that he conveyed two conditions: "No nukes. And two, stop killing protesters." Ten U.S. warships, including the nuclear-powered aircraft carrier USS Abraham Lincoln and six guided-missile destroyers, are now positioned within striking range of Iran, according to U.S. Navy officials.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1769794527/getty_uploads/2258052690_ud2k5o.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump deploys massive US naval force as Iran nuclear deadline nears</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-deploys-massive-us-naval-SWF2K3JsQ8G2zw6DzdWKwg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has dispatched a substantial U.S. naval fleet to the Persian Gulf in an escalating standoff with Iran, warning Tehran on Thursday that "time is running out" to negotiate a nuclear agreement or face military action he described as "far worse" than the June 2025 strikes that targeted Iranian nuclear facilities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The deployment, which Trump has repeatedly called a "massive Armada," is led by the aircraft carrier USS Abraham Lincoln and now includes at least six guided-missile destroyers in the region, with the USS Delbert D. Black crossing into the Red Sea on January 29 and docking at Israel's port of Eilat on Friday. The carrier strike group entered the Middle East region on January 26 after departing the South China Sea earlier this month.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/F9jGLqvEViqZyD6VATdlGg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/bbc_us_articles_995/61c93e342955bdfe37d3defcbfed04c8" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satellite images show Iran building roofs over bombed nuclear sites</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-rebuilds-bombed-nuclear-s-tdSvIDAESUO_JLX95_m6lw</link>
      <description>New satellite imagery reveals Iran is placing roofs over two nuclear facilities bombed by Israel and the United States last year, raising concerns that Tehran is attempting to shield salvage operations from outside observation as the regime continues to block international inspectors from the sites.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Images from Planet Labs PBC show that Iran completed construction of roofs over damaged buildings at its Natanz and Isfahan nuclear facilities in late December 2025 and early January 2026, according to an Associated Press report published Thursday. The activity marks the first major construction visible by satellite at any of Iran's stricken nuclear sites since Israel's 12-day war with the Islamic Republic in June 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://imengine.public.prod.dur.navigacloud.com/?uuid=d51db679-1da5-5745-895a-ba4cb29c932f&amp;function=original&amp;type=preview" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA probe data reveals origins of solar wind heating</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/parker-solar-probe-reveals-sol-wVONvsMNQ2ancHdfztMuVQ</link>
      <description>Using measurements from NASA's Parker Solar Probe during its record-breaking closest approach to the sun, scientists have mapped the dynamic "shell" of hot gas where the solar wind is born, shedding new light on one of the most enduring mysteries in heliophysics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The research, led by University of Arizona associate professor Kristopher Klein and published this week in Geophysical Research Letters, offers the first detailed analysis of how energy moves through the sun's outer atmosphere at distances never before measured, with implications for predicting space weather events that affect Earth's satellites, communications systems, and power grids.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2023/durable-parker-solar-p.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky backs energy truce, says Ukraine will halt strikes if Russia reciprocates</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/zelensky-voices-support-for-u-QA_w7OKQSg2YGtSFXtaU5Q</link>
      <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky endorsed a U.S.-proposed pause on strikes targeting energy infrastructure on Friday, pledging that Kyiv would halt attacks on Russian energy facilities if Moscow reciprocates—though he emphasized that no formal agreement exists between the two nations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"If Russia does not strike our energy infrastructure—generation facilities or any other energy assets—we will not strike theirs," Zelensky told reporters on January 30, characterizing the arrangement as "an opportunity, not an agreement."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The development follows President Donald Trump's announcement Thursday that Russian President Vladimir Putin had agreed to suspend attacks on Kyiv and other Ukrainian cities for one week amid extreme cold weather. Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov confirmed Friday that Trump "did indeed make a personal request to President Putin to refrain from striking Kyiv for a week until February 1 in order to create favorable conditions for negotiations."</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/XO2D623IMJOHFBKHPCVOAPWPII.jpg?auth=20e228e0da5e806f0b767fd17edf82740d9093e7d06f14e6c43826718e25fbdd&amp;width=1920&amp;quality=80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's Greenland threats halt US-Danish climate research</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-s-greenland-moves-disrup-MgMj.CU0QrmMDtiI_htCng</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's escalating pressure on Greenland has begun to chill scientific ties between American and Greenlandic researchers, with at least one climate program halted and future collaborations cast into uncertainty. The diplomatic strain comes just days after the United States officially exited the Paris Agreement, further isolating the country from global climate efforts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ross Virginia, a professor emeritus of environmental studies at Dartmouth College, said a climate program he ran with Greenlandic colleagues was halted by "mutual agreement" due to the tensions, according to Bloomberg News. "Direct cooperation is paused while we determine what a future vision for collaborative science diplomacy — particularly involving education and younger students — could look like," he said.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Another US scientist, speaking anonymously for fear of jeopardizing relationships, said some research partnerships had been affected by the political climate.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i3mI08XqNv2g/v1/1200x800.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
