<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:29:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark to meet US on Greenland as Trump threats escalate</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/denmark-and-us-to-hold-talks-o-dbn7SeiqQxmdDHtk8z8mQQ</link>
      <description>Denmark confirmed Sunday that Foreign Minister Lars Løkke Rasmussen will meet with US Secretary of State Marco Rubio next week to discuss Greenland, as tensions escalate over President Donald Trump's repeated threats to take control of the Arctic territory[1][2].

"We are at a crossroads," Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen said during a party conference, according to the Ritzau news agency[1][2]. The meeting comes after Denmark and Greenland requested talks with Rubio following intensifying rhetoric from the Trump administration, which has refused to rule out military force to acquire the mineral-rich island[3][4][5].

Trump said Friday that the US would "do something on Greenland whether they like it or not," adding that if America doesn't act, "Russia or China will take over Greenland"[6][7][8]. The White House confirmed Tuesday it is "discussing a range of options" to acquire Greenland, with press secretary Karoline Leavitt stating that "utilizing the U.S. military is always an option"[9][10].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 18:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--vx2qL_1B--/t_thumbnail/https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims3/default/strip/false/crop/6000x3375%2B0%2B313/resize/1400/quality/100/format/jpeg/%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fb0%252Fc7%252F814ecfb34708aec91f92d2625913%252Fgettyimages-2204351314.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protest death toll surpasses 500 under internet blackout</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-protest-death-toll-surpas-6eC6wnoFT3m42FcYcb3hqg</link>
      <description>Two weeks of nationwide protests in Iran have left more than 500 people dead as authorities intensified their crackdown under the cover of a near-total internet blackout, according to rights groups monitoring the unrest that has evolved into one of the most serious challenges to the Islamic Republic's theocratic government in years.

The U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency reported Sunday that at least 538 people have been killed, including 490 protesters and 48 security personnel[1][2][3]. More than 10,600 people have been arrested[1][2][4][3]. The Norway-based Iran Human Rights organization separately documented 192 deaths, warning the actual toll could be significantly higher as the ongoing communications blackout has made verification increasingly difficult[5][6].

The protests erupted on December 28 following the collapse of Iran's currency, the rial, which now trades at over 1.4 million to one U.S. dollar as the country's economy buckles under international sanctions[4][3][7]. What began as demonstrations over economic hardship has transformed into direct challenges to Iran's theocratic regime, with protesters chanting "Death to Khamenei" in reference to Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei[8][9].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--GZVfgMlq--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AFP__20251229__898K4ZR__v2__HighRes__IranPoliticsEconomyDemo-1767364417.jpg%3Fresize%3D1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Von der Leyen backs Iran protesters, condemns crackdown</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/von-der-leyen-backs-iranian-pr-1rr_3k6ZRV.v4VG2jYJeBg</link>
      <description>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen expressed full support for anti-government protesters in Iran on January 10, condemning the violent crackdown by authorities and calling for the immediate release of detained demonstrators and restoration of internet access[1][2][3][4][5][6].

"Tehran's streets, and cities around the world, echo with the footsteps of Iranian women and men demanding freedom," von der Leyen wrote on social media[2][3][6]. "Europe stands fully behind them. We unequivocally condemn the violent repression of these legitimate demonstrations. Those responsible will be remembered on the wrong side of history."[3][4][6]

The statement comes as Iran faces its most widespread unrest since the 1979 Islamic Revolution, according to observers[7][8]. Protests erupted December 28 after the Iranian rial collapsed to over 1.4 million against the U.S. dollar, triggering demonstrations by Tehran bazaar merchants that quickly spread to at least 27 provinces[9][7][10][11].

Human rights groups report escalating violence under a nationwide internet blackout imposed January 8[12][13][14]. The Human Rights Activists in Iran documented at least 538 deaths, including 490 protesters and 48 security forces members, as of January 10[15]. The organization's data, based on activist networks inside the country, has proven accurate in previous unrest[16].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--oMUbj0Kq--/t_thumbnail/https://en.apa.az/storage/news/2026/january/10/big/6962889e6bc3f6962889e6bc4017680651826962889e6bc3d6962889e6bc3e.png" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exiled prince says he's preparing to return to Iran</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/exiled-crown-prince-reza-pahla-KYOfh8b_SVq9AfXhI0nl5Q</link>
      <description>Reza Pahlavi, the U.S.-based son of Iran's last shah, has declared he is "preparing to return to Iran" to lead a democratic transition as anti-regime protests enter their third week, marking a significant shift from passive supporter to active opposition leader attempting to direct a movement that has left at least 538 people dead[1][2][3].

The 63-year-old announced his readiness to return on January 10, telling Fox News he would lead the transition "to make sure that in full transparency, people have an opportunity to elect their leaders freely and to decide their own future"[4]. His calls for coordinated demonstrations at 8 p.m. local time on January 8 and 9 drew large crowds to the streets of Tehran and other cities, with protesters chanting "Long live the shah" and "Pahlavi will return"[5][6][7].

Pahlavi has moved beyond issuing statements from exile to providing tactical guidance, urging demonstrators to "seize and hold city centers," stay together on main streets, and maintain discipline[6][7]. He has also called for nationwide strikes among energy and transportation workers, seeking to apply economic pressure on the Islamic Republic[8]. Videos verified by monitoring groups showed thousands responding to his appeals despite a nationwide internet blackout imposed by authorities[5][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 22:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--lpSKsfGI--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.politis.com.cy/thumbnails/409001/conversions/reza_pahlavi-seo.webp" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protest death toll reaches 544, over 10,600 arrested</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-protests-intensify-with-d-WyJv6iZVQIWwXLS5YN3tzA</link>
      <description>Nationwide protests in Iran have entered their third week, with the death toll rising to at least 544 as security forces intensify a violent crackdown on demonstrators calling for the end of the Islamic Republic, according to the U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency[1]. The unrest, which has spread to 185 cities across all 31 provinces, represents one of the most serious challenges to Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's regime since the 1979 revolution[2][3].

HRANA reported Sunday that more than 10,600 people have been arrested since protests erupted on December 28, when Iran's currency plummeted to historic lows against the U.S. dollar[4][1]. The agency, which has a history of accurate reporting during previous Iranian unrest, confirmed 490 protester deaths and 48 security force fatalities, though the actual toll may be higher due to a nationwide internet blackout imposed January 8[2][5].

President Donald Trump has been briefed on military strike options for Iran and warned Tehran he would hit the regime "very, very hard where it hurts" if it continues killing protesters[6][7]. Iran's parliament speaker responded by threatening that U.S. troops and Israel would become "legitimate targets" if America intervenes militarily[8][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--fqSI3bzA--/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/10/multimedia/10int-iran-streets-mjht/10int-iran-streets-mjht-articleLarge.jpg%3Fquality%3D75%26auto%3Dwebp%26disable%3Dupscale" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan launches first deep-sea rare earth mission amid China export curbs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/japan-launches-deep-sea-rare-e-tXRpUUS4Qma6yznxmaPu2Q</link>
      <description>A Japanese research vessel departed Monday for a remote Pacific atoll to begin the world's first attempt to extract rare earths from deep-sea mud, as Tokyo accelerates efforts to reduce its dependence on China following Beijing's latest export restrictions.

The deep-sea scientific drilling ship Chikyu set sail from the port city of Shizuoka bound for Minamitori Island, approximately 1,900 kilometers southeast of Tokyo, for a month-long mission to retrieve mineral-rich sediment from depths of 6,000 meters, according to Reuters[1][2]. The voyage marks a first-of-its-kind effort to continuously lift rare-earth material from such depths to a ship.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--VhF-dWQD--/t_thumbnail/https://cms-image-bucket-productionv3-ap-northeast-1-a7d2.s3.ap-northeast-1.amazonaws.com/images/4/1/1/7/49747114-3-eng-GB/Cropped-1751305757photo_SXM2025061800007028.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wagner Moura becomes first Brazilian man to win Golden Globe</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/wagner-moura-and-the-secret-ag-KA2KPH7oQuCr8D0mtkEXcQ</link>
      <description>Brazilian actor Wagner Moura made Golden Globe history on Sunday night, becoming the first Brazilian man to win Best Actor in a Drama for his performance in "The Secret Agent," a political thriller set during Brazil's 1977 military dictatorship. The film also captured the Best Non-English Language Motion Picture award, cementing a triumphant night for Brazilian cinema at the Beverly Hilton.

"I was not prepared for this because I thought I was too old," Moura, 49, said during his acceptance speech, as reported by the Los Angeles Times[1]. The actor, who arrived on the red carpet in a white double-breasted jacket alongside his partner of nearly 30 years, Sandra Delgado, thanked his wife first in his remarks[2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 04:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768191143/url_uploads/Wagner-Moura-Golden-Globe-Win-2_nkfhnf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold hits record high amid Fed probe, Iran unrest</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/gold-hits-record-4600-amid-fed-RP4SHOI.S9KVBIFp_GnkbA</link>
      <description>Gold surged past $4,600 per ounce for the first time on Monday, as investors rushed into safe-haven assets following the U.S. Justice Department's criminal investigation into Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell and escalating violence from protests in Iran.

Spot gold jumped as much as 1.7% to reach a record high of $4,600.33 per ounce in Asian trading, according to Reuters[1][2]. Silver also climbed to an all-time high of $84.60 per ounce before settling around $83-84, extending a rally that has seen the white metal gain nearly 150% over the past year[3][4].

"So, between events in Iran, and potential U.S. involvement, and the (Fed) chair being the focus of a criminal probe... U.S. futures turned lower on the Powell news, which was a green light for gold to take a run higher," said Tim Waterer, chief market analyst at KCM Trade[1].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 08:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Lgu5pZJQ--/t_thumbnail/https://economymiddleeast.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Gold-prices-1.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany and India sign defense, AI deals to reduce China dependence</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/merz-and-modi-deepen-india-ger-qZcXDrRbSL2nUtfFvUvhog</link>
      <description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday signed a series of agreements on defense, critical minerals, artificial intelligence, and education during Merz's first official visit to India, as both nations seek to reduce reliance on China and Russia amid shifting global alliances.

The two-day visit, taking place in Modi's home state of Gujarat, produced memorandums of understanding covering security cooperation, health sector collaboration, and the establishment of an AI innovation centre[1][2]. Modi announced visa-free transit for Indian citizens through Germany and invited German universities to open campuses in India as part of a new higher education roadmap[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--hzSNdYoq--/t_thumbnail/https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%252F2026-01-12%252F20n2mm40%252FPTI01122026000221B.jpg%3Fw%3D1200%26auto%3Dformat%252Ccompress%26ogImage%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexplained shock wave around dead star puzzles astronomers</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mysterious-shock-wave-around-w-5Jos.SkFQsGqM5nuMwjEqw</link>
      <description>Astronomers have discovered a colorful, persistent shock wave around a dead star that defies all known explanations, revealing what scientists describe as a first-of-its-kind cosmic phenomenon.

The white dwarf star RXJ0528+2838, located approximately 730 light-years from Earth, is surrounded by a glowing bow shock stretching roughly 3,800 times the distance between Earth and the Sun. The discovery, published Monday in the journal Nature Astronomy, has left researchers searching for answers to what they call a "mystery engine" powering the phenomenon[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--zjrepCtc--/t_thumbnail/https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2026/astronomers-surprised.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope finds black hole that slowly starved galaxy</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/webb-telescope-uncovers-early-O1Y.4v4iTqSGQtu.3LWRRQ</link>
      <description>The James Webb Space Telescope has delivered a series of discoveries reshaping scientists' understanding of the early cosmos, including a "dead" galaxy starved by its own black hole, rare cosmic dust formed without typical ingredients, and a puzzling new class of galaxies that defy classification.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--qKSzuaJL--/t_thumbnail/https://interestingengineering.com/_next/image%3Furl%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fcms.interestingengineering.com%252Fwp-content%252Fuploads%252F2026%252F01%252FIE-1.jpg%26w%3D3840%26q%3D75" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China files plans for 200,000 satellites, dwarfing SpaceX</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-files-plans-for-200000-i-SIZASLCsQjuQGnOyLeyvJA</link>
      <description>In a move that dramatically escalates competition for prime real estate in low Earth orbit, China has submitted plans to the International Telecommunication Union covering more than 200,000 satellites, according to ITU records released Sunday[1][2][3].

The filings, submitted in the final week of December 2025, dwarf any previous satellite constellation proposals and come just days after U.S. regulators approved an expansion of SpaceX's Starlink network[4][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--KLvpPeSN--/t_thumbnail/https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_%218xrH%21%2Cw_1200%2Ch_675%2Cc_fill%2Cf_jpg%2Cq_auto:good%2Cfl_progressive:steep%2Cg_auto/https%253A%252F%252Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%252Fpublic%252Fimages%252F05471c27-b73c-4c13-a30f-f5ae48d70490_1280x720.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany's Uniper signs major green ammonia deal with India</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uniper-signs-500000-ton-green-zKBVDDgaRHe_FDfxvTgLlQ</link>
      <description>German energy company Uniper and India's AM Green Ammonia have signed a long-term binding offtake agreement for up to 500,000 tons per year of renewable ammonia, marking what the companies call one of the first large-scale green fuel supply corridors between India and Europe[1][2][3].

The agreement was exchanged Monday in Ahmedabad in the presence of German Chancellor Friedrich Merz and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, underlining the deal's geopolitical significance as both nations seek closer collaboration on clean energy[2][4]. First shipments are expected as early as 2028 from AM Green's one-million-ton-per-year facility currently under construction in Kakinada, Andhra Pradesh[5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ZmCWpRpe--/t_thumbnail/https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/b4001e42-2fa7-47d1-8ebf-3a742029e0ed/wirestory_8c73b02ad2bbe6cc4938b91d4771e48b_16x9.jpg%3Fw%3D1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient galaxy was slowly strangled to death by its black hole</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/black-hole-starves-ancient-gal-YuAmvDzmQb.JMquXjFXvEQ</link>
      <description>Astronomers have identified one of the earliest "dead" galaxies in the universe, revealing that its central supermassive black hole killed star formation not through a violent explosion but through repeated cycles of heating and expelling gas—a process researchers describe as "death by a thousand cuts."

The study, published January 11 in Nature Astronomy, used data from the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) and the Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) to examine a galaxy designated GS-10578, nicknamed "Pablo's Galaxy" after the astronomer who first observed it in detail[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--vadzFbTp--/t_thumbnail/https://media.newindianexpress.com/newindianexpress/2024-06/4fd4d94e-e026-4497-8363-236e5eab2517/ANI_20240610114636.jpg%3Fw%3D1200%26h%3D900%26auto%3Dformat%252Ccompress%26fit%3Dmax%26enlarge%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China releases first software to sync time between Earth and Moon</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-unveils-first-lunar-time-GYgPpNdoR4Kc3NxVeYUf5g</link>
      <description>Scientists at China's Purple Mountain Observatory in Nanjing have released LTE440, the world's first publicly available software designed to synchronize time between Earth and the Moon. The Lunar Time Ephemeris package addresses a growing engineering challenge as space agencies prepare for more frequent and complex lunar missions in the coming decade.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--NW0HeTam--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/08/21cbb540-582c-4542-8334-b74d46503dda_df8babb9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uniper signs deal to import green ammonia from India</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uniper-signs-major-green-ammon-7hYoc6DASAmX8ytbFZoIMA</link>
      <description>German energy company Uniper and India's AM Green Ammonia have finalized a long-term agreement for the supply of up to 500,000 tons of renewable ammonia annually, creating one of the first large-scale green fuel corridors between India and Europe[1][2][3].

The binding agreement, signed Monday in Ahmedabad in the presence of German Chancellor Friedrich Merz and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, marks a milestone in both countries' clean energy ambitions[4][5]. First deliveries are expected as early as 2028 from AM Green's 1 million-ton-per-year facility currently under construction in Kakinada, Andhra Pradesh[1][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ZmCWpRpe--/t_thumbnail/https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/b4001e42-2fa7-47d1-8ebf-3a742029e0ed/wirestory_8c73b02ad2bbe6cc4938b91d4771e48b_16x9.jpg%3Fw%3D1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran says it's ready for war or talks as Trump weighs strike</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-foreign-minister-says-rea-flE5FUEFTnuR4.4Wxk9r.w</link>
      <description>Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi declared Monday that Tehran is "fully prepared for war" but remains open to diplomacy with the United States, as President Donald Trump considers military intervention over the Iranian government's deadly crackdown on nationwide protests.

"The Islamic Republic of Iran is not seeking war but is fully prepared for war," Araghchi told a conference of foreign ambassadors in Tehran, broadcast on state television[1][2]. "We are also ready for negotiations, but these negotiations should be fair, with equal rights and based on mutual respect."

The statement came hours after Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One on Sunday that Iranian leaders had called him seeking to negotiate and that "a meeting is being set up"[3][4]. However, Trump warned the U.S. "may have to act before a meeting" due to the escalating violence against protesters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MpzOOysx--/t_thumbnail/https://twt-thumbs.washtimes.com/media/image/2025/09/09/Egypt_Iran_IAEA_42337_c0-0-3346-1950_s885x516.jpg%3F52fafb7f13f2b026c97e399591f35cdca4638a61" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta taps ex Trump adviser Dina Powell McCormick as president</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/meta-taps-ex-trump-adviser-din-W2QrZYM5QhKTNEkbdfJXDw</link>
      <description>Meta Platforms announced Monday that Dina Powell McCormick, a former Goldman Sachs executive and deputy national security adviser under President Donald Trump, will join the company as president and vice chairman. The appointment marks the first time Meta has created a presidential role in the company's history.[1][2][3]

Powell McCormick, who served on Meta's board of directors from April to December 2025, will become part of the company's executive team and help guide its overall strategy. The move comes as Meta races to scale its AI infrastructure amid intense competition in the artificial intelligence sector.[1][2][4]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--pTu3kqYw--/t_thumbnail/https://images.axios.com/4pbKxMeuK6fnOHwdptpPCzE4kPA%3D/0x417:4000x2667/1366x768/2026/01/12/1768176277809.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eutelsat orders 340 satellites from Airbus to rival Starlink</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/eutelsat-orders-340-oneweb-sat-PNUcC5tWS3i4L5ybRUEdwg</link>
      <description>Eutelsat, the French-British satellite operator and sole European competitor to Elon Musk's Starlink, has ordered 340 low Earth orbit satellites from Airbus to expand and refresh its OneWeb constellation, the companies announced Monday.

The contract marks Eutelsat's first major industrial commitment since completing a €1.5 billion capital raise in late 2025, signaling the company's intent to aggressively pursue growth in the competitive LEO broadband market[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--r6tq2lBJ--/t_thumbnail/https://www.computerweekly.com/visuals/ComputerWeekly/Hero%20Images/OneWeb-Eutelsat-PR-hero.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alphabet becomes fourth company to hit $4 trillion valuation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/alphabet-hits-4-trillion-dolla-93Klm2qpS4e1cX9mKBf1ig</link>
      <description>Alphabet broke through the $4 trillion market capitalization threshold on Monday, joining an exclusive club of companies to ever reach the valuation as investors bet heavily on the Google parent's dominance in artificial intelligence.

Shares rose as much as 1.7% to $334.04 on the news that Apple had selected Google's Gemini models to power the next generation of Siri, according to CNBC[1][2]. The announcement cemented Alphabet's position as Wall Street's second-most valuable company, surpassing Apple for the first time since 2019[3][4]. Only Nvidia, Microsoft, and Apple have previously crossed the $4 trillion mark[5][6].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--SodjlpRY--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108175922-1761769839779-108175922-1753295096051-gettyimages-2215577882-AFP_47H33MP.jpeg%3Fv%3D1767911560%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
