<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:44:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>UK regulator opens first Online Safety Act probe into X</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uk-ofcom-launches-formal-inves-smPJ86vqRB6IQOaNwg8b9Q</link>
      <description>Britain's communications regulator Ofcom announced Monday that it has opened a formal investigation into Elon Musk's social media platform X over concerns that its AI chatbot Grok is being used to create and distribute sexualized deepfake images of women and children. The probe marks the first significant enforcement action under the UK's Online Safety Act targeting a major social media platform.

"There have been deeply concerning reports of the Grok AI chatbot account on X being used to create and share undressed images of people — which may amount to intimate image abuse or pornography — and sexualised images of children that may amount to child sexual abuse material," Ofcom said in a statement[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--2gJonRbQ--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/VU3G4YSWZ5IXNEEIEXVW57Q4PY.jpg%3Fauth%3D2447f678233cef3c084f4db8550947448bcf93a719c4d2a91806742d3df320ac%26height%3D1005%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80%26smart%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple picks Google's Gemini AI to power next-gen Siri</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/apple-announces-google-gemini-mik1crqzTneJh3ssPz63Mg</link>
      <description>Apple officially confirmed Monday that it has selected Google's Gemini AI models to power the next-generation version of Siri, marking one of the most consequential partnerships between the two longtime rivals in the competitive artificial intelligence landscape.

"After careful evaluation, we determined that Google's technology provides the most capable foundation for Apple Foundation Models and we're excited about the innovative new experiences it will unlock for our users," Apple said in a statement shared with CNBC[1][2].

The announcement immediately boosted shares of Alphabet, Google's parent company, helping push it past the $4 trillion market capitalization threshold for the first time. Alphabet shares rose as much as 1.7% to $334.04 on Monday, with the company recently overtaking Apple to become the world's second-most valuable corporation behind Nvidia[3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--XSpyY-7r--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/GVYMQ3XJXVMA7H6APECEE2HSKI.jpg%3Fauth%3D20bf861d026ccf8bf7e00e3f316ab204cfeb0044e87b4d0ddc9ba4446af360be%26height%3D1005%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80%26smart%3Dtrue" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland seeks NATO defense umbrella as Trump refuses to rule out force</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/greenland-boosts-nato-defense-rJAAVi2STeStVUs0X6icCQ</link>
      <description>Greenland's government announced on Monday that it will intensify efforts to ensure the Arctic territory's defense falls under NATO's framework, as US President Donald Trump doubled down on his ambition to acquire the island, refusing to rule out military force.

"All NATO member states, including the United States, have a common interest in the defence of Greenland," Greenland's coalition government said in a statement published on the Naalakkersuisut (government) website[1][2]. The move comes as Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One that "one way or the other, we are going to have Greenland"[3].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--z2btN7PQ--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/AFP__20251028__82932ZE__v2__MidRes__DenmarkPolitics-1768178954.jpg%3Fresize%3D1200%252C630" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran imposes near-total internet blackout as protests spread</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-faces-nationwide-protests-eGeArFwkRkOcf_Mnh0CuJw</link>
      <description>The most widespread protests in years have swept across Iran over the past two weeks, with hundreds killed as authorities impose a near-total internet blackout and security forces escalate their crackdown on demonstrators demanding an end to clerical rule.

As the digital blackout enters its fifth day, the Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA) reported Monday that at least 544 people have been killed, including 496 protesters and 48 security personnel, while more than 10,600 individuals have been detained since demonstrations began on December 28[1][2]. Iran Human Rights, a Norway-based monitoring group, said unverified reports suggest the actual death toll could exceed 2,000, with much of the violence obscured by the communications shutdown[2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Ao5lLuVz--/t_thumbnail/https://static.the-independent.com/2026/01/12/4/07/-BESTPIX-BRITAIN-IRAN-PROTEST-RIGHTS-fs3vke91.jpeg%3Ftrim%3D0%252C0%252C0%252C0%26width%3D1200%26height%3D800%26crop%3D1200%253A800" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba rejects U.S. talks after Trump threatens oil cutoff</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-threatens-cuba-oil-cutof-s0KVvXeMRhygdRimMQuBpg</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump declared on Sunday that Cuba will no longer receive Venezuelan oil or money, demanding the Caribbean nation "make a deal, BEFORE IT IS TOO LATE" in a Truth Social post that drew a fiery rebuke from Cuban leadership. The threat marks an escalation of pressure on Cuba following the U.S. capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro on January 3.

Cuban President Miguel Díaz-Canel responded defiantly on X, stating, "Cuba is a free, independent and sovereign nation. No one tells us what to do."[1][2] He added that Cuba "does not attack; it has been attacked by the U.S. for 66 years, and it does not threaten; it prepares, ready to defend the homeland to the last drop of blood."[3][4]

On Monday, Díaz-Canel stated there are "no conversations with the US government except for technical contacts in the area of migration," while expressing openness to dialogue "founded on principles of sovereign equality, mutual respect, adherence to international law."[5][6]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--l9uG5xyI--/t_thumbnail/https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php%3Fsrc%3Dhttps://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/6ILGKXKCEMGIXXMIDITNFYRVBU_size-normalized.jpg%26w%3D1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran says it's ready for war or talks as Trump weighs strike</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-foreign-minister-says-rea-flE5FUEFTnuR4.4Wxk9r.w</link>
      <description>Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi declared Monday that Tehran is "fully prepared for war" but remains open to diplomacy with the United States, as President Donald Trump considers military intervention over the Iranian government's deadly crackdown on nationwide protests.

"The Islamic Republic of Iran is not seeking war but is fully prepared for war," Araghchi told a conference of foreign ambassadors in Tehran, broadcast on state television[1][2]. "We are also ready for negotiations, but these negotiations should be fair, with equal rights and based on mutual respect."

The statement came hours after Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One on Sunday that Iranian leaders had called him seeking to negotiate and that "a meeting is being set up"[3][4]. However, Trump warned the U.S. "may have to act before a meeting" due to the escalating violence against protesters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--MpzOOysx--/t_thumbnail/https://twt-thumbs.washtimes.com/media/image/2025/09/09/Egypt_Iran_IAEA_42337_c0-0-3346-1950_s885x516.jpg%3F52fafb7f13f2b026c97e399591f35cdca4638a61" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White House weighs Iran nuclear talks as Trump considers strikes</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/white-house-weighs-iran-nuclea-8B2aBGPBS8uiN8ZVRv0D0w</link>
      <description>The White House is considering Iran's proposal to enter nuclear negotiations even as President Donald Trump leans toward authorizing military strikes against the Islamic Republic, according to U.S. officials familiar with the matter[1][2].

Trump announced Sunday that Iran had reached out to the United States the previous day proposing to negotiate a nuclear agreement[2][3]. "Iran reached out because they want to talk," Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One[3]. The President indicated his administration was working to arrange a meeting with Tehran but warned he might need to take action beforehand as the death toll from protests continues to rise[3].

The overture arrives amid a brutal crackdown on nationwide demonstrations that erupted December 28 following the Iranian rial's collapse to a record low of 1.4 million to the dollar[4][5][6]. At least 538 people have been killed in the two-week uprising, according to the U.S.-based Human Rights Activists News Agency, which has a history of accuracy during previous unrest in Iran[4][7]. More than 10,600 individuals have been arrested[7].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768246866/url_uploads/image_es5zly.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump to meet Venezuelan opposition leader Machado at White House</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/venezuela-frees-over-100-polit-O8vUYtPWT3GmhF4b3zNMxQ</link>
      <description>Venezuela's interim government announced on Monday the release of 116 political prisoners, though human rights organizations have only been able to verify roughly half that number. The releases come after U.S. pressure following the capture of former President Nicolás Maduro by American forces earlier this month.

The discrepancy highlights ongoing tensions between the interim government's claims and the reality on the ground. The Penitentiary Services Ministry stated that those freed had been "deprived of their liberty for acts associated with disrupting the constitutional order and undermining the stability of the nation."[1][2] However, the human rights group Foro Penal reported that only 41 prisoners had been released as of Monday, including 24 freed overnight.[3][4] Another watchdog, Justicia, Encuentro y Perdón, confirmed 53 "duly verifiable" releases and called the current pace "clearly inadequate."[5][6]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--GIVAPK6m--/t_thumbnail/https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630%2Cf_auto%2Cq_auto:best/rockcms/2025-10/251010-Marina-Corina-Machado-mb-1009-886c22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NASA to roll Artemis II rocket to launchpad Saturday</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nasa-to-roll-artemis-ii-rocket-qSCDydoZTeeWoImoDzBgrA</link>
      <description>NASA is set to begin final preparations for humanity's return to lunar space this weekend, with the agency planning to roll the massive Space Launch System rocket and Orion spacecraft to Kennedy Space Center's Launch Pad 39B on Saturday, January 17[1][2][3].

The 4-mile journey from the Vehicle Assembly Building will mark a critical milestone for Artemis II, the first crewed mission to the Moon since Apollo 17 in December 1972. If all goes according to plan, four astronauts could be launched toward the Moon as early as February 6[2][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--sgM-sbbf--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/oRR.O_SsiAgtvIGjScq3Ug--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/al_com_articles_125/0ac0126257ac0a10a2be73dfa672dc55" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO commander warns Russia, China pose growing Arctic threat</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/uk-and-nato-allies-discuss-boo-Pe.7JltPREKiguYzTkN3ZQ</link>
      <description>Britain is in discussions with NATO allies about strengthening military presence in the Arctic amid growing concerns over Russian and Chinese activity in the region, a UK government minister confirmed Sunday.

Transport Secretary Heidi Alexander described the conversations as "business as usual" rather than a response to U.S. President Donald Trump's threats to acquire Greenland. "It's becoming an increasingly contested geopolitical region, with Russia and China … you would expect us to be talking to all our allies in NATO about what we can do to deter Russian aggression in the Arctic Circle," Alexander told Sky News[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--YoHhWcBU--/t_thumbnail/https://images.euronews.com/articles/stories/09/61/05/77/808x539_cmsv2_7cbee892-3688-5f3f-af96-151906874b66-9610577.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexico's Sheinbaum says Trump call ruled out US military action</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mexico-s-sheinbaum-says-trump-vesG6XDuRUGjgYLvlYql7A</link>
      <description>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio spoke with Mexican Foreign Minister Juan Ramon de la Fuente on January 11, 2026, in a call focused on dismantling drug trafficking networks and stopping the flow of fentanyl across the border. The conversation came days after President Donald Trump threatened to launch ground operations against Mexican cartels, remarks that have heightened tensions between the neighboring nations.[1][2]

The call was initiated at the instruction of Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum, who on Friday directed de la Fuente to engage with U.S. officials to "strengthen coordination" under the existing bilateral security agreement.[3][4]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 22:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--SW8sH0ni--/t_thumbnail/https://i.abcnewsfe.com/a/924f6b61-2b92-4778-9aec-e7908a0c248d/wirestory_3b90e4a7efaf26f8f481dedf5e6423f4_16x9.jpg%3Fw%3D1600" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cornell study finds 70-year metal strength rule reverses at supersonic speeds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/cornell-study-overturns-70-yea-IFBzb7YYSseh.cn7CvtrKw</link>
      <description>For more than seven decades, the Hall-Petch effect has guided engineers in strengthening metals: make the grains smaller, and the metal gets harder. But a new study from Cornell University has upended that foundational principle, revealing that at extreme speeds, smaller-grained metals actually become weaker.

The research, published January 12, 2026 in Physical Review Letters, found that when copper is deformed at supersonic velocities, the long-held relationship between grain size and strength reverses entirely[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 22:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--V9hhRn9c--/t_thumbnail/https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/X2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European nations declare 'Greenland belongs to its people' after Trump threats</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/greenland-emerges-as-strategic-3iYWv8lEQ1qPrqeuXQTQ.A</link>
      <description>The world's largest island has become a flashpoint in an escalating geopolitical contest, as its melting ice sheet reveals both scientific warnings about climate change and vast mineral wealth coveted by global powers.

President Donald Trump's continued insistence that the United States will acquire Greenland "one way or the other" has thrust the sparsely populated Danish territory into the center of international tensions, even as researchers race to understand how its ice loss will reshape coastlines worldwide.[1][2]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Roy11j4T--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108085415-1736763405518-gettyimages-2192274023-AFP_36T98MH.jpeg%3Fv%3D1736772753%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China, India cut coal power together for first time since 1970s</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-and-india-cut-coal-power-KZHeTZuSQguMVsUhJwsNSw</link>
      <description>For the first time in more than half a century, coal-fired power generation declined simultaneously in China and India last year, according to new analysis, marking what researchers call a "historic moment" in the global energy transition.

The concurrent reduction in coal-generated electricity in the world's two largest coal-consuming nations had not occurred since 1973, according to the Centre for Research on Energy and Clean Air (CREA), a Helsinki-based think tank. The analysis, commissioned by the UK climate news platform Carbon Brief, found that coal power generation in India fell by 3% in 2025, while China saw a 1.6% decline.[1][2][3]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768261950/getty_uploads/2255364315_lyos3g.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky warns of imminent Russian strike as Kyiv struggles to restore heat</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/ukraine-struggles-to-restore-p-CumwQiGjQ3GnYz0KhUmtlg</link>
      <description>Emergency crews worked around the clock on Monday to restore heating and electricity to Kyiv residents more than three days after devastating Russian attacks on energy infrastructure, as President Volodymyr Zelensky warned that another large-scale assault could be imminent.

About 800 residential buildings in the Ukrainian capital remained without heating as of January 12, according to Mayor Vitali Klitschko[1], down from approximately 6,000 buildings that lost heat following a massive overnight assault on January 9 that killed at least four people and injured 25 others[2]. Deputy Prime Minister Oleksiy Kuleba reported that 85% of Kyiv's residential buildings have had heating restored[3][4].

"There is intelligence information. The Russians are preparing a new massive strike," Zelensky said in his evening video address. "Drones to exhaust air defense systems and missiles. They want to take advantage of the cold. The strike may occur in the coming days."[3][5]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 01:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768266942/getty_uploads/2255038483_obq0cg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia strikes Ukraine power grid, cutting electricity to 7 regions</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/russia-attacks-ukraine-energy-HD.kzkDTTFGQDz_L65ip.g</link>
      <description>Russian forces struck Ukraine's energy infrastructure overnight on Monday, cutting power to seven regions as the country endures its fourth wartime winter under relentless bombardment. The attack left consumers in Odesa, Zhytomyr, Sumy, Kharkiv, Donetsk, Dnipropetrovsk, and Chernihiv without electricity, according to Ukraine's Ministry of Energy[1][2].

Emergency blackouts were imposed in Kyiv and the surrounding region, as well as in Odesa, Kharkiv, and Donetsk oblasts. Authorities said a gradual transition from emergency restrictions to scheduled hourly shutdowns was underway in the capital[1].

The overnight assault extends a devastating week of Russian strikes targeting Ukraine's power grid. Prime Minister Yulia Svyrydenko said not a single day had passed this week without attacks on energy facilities, with 44 strikes recorded in total[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 01:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768266942/getty_uploads/2255038483_obq0cg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink helps some Iranians bypass internet blackout</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iranians-use-starlink-to-bypas-dDRrNNk6QvOJJ7vhgAe7Qw</link>
      <description>Some Iranians are maintaining access to the outside world through Elon Musk's Starlink satellite internet service despite a sweeping communications blackout imposed by authorities amid deadly crackdowns on nationwide protests, three people inside the country told Reuters [1][2].

The satellite service, which beams internet directly from thousands of low-Earth orbit satellites operated by SpaceX, continues to function in some parts of Iran even though authorities have banned the technology and imposed severe penalties on users [1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768274971/getty_uploads/2255384533_mpzfvt.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 200 U.S. scientists condemn Trump's Greenland acquisition push</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-faces-backlash-over-gree-PWAGlRDvQWOAynvSUktgXQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's renewed push to bring Greenland under American control has drawn fierce opposition from European allies and a coordinated rebuke from more than 200 U.S. scientists, even as mining experts say the island's mineral wealth may be far more difficult to access than the administration suggests.

"We are going to do something on Greenland whether they like it or not," Trump declared on Friday during a White House meeting with oil executives[1][2]. "If we don't do it the easy way, we're going to do it the hard way."

The remarks, coming days after U.S. military forces removed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro on January 3, have alarmed European leaders and prompted Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen to declare that her country faces a "decisive moment" in its diplomatic struggle with Washington[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ShpB5H7l--/t_thumbnail/https://www.highnorthnews.com/sites/default/files/styles/media_image/public/2025-11/IMG_6232-2.JPG%3Fitok%3DZb4Gyia8" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian currencies slide after Trump threatens Iran trade tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-currencies-fall-amid-tru-Mb7LzyUDRM2UvtFv.M2.wA</link>
      <description>Asian currencies weakened broadly on Tuesday as traders grappled with fresh tariff warnings from President Donald Trump targeting countries that do business with Iran, while rising oil prices and concerns over the Federal Reserve's independence added to regional market pressures.

The Japanese yen fell to a one-year low against the dollar, while the Indian rupee and South Korean won also declined, according to Investing.com [1]. The selloff came after Trump announced Monday that any country doing business with Iran would face a 25% tariff on U.S. trade, escalating economic pressure as anti-government protests spread across the Middle Eastern nation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768274242/getty_uploads/2255277403_nnlaeo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Webb telescope reveals how black holes starved early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-uncover-surprising-MrQN8icjSHCs7LdqWbCyfA</link>
      <description>A series of discoveries announced this week are reshaping astronomers' understanding of the early universe, revealing unexpected heat, unusual galaxy types, and cosmic structures that defy existing models of how the first galaxies formed and evolved.

Research published January 12 in Nature Astronomy describes a massive galaxy that "lived fast and died young" after its supermassive black hole slowly starved it of the cold gas needed to form new stars. Meanwhile, separate findings presented at the 247th meeting of the American Astronomical Society in Phoenix show galaxy clusters far hotter than predicted and objects so strange that scientists are comparing them to the platypus.[1][2][3]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--_hxRt4J4--/t_thumbnail/https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/41/2025/10/Galaxies.jpg%3Fw%3D1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
