<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
    <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    <description>Perplexity's Discover News Feed.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://docs.perplexity.ai/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Perplexity Discover</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover</link>
    </image>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:32:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink helps some Iranians bypass internet blackout</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iranians-use-starlink-to-bypas-dDRrNNk6QvOJJ7vhgAe7Qw</link>
      <description>Some Iranians are maintaining access to the outside world through Elon Musk's Starlink satellite internet service despite a sweeping communications blackout imposed by authorities amid deadly crackdowns on nationwide protests, three people inside the country told Reuters [1][2].

The satellite service, which beams internet directly from thousands of low-Earth orbit satellites operated by SpaceX, continues to function in some parts of Iran even though authorities have banned the technology and imposed severe penalties on users [1][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768274971/getty_uploads/2255384533_mpzfvt.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 200 U.S. scientists condemn Trump's Greenland acquisition push</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-faces-backlash-over-gree-PWAGlRDvQWOAynvSUktgXQ</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump's renewed push to bring Greenland under American control has drawn fierce opposition from European allies and a coordinated rebuke from more than 200 U.S. scientists, even as mining experts say the island's mineral wealth may be far more difficult to access than the administration suggests.

"We are going to do something on Greenland whether they like it or not," Trump declared on Friday during a White House meeting with oil executives[1][2]. "If we don't do it the easy way, we're going to do it the hard way."

The remarks, coming days after U.S. military forces removed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro on January 3, have alarmed European leaders and prompted Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen to declare that her country faces a "decisive moment" in its diplomatic struggle with Washington[3][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--ShpB5H7l--/t_thumbnail/https://www.highnorthnews.com/sites/default/files/styles/media_image/public/2025-11/IMG_6232-2.JPG%3Fitok%3DZb4Gyia8" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian currencies slide after Trump threatens Iran trade tariffs</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/asian-currencies-fall-amid-tru-Mb7LzyUDRM2UvtFv.M2.wA</link>
      <description>Asian currencies weakened broadly on Tuesday as traders grappled with fresh tariff warnings from President Donald Trump targeting countries that do business with Iran, while rising oil prices and concerns over the Federal Reserve's independence added to regional market pressures.

The Japanese yen fell to a one-year low against the dollar, while the Indian rupee and South Korean won also declined, according to Investing.com [1]. The selloff came after Trump announced Monday that any country doing business with Iran would face a 25% tariff on U.S. trade, escalating economic pressure as anti-government protests spread across the Middle Eastern nation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768274242/getty_uploads/2255277403_nnlaeo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Webb telescope reveals how black holes starved early galaxies</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/astronomers-uncover-surprising-MrQN8icjSHCs7LdqWbCyfA</link>
      <description>A series of discoveries announced this week are reshaping astronomers' understanding of the early universe, revealing unexpected heat, unusual galaxy types, and cosmic structures that defy existing models of how the first galaxies formed and evolved.

Research published January 12 in Nature Astronomy describes a massive galaxy that "lived fast and died young" after its supermassive black hole slowly starved it of the cold gas needed to form new stars. Meanwhile, separate findings presented at the 247th meeting of the American Astronomical Society in Phoenix show galaxy clusters far hotter than predicted and objects so strange that scientists are comparing them to the platypus.[1][2][3]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--_hxRt4J4--/t_thumbnail/https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/41/2025/10/Galaxies.jpg%3Fw%3D1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan and South Korea pledge deeper ties at Nara summit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/japan-and-south-korea-hold-sum-7nvN_WeUQqmAIoRUUv2hUg</link>
      <description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi and South Korean President Lee Jae Myung met in the ancient city of Nara on Tuesday for a summit aimed at deepening economic and security cooperation as the two U.S. allies navigate an increasingly complex regional landscape shaped by China's growing assertiveness and North Korea's nuclear program.

The meeting, held in Takaichi's home prefecture, marks the third encounter between the two leaders since Takaichi took office in October 2025 and carries added significance as this year marks 60 years since Japan and South Korea normalized diplomatic relations[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--Zzl3cDUm--/t_thumbnail/https://newsimg.koreatimes.co.kr/2025/12/11/59ae90bf-071f-4a1d-96c6-bb94c9810398.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran restores some international calls amid ongoing blackout</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iran-restores-some-internation-O6Q2_hg0StC0869xUjktHw</link>
      <description>Mobile phones in Iran were able to call abroad on Tuesday after a deadly crackdown on nationwide protests in which the government severed both internet access and international calling capabilities, according to the Associated Press. Several people in Tehran were able to reach an AP journalist, though the news agency's bureau in Dubai could not call those numbers back[1][2].

The partial restoration comes as the country enters its fifth day of a near-total communications blackout that has isolated millions of Iranians from the outside world. According to NetBlocks, the internet monitoring organization, connectivity throughout the country remains at just 1% of normal levels[3][4]. Text messaging appeared to remain down, and witnesses confirmed the internet was still inaccessible[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768284351/getty_uploads/2255209414_vayzfi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iranians bypass blackout with Starlink as phone calls resume</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/iranians-use-starlink-and-phon-M2qn16X5S5OmeIpnkuZ6cQ</link>
      <description>On Tuesday, Iranians were able to make international phone calls for the first time since their government imposed a near-total communications blackout on January 8, even as some citizens continue accessing the internet through Elon Musk's Starlink satellite service. The partial restoration of communications came as activists reported that at least 646 people have been killed in a bloody government crackdown on nationwide protests.[1][2][3]

Several people in Tehran were able to call The Associated Press, though calls from outside Iran could not reach them. Witnesses reported that SMS text messaging remained blocked and internet users could only access government-approved domestic websites, while international connections stayed severed.[1][2]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--5RC7FK3o--/t_thumbnail/https://sm.pcmag.com/t/pcmag_uk/news/i/iran-appea/iran-appears-to-be-jamming-starlink-amid-protests-internet-b_6vgt.1920.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mars shapes Earth's ice ages despite its small size, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/mars-gravitational-pull-influe-.jpDT2jEQMC0qQwzJa1Nzg</link>
      <description>Despite being half the size of Earth and only one-tenth its mass, Mars exerts a measurable influence on our planet's long-term climate patterns, including the timing of ice ages, according to new research published this week.

The study, led by Stephen Kane, a professor of planetary astrophysics at the University of California, Riverside, used computer simulations to model how Earth's orbit and axial tilt would behave with and without Mars present in the solar system. The findings, published in Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, reveal that two major climate cycles vanish entirely when the red planet is removed from the equation.[1][2]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--bJfVMW-o--/t_thumbnail/https://d4hal6uazahag.cloudfront.net/783397/uploads/92a3f8e0-d73a-11f0-80bf-5b2aa2b70a1e_1200_630.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unstable water cycle drove nearly 5,000 deaths in 2025, report finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/global-water-cycle-instability-ldJEiTDFTZi3ZVrZH1L52A</link>
      <description>Water-related disasters caused nearly 5,000 deaths, displaced 8 million people, and resulted in economic losses exceeding US$360 billion during 2025, according to a new international report that attributes these catastrophes to an increasingly unstable global water cycle driven by rapid warming.

The 2025 Global Water Monitor Report, released Sunday by researchers led by Professor Albert van Dijk at The Australian National University's Fenner School of Environment and Society, documents how shifts in rainfall patterns, atmospheric moisture, and temperature combined to amplify floods, droughts, and heat extremes worldwide[1][2][3].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--b8s2BZCF--/t_thumbnail/https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/12506047-1758179701.jpg%3Fresize%3D1920%252C1440" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat waves overwhelm honey bees' ability to cool hives, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/extreme-heat-waves-threaten-ho-gxpKTbVdRLKJQyII_vnB4A</link>
      <description>A new study reveals that intensifying heat waves are overwhelming honey bees' natural ability to cool their hives, causing population declines that could threaten global pollination services. The research, published on January 12 in the journal Ecological and Evolutionary Physiology, is the first to assess how natural heat waves affect honey bee colonies' capacity to regulate temperature and maintain healthy populations.[1][2]

The findings arrive as commercial beekeepers across North America already face colony losses potentially reaching 60 to 70 percent in recent years, according to Washington State University entomologists, underscoring the urgency of understanding how climate change compounds existing threats to these critical pollinators.[3]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--KDS3OFCi--/t_thumbnail/https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2020/1-honeybee.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX to bring ISS astronauts home in first medical evacuation</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/spacex-launches-pandora-telesc-MFL6lPPyTIW1WcrX0pwBnw</link>
      <description>The past week has marked a whirlwind of activity for SpaceX and NASA, with the successful launch of the Pandora exoplanet telescope followed by preparations for what will be the first medical evacuation from the International Space Station in its 25-year history.

NASA's Pandora mission lifted off aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket from Vandenberg Space Force Base in California on January 11, joining a rideshare flight that SpaceX dubbed "Twilight" for its destination in a dusk-dawn sun-synchronous orbit[1][2]. The 325-kilogram spacecraft, equipped with a 45-centimeter all-aluminum telescope, will study at least 20 known exoplanets over its one-year primary mission[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--zMonyWoS--/t_thumbnail/https://nypost.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/118805373.jpg%3Fquality%3D75%26strip%3Dall%26w%3D1200" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webb telescope overturns decades of thinking on black hole behavior</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/webb-telescope-unveils-black-h-8NzJy5s5Tly72s..PX2DIg</link>
      <description>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope has overturned decades of scientific thinking about supermassive black holes, revealing that hot, dusty material near the Circinus Galaxy's central black hole is primarily feeding it rather than being expelled outward as previously believed.

The research, published Tuesday in Nature, includes what NASA describes as the sharpest image of a black hole's surroundings ever captured by Webb[1][2].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--s9KNzqD5--/t_thumbnail/https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nncziUx4LsHDWThxdtExRe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan, South Korea agree to joint DNA testing for 1942 mine disaster victims</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/japan-and-south-korea-hold-sum-a9BK.1n9Se..kdcp6IkuTw</link>
      <description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi and South Korean President Lee Jae Myung met in Nara, Japan, on Tuesday to strengthen bilateral ties and regional cooperation as Tokyo faces intensifying economic pressure from Beijing over its stance on Taiwan.

"Cooperation between our two countries is more important than ever," Lee said at the opening of the summit in Takaichi's hometown, calling on both nations to work toward "a better future" amid "a complex and dizzying international order."[1][2] Takaichi responded that both countries should "cooperate to ensure regional stability and fulfill their respective roles."[3]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t_thumbnail/v1768297005/getty_uploads/2255479805_l8ynxn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-rich soil nearly doubles tropical forest regrowth, study finds</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/nitrogen-doubles-tropical-fore-YjK1oxPhRN2XDaSQty.r_g</link>
      <description>Tropical forests can recover at nearly double the pace if they have adequate nitrogen in their soil, according to research published Monday in Nature Communications that carries implications for global reforestation strategies and climate change mitigation efforts.

The study, described as the world's largest and longest nitrogen and phosphorus addition experiment of its kind, found that young forests grew back 95% faster on recently abandoned agricultural land and 48% faster in forests recovering for 10 years when nitrogen was added to the soil[1][2][3].

"Nitrogen is limiting how quickly young forests can regrow," said Sarah Batterman, senior author on the paper and ecologist at the Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies and University of Leeds. "When we added nitrogen to the soil, forests grew back almost twice as fast in the first 10 years. Faster growth rates mean faster absorption of carbon dioxide"[2][4].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--CRUy59oN--/t_thumbnail/https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2026/recovering-tropical-fo-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global markets pause as investors await key US inflation data</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/global-markets-dip-as-investor-Si39I5LfRXO_IF8EoshPIw</link>
      <description>Stock markets around the world entered a holding pattern on Tuesday as investors awaited a crucial US consumer inflation report that could shape Federal Reserve policy decisions in the months ahead. While US futures edged lower, Asian equities surged to record highs and European markets traded flat to slightly higher.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--DE95eP6t--/t_thumbnail/https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108235958-1764775162327-gettyimages-2249102611-AFP_86YG4QD.jpeg%3Fv%3D1764775238%26w%3D1920%26h%3D1080" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China says sci-fi flying aircraft carrier could become real</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-aims-to-turn-scifi-jets-hWpcD_b2S2CZDEbZrtNkyw</link>
      <description>Chinese state media has declared the nation's science fiction-inspired aerospace concepts will become reality, signaling a shift in how Beijing frames its ambitions for air and space dominance. A CCTV military channel broadcast on January 10 repositioned the Nantianmen Project—a futuristic weapons program dating to 2017—from fantasy to attainable technology[1][2].

Military analyst Wang Mingzhi of the PLA Air Force Command College stated on the program that "whether it can be realized is no longer the question; we should ask what will be realized first."[1][3] The comments mark the first official framing of the concepts as genuine development targets rather than educational displays.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--rPn8XyuZ--/t_thumbnail/https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/gFwrUBtG.LAe0AEZR4l6Cw--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTk2MDtoPTU0MDtjZj13ZWJw/https://media.zenfs.com/en/interesting_engineering_646/7533059bb8a9fe44c4133f9ef7b3a670" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark, Greenland officials to meet Vance, Rubio at White House</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/trump-pushes-for-us-control-of-1Ylp8RT9TGyQ2bF3K5y3tw</link>
      <description>Foreign ministers from Denmark and Greenland are set to meet US Vice President JD Vance and Secretary of State Marco Rubio at the White House on Wednesday, as President Donald Trump intensifies threats to take control of the Arctic territory "whether they like it or not."[1][2] Danish Foreign Minister Lars Lokke Rasmussen said the meeting was requested to "move this whole discussion into a meeting room where we can look each other in the eye."[1]

Trump has repeatedly framed the acquisition of Greenland as essential for US national security, citing concerns about Russian and Chinese activity in the Arctic. "We don't want Russia or China going to Greenland, which if we don't take Greenland, you can have Russia or China as your next door neighbor," Trump told reporters Friday.[3][4]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--gt8v5eS---/t_thumbnail/https://static01.nyt.com/images/2026/01/08/multimedia/08us-venezuela-rubio-greenland-fjwh/08us-venezuela-rubio-greenland-fjwh-facebookJumbo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China urges Canada to break from U.S. ahead of Carney visit</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/china-pressures-canada-to-shif-cWglMG_tTEO3fhAdmTrZiw</link>
      <description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney arrives in Beijing on Wednesday for a four-day visit, the first by a Canadian leader in nearly a decade, as China's state media ramps up pressure on Ottawa to chart a foreign policy course independent of the United States[1][2][3].

The trip, scheduled for January 14-17, comes as Canada grapples with a trade war with its southern neighbor and the fallout from President Donald Trump's tariffs and repeated suggestions that Canada could become "the 51st state"[3][4]. China sees an opportunity to peel the longtime U.S. ally away from Washington, at least partially, through what Beijing calls "strategic autonomy"[2][5].</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--hIMWSOSU--/t_thumbnail/https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/7T2KRPQ2URJXJITUNT2PEOOSXE.jpg%3Fauth%3Df30c1cf1a1d232798f4b10883b0fde310e6b65f4a28a698fd8ac28d38a760342%26width%3D1920%26quality%3D80" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IOC considers rotating Winter Olympics among fixed venues</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/climate-change-threatens-futur-2td6cDZ2R.CLm.g5FGuz7g</link>
      <description>As the Milan-Cortina Winter Olympics approach next month, growing evidence shows that climate change is reshaping the geography of where the Winter Games can be held. The International Olympic Committee is now considering rotating the Olympics among a permanent pool of suitable locations and moving events earlier in the season as warming temperatures diminish reliable winter conditions worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--IBnrnXJD--/t_thumbnail/https://i.cbc.ca/ais/1.2508249%2C1390498375000/full/max/0/default.jpg%3Fim%3DCrop%252Crect%253D%25280%252C0%252C1180%252C663%2529%253B" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta cuts 1,000 Reality Labs jobs, shifting focus to AI glasses</title>
      <link>https://perplexity.ai/discover/you/meta-cuts-1000-reality-labs-jo-n1tqivzMT_mnbtAbXSi7MQ</link>
      <description>Meta Platforms has begun notifying more than 1,000 employees in its Reality Labs division of layoffs, marking a decisive retreat from the virtual reality and metaverse ambitions that once defined the company's future. The cuts, announced Tuesday morning, represent roughly 10% of the 15,000-person division and will disproportionately impact teams working on VR headsets and Horizon Worlds, Meta's VR-based social network[1][2][3].

Chief Technology Officer Andrew Bosworth informed affected employees via an internal memo reviewed by Bloomberg, with resources being redirected toward AI-powered wearables and smartphone features[2][4]. The move signals an acknowledgment that Meta's costly metaverse vision—which prompted CEO Mark Zuckerberg to rename the company from Facebook in 2021—has failed to gain mainstream traction.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="https://pplx-res.cloudinary.com/image/fetch/s--nkhlEZ_X--/t_thumbnail/https://sm.pcmag.com/t/pcmag_au/news/m/meta-is-re/meta-is-reportedly-laying-off-hundreds-of-metaverse-employee_4kw2.1200.jpg" type="image/jpeg" medium="image"/>
      </media:group>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
